Korea

Korea is a peninsula↗r region in East Asia↗ consisting of the Korean Peninsula, Jeju Island↗, and smaller islands. Since the end of World War II in Asia↗ in 1945, it has been politically divided↗ at or near the 38th parallel↗ between North Korea↗ (Democratic People's Republic of Korea; DPRK) and South Korea↗ (Republic of Korea; ROK). Both countries proclaimed independence in 1948, and the two countries fought the Korean War↗ from 1950 to 1953. The region is bordered by China↗ to the north and Russia↗ to the northeast, across the Amnok↗ (Yalu) and Duman↗ (Tumen) rivers, and is separated from Japan↗ to the southeast by the Korea Strait↗.

Known human habitation of the Korean peninsula dates to 40,000 BC. The kingdom of Gojoseon↗, which according to tradition was founded in 2333 BC, fell to the Han dynasty↗ in 108 BC. It was followed by the Three Kingdoms↗ period, in which Korea was divided into Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗. In 668 AD, Silla conquered Baekje and Goguryeo with the aid of the Tang dynasty↗, forming Unified Silla↗; Balhae↗ succeeded Goguryeo in the north. In the late 9th century, Unified Silla collapsed into three states, beginning the Later Three Kingdoms↗ period. In 918, Goguryeo was resurrected as Goryeo↗, which achieved what has been called a "true national unification" by Korean historians, as it unified both the Later Three Kingdoms and the ruling class of Balhae after its fall. Goryeo, whose name developed into the modern exonym↗ "Korea", became a vassal state↗ of the Mongol Empire↗ during the 13th century. Goryeo overthrew Mongol rule before falling to a coup led by General Yi Seong-gye↗, who established the Joseon↗ dynasty in 1392. The first 200 years of Joseon were marked by peace; the Hangul, the Korean alphabet↗ was created and Confucianism↗ became influential. This ended with Japanese↗ and Qing invasions↗, which brought devastation to Joseon and led to Korean isolationism. After the invasions, an isolated Joseon experienced another nearly 200-year period of peace and prosperity, along with cultural and technological development. In the final years of the 19th century, Japan forced Joseon to open up↗ and Joseon experienced turmoil such as the Kapsin Coup↗, Donghak Peasant Revolution↗, and the assassination of Empress Myeongseong↗. In 1895, Japan defeated China↗ in the First Sino-Japanese War↗ and China lost suzerainty over Korea and Korea was placed under further Japanese influence. In 1897, the centuries old Joseon was replaced by the Korean Empire↗ with the Joseon's last king, Gojong↗, becoming the Emperor of the Korean Empire. Japan's further victory in the 1904–1905 Russo-Japanese War↗, expelled Russian influence in Korea and Manchuria. In 1905, the Korean Empire became a protectorate of the Empire of Japan↗. In 1910, the Empire of Japan↗ officially annexed the Korean peninsula↗.

Korea under Japanese rule↗ was marked by industrialization and modernization, economic exploitation, and brutal suppression of the Korean independence movement↗, as reflected in the 1919 March First Movement↗. The Japanese suppressed Korean culture, and during World War II forcefully mobilized millions of Koreans to support its war effort. In 1945, Japan surrendered to the Allies↗, and the Soviet Union↗ and United States↗ agreed to divide Korea into two military occupation zones divided by the 38th parallel, with the Soviet zone in the north and American zone in the south. The division was meant to be temporary, with plans for Korea to be reunited under a single government. In 1948, the DPRK and ROK were established with the backing of each power, and ongoing tensions led to the outbreak of the Korean War in 1950, which came to involve U.S.-led United Nations↗ and communist Chinese↗ forces. The war ended in stalemate in 1953, but without a peace treaty. A demilitarized zone↗ was created between the countries, approximating the original partition.

This status contributes to the high tensions that divide the peninsula, and South Korea claims to be the sole legitimate government of Korea. South Korea is a regional power↗ and a developed country↗, with its economy↗ ranked as the world's fourteenth-largest by GDP (PPP)↗. Its armed forces↗ are one of the world's strongest militaries, with the world's second-largest standing army by military and paramilitary personnel↗. South Korea has been renowned for its globally influential pop culture, particularly in music (K-pop↗) and cinema↗, a phenomenon referred to as the Korean Wave↗. North Korea follows Songun↗, a "military first↗" policy which prioritizes the Korean People's Army↗ in state affairs and resources. It possesses nuclear weapons↗, and is the country with the highest number of military personnel↗, with a total of 7.8 million active↗, reserve↗, and paramilitary↗ personnel, or approximately 30% of its population. Its active duty army of 1.3 million soldiers is the fourth-largest in the world, consisting of 4.9% of its population. North Korea is widely considered to have the worst human rights record↗ in the world.

Etymology

Main article: Names of Korea↗ See also: Korean romanization↗

"Korea" is the modern spelling of "Corea", a name attested in English as early as 1614. "Corea" is derived from the name of the ancient kingdom of Goryeo↗. Korea was transliterated↗ as Cauli in The Travels of Marco Polo↗, of the Chinese↗ 高麗 (MC↗: Kawlej, mod.↗ Gāolì). This was the Hanja↗ for the Korean kingdom of Goryeo↗ (고려 / 高麗), which ruled most of the Korean peninsula during the 12th century. Korea's introduction to the West resulted from trade and contact with merchants from Arabic lands, with some records dating back as far as the 9th century. Goryeo's name was a continuation of Goguryeo↗ (Koguryŏ) the northernmost of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, which was officially known as Goryeo beginning in the 5th century. The original name was a combination of the adjectives "high" and "lofty" with the name of a local Yemaek↗ tribe, whose original name is thought to have been either "Guru" (溝樓, lit. Walled City, inferred from some toponyms in Chinese historical documents) or "Gauri" (가우리, lit. Center). With expanding British and American trade following the opening of Korea↗ in the late 19th century, the spelling "Korea" appeared and gradually grew in popularity. The name Korea is now commonly used in English contexts by both North and South Korea.

In South Korea, Korea as a whole is referred to as Hanguk/Han'guk (한국, [haːnɡuk]). The name references Samhan↗, referring to the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, not the ancient confederacies in the southern Korean Peninsula. Although written in Hanja as 韓, 幹, or 刊, this Han has no relation to the Chinese place names or peoples who used those characters but was a phonetic transcription↗ (OC↗: *↗Gar, MC↗: Han or Gan) of a native Korean word that seems to have had the meaning "big" or "great", particularly in reference to leaders. It has been tentatively linked with the title khan↗ used by the nomads of Manchuria↗ and Central Asia↗.

In North Korea, Korea as a whole is referred to as Chosŏn/Joseon, (조선, [tɕosʰʌn]) which is also the basis of the word for Korea as a whole in Japan↗ (朝鮮 (Chōsen)), China↗ (朝鮮 (Cháoxiǎn)), and Vietnam↗ (Triều Tiên). "Great Joseon↗" was the name of the kingdom ruled by the Joseon dynasty↗ from 1392 until their declaration of the short-lived Great Korean Empire↗ in 1897. King Taejo↗ had named them for the earlier Gojoseon↗ (고조선), who ruled northern Korea from its legendary prehistory↗ until their conquest in 108 BCE by China's Han Empire↗. The Go- in Gojoseon is the Hanja word 古 and simply means "ancient" or "old"; it is a modern usage to distinguish the ancient Joseon from the later dynasty. It is unclear whether Joseon was a transcription↗ of a native Korean name (OC↗ *↗T[r]awser, MC↗ Trjewsjen) or a partial translation into Chinese of the Korean capital Asadal↗ (아사달), whose meaning has been reconstructed as "Morning Land" or "Mountain".

History

Main article: History of Korea↗ For a timeline, see: Timeline of Korean history↗

Prehistory

Main article: Prehistoric Korea↗ The Korean Academy claimed ancient hominid fossils originating from about 100,000 BCE in the lava at a stone city site in Korea. Fluorescent and high-magnetic analyses indicate the volcanic fossils may be from as early as 300,000 BCE. The best preserved Korean pottery goes back to the Paleolithic↗ times around 10,000 BCE and the Neolithic↗ period begins around 6000 BCE.

Beginning around 300 BC, the Japonic↗-speaking Yayoi people↗ from the Korean Peninsula entered the Japanese islands and displaced or intermingled with the original Jōmon↗ inhabitants. The linguistic homeland of Proto-Koreans↗ is located somewhere in Southern Siberia / Manchuria, such as the Liao river↗ area or the Amur region. Proto-Koreans arrived in the southern part of the Korean Peninsula at around 300 BC, replacing and assimilating Japonic-speakers and likely causing the Yayoi↗ migration.

Gojoseon

Main article: Gojoseon↗ According to Korean legend, Dangun↗, a descendant of Heaven↗, established Gojoseon↗ in 2333 BCE. In 108 BCE, the Han dynasty↗ defeated Gojoseon and installed four commanderies↗ in the northern Korean peninsula. Three of the commanderies fell or retreated westward within a few decades, but the Lelang Commandery↗ remained as a center of cultural and economic exchange with successive Chinese dynasties for four centuries. By 313, Goguryeo↗ annexed all of the Chinese commanderies.

Proto–Three Kingdoms

Main article: Proto–Three Kingdoms of Korea↗

The Proto–Three Kingdoms period, sometimes called the Multiple States Period, is the earlier part of what is commonly called the Three Kingdoms Period↗, following the fall of Gojoseon↗ but before Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗ fully developed into kingdoms.

This time period saw numerous states spring up from the former territories of Gojoseon, which encompassed northern Korea and southern Manchuria↗. With the fall of Gojoseon, southern Korea entered the Samhan↗ period.

Located in the southern part of Korea, Samhan referred to the three confederacies of Mahan↗, Jinhan↗, and Byeonhan↗. Mahan was the largest and consisted of 54 states. Byeonhan↗ and Jinhan↗ both consisted of twelve states, bringing a total of 78 states within the Samhan↗. These three confederacies eventually developed into Baekje↗, Silla↗, and Gaya↗.

Three Kingdoms

Main articles: Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, Baekje↗, Goguryeo↗, and Silla↗

The Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ consisted of Goguryeo↗, Silla↗, and Baekje↗. Silla and Baekje controlled the southern half of the Korean Peninsula↗, maintaining the former Samhan↗ territories, while Goguryeo controlled the northern half of the Korean Peninsula, Manchuria and the Liaodong Peninsula↗, uniting Buyeo↗, Okjeo↗, Dongye↗ and other states in the former Gojoseon↗ territories.

Goguryeo↗ was a highly militaristic state, and a large empire in East Asia, reaching its zenith in the 5th century when its territories expanded to encompass most of Manchuria to the north, parts of Inner Mongolia↗ to the west, parts of Russia to the east, and the Seoul region to the south. Goguryeo experienced a golden age under Gwanggaeto the Great↗ and his son Jangsu↗, who both subdued Baekje and Silla during their times, achieving a brief unification of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ and becoming the most dominant power on the Korean Peninsula. In addition to contesting for control of the Korean Peninsula, Goguryeo had many military conflicts↗ with various Chinese dynasties, most notably the Goguryeo–Sui War↗, in which Goguryeo defeated a huge force said to number over a million men. In 642, the powerful general Yŏn Kaesomun↗ led a coup and gained complete control over Goguryeo. In response, Emperor Tang Taizong↗ of China led a campaign against Goguryeo↗, in which the Gorguryeo forces were decimated by the Tang at the Battle of Mount Jupil↗. Taizong was later defeated at the Battle of Ansi↗ and withdrew his forces from Goguryeo. After the death of Tang Taizong, his son Emperor Tang Gaozong↗ allied with the Korean kingdom of Silla and invaded Goguryeo again, but were forced to withdraw in 662. However, Yŏn Kaesomun died of a natural cause in 666 and Goguryeo was thrown into chaos and weakened by a succession struggle among his sons and younger brother, with his eldest son defecting to Tang↗ and his younger brother defecting to Silla. The Tang-Silla alliance conquered Goguryeo in 668. After the collapse of Goguryeo, Tang and Silla ended their alliance and fought over control of the Korean Peninsula. Silla succeeded in gaining control over most of the Korean Peninsula, while Tang gained control over Goguryeo's northern territories. However, 30 years after the fall of Goguryeo, a Goguryeo general by the name of Dae Joyeong↗ founded the Korean-Mohe state of Balhae↗ and successfully expelled the Tang presence from much of the former Goguryeo territories.

The southwestern Korean kingdom of Baekje↗ was founded around modern-day Seoul by a Goguryeo prince↗, a son of the founder of Goguryeo↗. Baekje absorbed all of the Mahan↗ states and subjugated most of the western Korean peninsula (including the modern provinces of Gyeonggi↗, Chungcheong↗, and Jeolla↗, as well as parts of Hwanghae↗ and Gangwon↗) to a centralised government; during the expansion of its territory, Baekje acquired Chinese culture and technology through maritime contacts with the Southern Dynasties↗. Baekje was a great maritime power; its nautical skill, which made it the Phoenicia↗ of East Asia, was instrumental in the dissemination of Buddhism throughout East Asia and continental culture to Japan. Historic evidence suggests that Japanese culture, art, and language were influenced by the kingdom of Baekje and Korea itself; Baekje also played an important role in transmitting advanced Chinese culture to the Japanese archipelago. Baekje was once a great military power on the Korean Peninsula, most notably in the 4th century during the rule of Geunchogo↗ when its influence extended across the sea to Liaoxi↗ and Shandong↗ in China, taking advantage of the weakened state of Former Qin↗, and Kyushu↗ in the Japanese archipelago; however, Baekje was critically defeated by Gwanggaeto the Great and declined.

Although later records claim that Silla↗ was the oldest of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, it is now believed to have been the last kingdom to develop. By the 2nd century, Silla existed as a large state in the southeast, occupying and influencing its neighbouring city-states. In 562, Silla annexed the Gaya confederacy↗, which was located between Baekje and Silla. The Three Kingdoms of Korea often warred with each other and Silla was often dominated by Baekje and Goguryeo. Silla was the smallest and weakest of the three, but it used cunning diplomatic means to make opportunistic pacts and alliances with the more powerful Korean kingdoms, and eventually Tang China, to its great advantage. In 660, King Muyeol↗ ordered his armies to attack Baekje↗. General Kim Yu-shin↗, aided by Tang↗ forces, conquered Baekje after defeating General Gyebaek↗ at the Battle of Hwangsanbeol↗. In 661, Silla and Tang attacked Goguryeo but were repelled. King Munmu↗, son of Muyeol and nephew of General Kim Yu-shin, launched another campaign in 667 and Goguryeo fell in the following year.

North–South States Period

Main articles: North–South States Period↗, Later Silla↗, and Balhae↗ Beginning in the 6th century, Silla↗'s power gradually extended across the Korean Peninsula. Silla first annexed the adjacent Gaya confederacy↗ in 562. By the 640s, Silla formed an alliance with the Tang dynasty↗ of China to conquer Baekje↗ and later Goguryeo↗. After conquering Baekje and Goguryeo, Silla repulsed Tang China from the Korean peninsula in 676. Even though Silla unified most of the Korean Peninsula, most of the Goguryeo territories to the north of the Korean Peninsula were ruled by Balhae↗. Former Goguryeo general or chief of Sumo Mohe Dae Jo-yeong↗ led a group of Goguryeo and Mohe↗ refugees to the Jilin↗ and founded the kingdom of Balhae↗, 30 years after the collapse of Goguryeo, as the successor to Goguryeo. At its height, Balhae's territories extended from southern Manchuria↗ down to the northern Korean peninsula. Balhae was called the "Prosperous Country in the East".

Later Silla↗ carried on the maritime prowess of Baekje↗, which acted like the Phoenicia↗ of medieval East Asia↗, and during the 8th and 9th centuries dominated the seas of East Asia and the trade between China, Korea and Japan, most notably during the time of Chang Pogo↗; in addition, Silla people made overseas communities in China on the Shandong Peninsula↗ and the mouth of the Yangtze River↗. Later Silla was a prosperous and wealthy country, and its metropolitan capital of Gyeongju↗ was the fourth largest city in the world. Later Silla experienced a golden age of art and culture, as evidenced by the Hwangnyongsa↗, Seokguram↗, and Emille Bell↗. Buddhism flourished during this time, and many Korean Buddhists gained great fame among Chinese Buddhists and contributed to Chinese Buddhism, including: Woncheuk↗, Wonhyo↗, Uisang↗, Musang↗, and Kim Gyo-gak↗, a Silla prince whose influence made Mount Jiuhua↗ one of the Four Sacred Mountains↗ of Chinese Buddhism.

Later Silla fell apart in the late 9th century, giving way to the tumultuous Later Three Kingdoms period↗ (892–935), and Balhae was destroyed by the Khitan↗s in 926. Goryeo↗ unified the Later Three Kingdoms and received the last crown prince↗ and much of the ruling class of Balhae, thus bringing about a unification of the two successor nations of Goguryeo↗.

Goryeo dynasty

Main article: Goryeo↗ Goryeo↗ was founded in 918 and replaced Silla as the ruling dynasty of Korea. Goryeo's land was at first what is now South Korea and about 1/3 of North Korea, but later on managed to recover most of the Korean peninsula. Momentarily, Goryeo advanced to parts of Jiandao↗ while conquering the Jurchens↗, but returned the territories due to the harsh climate and difficulties in defending them. The name "Goryeo" (高麗) is a short form of "Goguryeo↗" (高句麗) and was first used during the time of King Jangsu↗. Goryeo regarded itself as the successor of Goguryeo, hence its name and efforts to recover the former territories of Goguryeo. Wang Geon↗, the founder of Goryeo, was of Goguryeo descent and traced his ancestry to a noble Goguryeo clan. He made Kaesong↗, his hometown, the capital.

During this period, laws were codified and a civil service system was introduced. Buddhism↗ flourished and spread throughout the peninsula. The development of celadon↗ industries flourished in the 12th and 13th centuries. The publication of the Tripitaka Koreana↗ onto more than 80,000 wooden blocks and the invention of the world's first metal movable type↗ in the 13th century attest to Goryeo's cultural achievements.

Goryeo had to defend frequently against attacks by nomadic empires, especially the Khitans↗ and the Mongols↗. Goryeo had a hostile relationship with the Khitans, because the Khitan Empire↗ had destroyed Balhae↗, also a successor state of Goguryeo. In 993, the Khitans, who had established the Liao dynasty↗ in 907, invaded Goryeo↗, demanding that it make amity with them. Goryeo sent the diplomat Sŏ Hŭi↗ to negotiate, who successfully persuaded the Khitans to let Goryeo expand to the banks of the Amnok (Yalu) River↗, citing that in the past the land belonged to Goguryeo, the predecessor of Goryeo. During the Goryeo–Khitan War↗, the Khitan Empire invaded Korea twice more in 1009↗ and 1018↗, but was defeated.

After defeating the Khitan Empire, which was the most powerful empire of its time, Goryeo experienced a golden age that lasted a century, during which the Tripitaka Koreana↗ was completed, and there were great developments in printing and publishing, promoting learning and dispersing knowledge on philosophy, literature, religion, and science; by 1100, there were 12 universities that produced famous scholars and scientists.

Goryeo was invaded by the Mongols↗ in seven major campaigns from the 1230s until the 1270s, but was never conquered. Exhausted after decades of fighting, Goryeo sent its crown prince↗ to the Yuan↗ capital to swear allegiance to the Mongols; Kublai Khan↗ accepted, and married one of his daughters to the Korean crown prince, and the dynastic line of Goryeo continued to survive under the overlordship↗ of the Mongol Yuan dynasty as a semi-autonomous vassal state and compulsory ally. The two nations became intertwined for 80 years as all subsequent Korean kings married Mongol princesses, and the last empress↗ of the Yuan dynasty was a Korean princess.

In the 1350s, King Gongmin↗ was free at last to reform the Goryeo government when the Yuan dynasty began to crumble. Gongmin had various problems that needed to be dealt with, which included the removal of pro-Mongol aristocrats and military officials, the question of land holding, and quelling the growing animosity between the Buddhists and Confucian↗ scholars. During this tumultuous period, Goryeo momentarily conquered Liaoyang↗ in 1356, repulsed two large invasions by the Red Turbans↗ in 1359 and 1360, and defeated the final attempt by the Yuan to dominate Goryeo when General Ch'oe Yŏng↗ defeated a Mongol tumen↗ in 1364. During the 1380s, Goryeo turned its attention to the Wokou↗ threat and used naval artillery↗ created by Ch'oe Mu-sŏn↗ to annihilate hundreds of pirate ships.

Joseon dynasty

Main article: Joseon↗

In 1392, the general Yi Seong-gye↗ overthrew the Goryeo↗ dynasty after he staged a coup and defeated General Ch'oe Yŏng↗. Yi Seong-gye named his new dynasty Joseon↗ and moved the capital from Kaesong↗ to Hanseong↗ (formerly Hanyang; modern-day Seoul) and built the Gyeongbokgung↗ palace. In 1394, he adopted Confucianism↗ as the country's official ideology, resulting in much loss of power and wealth by the Buddhists↗. The prevailing philosophy of the Joseon dynasty was Neo-Confucianism↗, which was epitomized by the seonbi↗ class, scholars who passed up positions of wealth and power to lead lives of study and integrity.

Joseon was a nominal tributary state of China↗ but exercised full sovereignty, and maintained the highest position among China's tributary states, which also included countries such as the Ryukyu Kingdom↗, Vietnam, Burma, Brunei, Laos, Thailand, and the Philippines, among others. In addition, Joseon received tribute from Jurchens and Japanese until the 17th century, and had a small enclave in the Ryukyu Kingdom that engaged in trade with Siam and Java.

During the 15th and 16th centuries, Joseon enjoyed many benevolent rulers who promoted education and science. Most notable among them was Sejong the Great (r. 1418–50), who personally created and promulgated Hangul↗, the Korean alphabet. This golden age saw great cultural and scientific advancements, including in printing, meteorological observation↗, astronomy, calendar science, ceramics↗, military technology, geography, cartography, medicine, and agricultural technology, some of which were unrivaled elsewhere. Joseon implemented a class system that consisted of yangban↗ the noble class, jungin the middle class, yangin the common class, and cheonin the lowest class, which included occupations such as butchers, tanners, shamans, entertainers, and nobi↗, the equivalent of slaves, bondservants, or serfs↗.

In 1592 and again in 1597, the Japanese invaded Korea↗; the Korean military at the time was unprepared and untrained, due to two centuries of peace on the Korean Peninsula↗. Toyotomi Hideyoshi↗ intended to conquer China and India through the Korean Peninsula, but was defeated by strong resistance from the Righteous Army↗, the naval superiority of Admiral Yi Sun-sin↗ and his turtle ship↗s, and assistance from Wanli Emperor↗ of Ming China↗. However, Joseon experienced great destruction, including a tremendous loss of cultural sites such as temples and palaces to Japanese pillaging, and the Japanese brought back to Japan an estimated 100,000–200,000 noses↗ cut from Korean victims. Less than 30 years after the Japanese invasions, the Manchus↗ took advantage of Joseon's war-weakened state and invaded↗ in 1627 and 1637, and then went on to conquer↗ the destabilized Ming dynasty.

After normalising relations with the new Qing dynasty↗, Joseon experienced a nearly 200-year period of peace. Kings Yeongjo↗ and Jeongjo↗ led a new renaissance of the Joseon dynasty during the 18th century.

In the 19th century, the royal in-law families gained control of the government, leading to mass corruption and weakening of the state, with severe poverty and peasant rebellions spreading throughout the country. Furthermore, the Joseon government adopted a strict isolationist policy, earning the nickname "the hermit kingdom↗", but ultimately failed to protect itself against imperialism↗ and was forced to open its borders, beginning an era leading into Japanese imperial rule↗.

Korean Empire

Main article: Korean Empire↗

Beginning in 1871, Japan↗ began to exert more influence in Korea, forcing it out of China's traditional sphere of influence. As a result of the First Sino-Japanese War↗ (1894–95), the Qing dynasty↗ had to give up such a position according to Article 1 of the Treaty of Shimonoseki↗, which was concluded between China and Japan in 1895. That same year, Empress Myeongseong↗ of Korea was assassinated by Japanese agents.

In 1897, the Joseon dynasty↗ proclaimed the Korean Empire↗ (1897–1910). King Gojong↗ became emperor. During this brief period, Korea had some success in modernising the military, economy, real property laws, education system, and various industries. Russia↗, Japan, France↗, and the United States all invested in the country and sought to influence it politically.

The Russians were pushed out of the fight for Korea following the conclusion of the Russo-Japanese War↗ (1904–1905). Korea became a protectorate↗ of Japan shortly afterwards. In Manchuria↗ on 26 October 1909, An Jung-geun↗ assassinated the former Resident-General of Korea↗, Itō Hirobumi↗, for his role in trying to force Korea into occupation.

Japanese annexation and occupation of Korea

Main article: Korea under Japanese rule↗ See also: Japanese war crimes↗

In 1910, an already militarily occupied Korea was a forced party to the Japan–Korea Annexation Treaty↗. The treaty was signed by Lee Wan-Yong↗, who was given the General Power of Attorney by the Emperor. However, the Emperor is said to have not actually ratified the treaty according to Yi Tae-jin. There is a long dispute whether this treaty was legal or illegal due to its signing under duress, threat of force and bribes.

Korean resistance to the brutal Japanese occupation was manifested in the nonviolent March First Movement↗ of 1919, during which 7,000 demonstrators were killed by Japanese police and military. The Korean liberation movement↗ also spread to neighbouring Manchuria↗ and Siberia↗.

Over five million Koreans were conscripted for labour beginning in 1939, and tens of thousands of men were forced into Japan's military. Nearly 400,000 Korean labourers died. Approximately 200,000 girls and women, mostly from China and Korea, were forced into sexual slavery for the Japanese military. In 1993, Japanese Chief Cabinet Secretary Yohei Kono↗ acknowledged the terrible injustices faced by these euphemistically named "comfort women↗".

During the Japanese annexation, the Korean language was suppressed in an effort to eradicate indigenous Korean national identity. Koreans were forced to take Japanese surnames, known as Sōshi-kaimei↗. Traditional Korean culture↗ suffered heavy losses, as numerous Korean cultural artefacts were destroyed or taken to Japan. One such artefact is rumored to be a sacred Korean mask (tal)↗, still up on display in a Japanese museum. To this day, valuable Korean artefacts can often be found in Japanese museums or among private collections. One investigation by the South Korean government identified 75,311 cultural assets that were taken from Korea, 34,369 in Japan and 17,803 in the United States. However, experts estimate that over 100,000 artefacts actually remain in Japan. Japanese officials considered returning Korean cultural properties, but to date this has not occurred. Both Koreas and Japan still dispute the ownership of the Dokdo↗ islets, located east of the Korean Peninsula.

There was significant emigration to the overseas territories of the Empire of Japan↗ during the Japanese occupation period, including Korea↗. By the end of World War II, there were over 850,000 Japanese settlers in Korea. After World War II, most of these overseas Japanese↗ repatriated to Japan. Migrants who remained squatted↗ in informal settlements↗.

Division and conflict

Main article: Division of Korea↗

In 1945, with the surrender of Japan↗, the United Nations↗ developed plans for a trusteeship administration, the Soviet Union↗ administering the peninsula north of the 38th parallel↗ and the United States↗ administering the south↗. The politics of the Cold War↗ resulted in the 1948 establishment of two separate governments, North Korea and South Korea.

The aftermath of World War II left Korea partitioned along the 38th parallel on 2 September 1945, with the north under Soviet occupation and the south under US occupation supported by other allied states. Consequently, North Korea, a Soviet-style socialist republic was established in the north, and South Korea, a Western-style regime, was established in the south↗.

North Korea is a one-party state↗ ruled by the Workers' Party of Korea↗, now centred on Kim Il Sung↗'s Juche↗ ideology, with a centrally planned↗ industrial economy. South Korea is a multi-party state↗ with a capitalist↗ market economy↗, alongside membership in the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development and the Group of Twenty↗. The two states have greatly diverged both culturally and economically since their partition, though they still share a common traditional culture and pre-Cold War history.

Since the 1960s, the South Korean economy has grown enormously and the economic structure was radically transformed. In 1957, South Korea had a lower per capita GDP↗ than Ghana↗, and by 2008 it was 17 times as high as Ghana's.

According to R. J. Rummel↗, forced labour↗, executions, and concentration camps were responsible for over one million deaths in North Korea from 1948 to 1987; others have estimated 400,000 deaths in concentration camps alone. Estimates based on the most recent North Korean census suggest that 240,000 to 420,000 people died as a result of the 1990s famine↗ and that there were 600,000 to 850,000 unnatural deaths in North Korea from 1993 to 2008. In South Korea, as guerrilla activities expanded, the South Korean government used strong measures against peasants, such as forcefully moving their families from guerrilla areas. According to one estimate, these measures resulted in 36,000 people killed, 11,000 people wounded, and 432,000 people displaced.

Korean War

Main article: Korean War↗ The Korean War broke out when Soviet-backed North Korea invaded South Korea. Despite massive swings in territorial gain back and forth, in the end neither side gained much territory as a result. The Korean Peninsula remained divided, the Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ being the de facto border between the two states.

In June 1950 North Korea invaded the South, using Soviet tanks and weaponry. During the Korean War↗ (1950–53) more than 1.2 million people died and the three years of fighting throughout the nation effectively destroyed most cities. The war ended with an armistice agreement↗ at approximately the Military Demarcation Line↗, but the two governments are officially still at war.

North and South Korea

See also: History of North Korea↗, History of South Korea↗, Korean conflict↗, and Korean reunification↗

In 2018, the leaders of North Korea and South Korea officially signed the Panmunjom Declaration↗, announcing that they will work to end the conflict.

In November 2020, South Korea and China agreed to work together to mend South Korea's relationship with North Korea. During a meeting between President Moon↗ and China's foreign minister, Wang Yi↗, Moon expressed his gratitude to China for its role in helping to foster peace in the Korean Peninsula. Moon was quoted telling Wang during their meeting that "[the South Korean] government will not stop efforts to put an end (formally) to war on the Korean Peninsula and achieve complete denuclearization and permanent peace together with the international community, including China."

Geography

Main article: Geography of Korea↗ See also: Geography of North Korea↗, Geography of South Korea↗, and Provinces of Korea↗

Korea consists of a peninsula↗ and nearby islands located in East Asia↗. The peninsula extends southwards for about 1100 km from continental Asia↗ into the Pacific Ocean↗ and is surrounded by the Sea of Japan↗ to the east and the Yellow Sea↗ (West Sea) to the west, the Korea Strait↗ connecting the two bodies of water. To the northwest, the Amnok River↗ separates Korea from China and to the northeast, the Duman River↗ separates it from China and Russia. Notable islands include Jeju Island↗, Ulleung Island↗, Dokdo↗.

The southern and western parts of the peninsula have well-developed plains, while the eastern and northern parts are mountainous. The highest mountain in Korea is Mount Paektu↗ (2,744 m), through which runs the border with China. The southern extension of Mount Paektu is a highland called Gaema Heights↗. This highland was mainly raised during the Cenozoic↗ orogeny↗ and partly covered by volcanic matter. To the south of Gaema Gowon, successive high mountains are located along the eastern coast of the peninsula. This mountain range is named Baekdu-daegan↗. Some significant mountains include Sobaeksan↗ (1,439 m), Mount Kumgang↗ (1,638 m), Seoraksan↗ (1,708 m), Taebaeksan↗ (1,567 m), and Jirisan↗ (1,915 m). There are several lower, secondary mountain series whose direction is almost perpendicular to that of Baekdu-daegan. They are developed along the tectonic line of Mesozoic↗ orogeny and their directions are basically northwest.

Unlike most ancient mountains on the mainland, many important islands in Korea were formed by volcanic activity in the Cenozoic orogeny. Jeju Island, situated off the southern coast, is a large volcanic island whose main mountain, Mount Halla↗ or Hallasan (1,950 m), is the highest in South Korea. Ulleung Island is a volcanic island in the Sea of Japan, the composition of which is more felsic↗ than Jeju. The volcanic islands tend to be younger, the more westward.

Because the mountainous region is mostly on the eastern part of the peninsula, the main rivers↗ tend to flow westwards. Two exceptions are the southward-flowing Nakdong River↗ and Seomjin River↗. Important rivers running westward include the Amnok River, the Chongchon River↗, the Taedong River↗, the Han River↗, the Geum River↗, and the Yeongsan River↗. These rivers have vast flood plains and provide an ideal environment for wet-rice↗ cultivation.

The southern and southwestern coastlines of the peninsula form a well-developed ria↗ coastline, known as Dadohae-jin in Korean. This convoluted coastline provides mild seas, and the resulting calm environment allows for safe navigation, fishing, and seaweed farming↗. In addition to the complex coastline, the western coast of the Korean Peninsula has an extremely high tidal amplitude↗ (at Incheon↗, around the middle of the western coast, the tide can get as high as 9 m). Vast tidal flats have been developing on the south and west coastlines.

Climate

Korea has a temperate climate with comparatively fewer typhoons↗ than other countries in East Asia. Due to the peninsula's position, it has a unique climate influenced by Siberia in the north, the Pacific Ocean in the east and the rest of Eurasia in the west. The peninsula has four distinct seasons: spring, summer, autumn and winter.

Spring

As influence from Siberia weakens, temperatures begin to increase while the high pressure begins to move away. If the weather is abnormally dry, Siberia will have more influence on the peninsula leading to wintry weather such as snow.

Summer

During June at the start of the summer, there tends to be a lot of rain due to the cold and wet air from the Sea of Okhotsk↗ and the hot and humid air from the Pacific Ocean combining. When these fronts combine, it leads to a so-called rainy season with often cloudy days with rain, which is sometimes very heavy. The hot and humid winds from the south west blow causing an increasing amount of humidity and this leads to the fronts moving towards Manchuria↗ in China and thus there is less rain and this is known as midsummer; temperatures can exceed 30 °C daily at this time of year.

Autumn

Usually, high pressure is heavily dominant during autumn leading to clear conditions. Furthermore, temperatures remain high but the humidity becomes relatively low.

Winter

The weather becomes increasingly dominated by Siberia during winter and the jet stream moves further south causing a drop in temperature. This season is relatively dry with some snow falling at times.

Biodiversity

Main article: Wildlife of Korea↗ Animal life of the Korean Peninsula includes a considerable number of bird species and native freshwater fish↗. Native or endemic↗ species of the Korean Peninsula include Korean hare↗, Korean water deer↗, Korean field mouse↗, Korean brown frog↗, Korean pine↗ and Korean spruce↗. The Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ (DMZ) with its forest and natural wetlands↗ is a unique biodiversity spot, which harbours eighty-two endangered species↗. Korea once hosted many Siberian tigers↗, but as the number of people affected by the tigers increased, the tigers were killed in the Joseon dynasty and the Siberian tigers in the South Korea became extinct during the Japanese colonial era period. It has been confirmed that Siberian tigers are only on the side of North Korea now.

There are also approximately 3,034 species of vascular plants↗ throughout the peninsula.

Economy

Science and technology

Main article: History of science and technology in Korea↗ See also: List of Korean inventions and discoveries↗

One of the best known artefacts of Korea's history of science and technology is the Cheomseongdae↗, a 9.4-meter high astronomical observatory↗ built in 634 CE.

The earliest known surviving Korean example of woodblock printing is The Great Dharani Sutra↗. It is believed to have been printed in Korea in 750–51 CE, which if correct, would make it older than the Diamond Sutra↗.

During the Goryeo↗ period, metal movable type↗ printing was invented by Ch'oe Yun-ŭi↗ in 1234 CE. This invention made printing easier, more efficient and also increased literacy, which observed by Chinese visitors was seen to be so important where it was considered to be shameful to not be able to read. The Mongol Empire↗ later adopted Korea's movable type printing and spread as far as Central Asia. There is conjecture as to whether or not Ch'oe's invention had any influence on later printing inventions such as Gutenberg's Printing press↗. When the Mongols↗ invaded Europe↗ they inadvertently introduced different kinds of Asian technology.

During the Joseon period, the Turtle Ship↗ was invented, which were covered by a wooden deck and iron with thorns, as well as other weapons such as the bigyeokjincheolloe cannon↗ (비격진천뢰, 飛擊震天雷) and the hwacha↗.

The Korean alphabet hangul↗ was also invented during this time by King Sejong the Great↗.

Demographics

Main articles: Koreans↗, Demographics of South Korea↗, and Demographics of North Korea↗ As of 2023, the combined population of the Koreas is about 77.9 million (South Korea: 51.7 million, North Korea: 26.1 million). Korea is chiefly populated by a highly homogeneous↗ ethnic↗ group, the Koreans↗, who speak the Korean language↗. The number of foreigners living in Korea has also steadily increased since the late 20th century, particularly in South Korea, where more than 1 million foreigners reside. It was estimated in 2006 that only 26,700 of the old Chinese community↗ now remain in South Korea. However, in recent years, immigration from mainland China has increased; 624,994 persons of Chinese↗ nationality have immigrated to South Korea, including 443,566 of ethnic Korean↗ descent. Small communities of ethnic Chinese and Japanese↗ are also found in North Korea.

Largest cities in Korea:

Seoul (Seoul, population 9,904,312)
Busan↗ (Busan, population 3,448,737)
Pyongyang↗ (Pyongyang, population 3,255,288)
Incheon↗ (Incheon, population 2,890,451)
Daegu↗ (Daegu, population 2,446,052)
Daejeon↗ (Daejeon, population 1,538,394)
Gwangju↗ (Gwangju, population 1,502,881)
Suwon↗ (Gyeonggi, population 1,194,313)
Ulsan↗ (Ulsan, population 1,166,615)
Changwon↗ (South Gyeongsang, population 1,059,241)
Goyang↗ (Gyeonggi, population 990,073)
Yongin↗ (Gyeonggi, population 971,327)
Seongnam↗ (Gyeonggi, population 948,757)
Bucheon↗ (Gyeonggi, population 843,794)
Cheongju↗ (North Chungcheong, population 833,276)
Hamhung↗ (South Hamgyong, population 768,551)
Ansan↗ (Gyeonggi, population 747,035)
Chongjin↗ (North Hamgyong, population 667,929)
Jeonju↗ (North Jeolla, population 658,172)
Cheonan↗ (South Chungcheong, population 629,062)

Language

Main articles: Korean language↗ and Korean Sign Language↗

Korean↗ is the official language of both North and South Korea, and (along with Mandarin) of Yanbian Korean Autonomous Prefecture↗ in Jilin Province↗, China↗. Worldwide, there are up to 80 million speakers of the Korean language. South Korea has around 50 million speakers while North Korea around 25 million. Other large groups of Korean speakers through Korean diaspora↗ are found in China↗, the United States↗, Japan↗, former Soviet Union↗ and elsewhere.

Modern Korean is written almost exclusively in the script of the Korean alphabet↗ (known as Hangul in South Korea and Chosungul in China and North Korea), which was invented in the 15th century. Korean is sometimes written with the addition of some Chinese characters called Hanja; however, this is only occasionally seen nowadays.

Religion

Main articles: Religion in Korea↗, Religion in South Korea↗, and Religion in North Korea↗ See also: Korean shamanism↗, Korean Confucianism↗, Korean Buddhism↗, Taoism in Korea↗, Christianity in Korea↗, and Islam in Korea↗

Confucian↗ tradition has dominated Korean thought, along with contributions by Buddhism↗, Taoism↗, and Korean Shamanism↗. Since the middle of the 20th century, however, Christianity↗ has competed with Buddhism in South Korea, while religious practice has been suppressed in North Korea. Throughout Korean history and culture, regardless of separation, the influence of traditional beliefs of Korean Shamanism, Mahayana Buddhism, Confucianism and Taoism have remained an underlying religion of the Korean people as well as a vital aspect of their culture; all these traditions have coexisted peacefully for hundreds of years up to today despite strong Westernisation from Christian missionary conversions in the South or the pressure from the Juche↗ government↗ in the North.

According to 2005 statistics from the South Korean government, about 46% of citizens profess no particular religion. Christians↗ account for 29.2% of the population (of which are Protestants 18.3% and Catholics 10.9%) and Buddhists↗ 22.8%. In North Korea, around 71.3% claim to be non-religious or atheists, 12.9% follow Cheondoism↗ and 12.3% Korean Folk Religion↗, while Christians account for 2% of the population and Buddhists 1.5%.

Islam in South Korea↗ is practised by about 45,000 natives (about 0.09% of the population) in addition to some 100,000 foreign workers from Muslim countries. While in North Korea it's estimated to be around 3000 Muslims, which is around 0.01% of the population. The Ar-Rahman Mosque↗ is the only mosque in DPRK, and it is located at the Iranian Embassy grounds in Pyongyyang.

In 1993, the Korean Overseas Culture and Information Service↗ estimated that around 1,600,000 people practice Korean new religions↗ in both Korean countries.

Education

Main articles: Education in South Korea↗ and Education in North Korea↗ The modern South Korean school system consists of six years in elementary school, three years in middle school, and three years in high school. Students are required to go to elementary and middle school, and do not have to pay for their education, except for a small fee called a "School Operation Support Fee" that differs from school to school. The Programme for International Student Assessment↗, coordinated by the OECD↗, ranks South Korea's science education as the third best in the world and being significantly higher than the OECD average.

Although South Korean students often rank high on international comparative assessments, the education system is criticized for emphasising too much upon passive learning and memorisation. The South Korean education system is rather notably strict and structured as compared to its counterparts in most Western societies.

The North Korean education system consists primarily of universal and state funded↗ schooling by the government↗. The national literacy rate for citizens 15 years of age and above is over 99 per cent. Children go through one year of kindergarten, four years of primary education↗, six years of secondary education↗, and then on to universities↗. The most prestigious university in the DPRK is Kim Il Sung University↗. Other notable universities include Kim Chaek University of Technology↗, which focuses on computer science, Pyongyang University of Foreign Studies↗, which trains working level diplomats and trade officials, and Kim Hyong Jik University of Education↗, which trains teachers.

Culture

Main articles: Culture of Korea↗, Korean art↗, Korean pottery and porcelain↗, Korean martial arts↗, Korean dance↗, Korean bow↗, and Korean architecture↗

In ancient Chinese texts, Korea is referred to as "Rivers and Mountains Embroidered on Silk" (금수강산 / 錦繡江山) and "Eastern Nation of Decorum" (동방예의지국 / 東方禮儀之國). Individuals are regarded as one year old when they are born, as Koreans reckon the pregnancy period as one year of life for infants, and age increments increase on New Year's Day↗ rather than on the anniversary of birthdays. Thus, one born immediately before New Year's Day may only be a few days old in western reckoning, but two years old in Korea. Accordingly, a Korean person's stated age (at least among fellow Koreans) will be one or two years more than their age according to western reckoning. However, western reckoning is sometimes applied with regard to the concept of legal age↗; for example, the legal age for purchasing alcohol↗ or cigarettes↗ in the Republic of Korea is 19, which is measured according to western reckoning.

Literature

Excerpt from: Korean literature↗

Music

Main article: Traditional music of Korea↗ Traditional Korean music includes combinations of the folk, vocal, religious and ritual↗ music styles of the Korean people↗. Korean music has been practised since prehistoric times. Korean music falls into two broad categories. The first, Hyangak↗, literally means The local music or Music native to Korea, a famous example of which is Sujechon, a piece of instrumental music often claimed to be at least 1,300 years old. The second, yangak, represents a more Western style.

Cuisine

Main article: Korean cuisine↗ See also: Korean tea ceremony↗ and Korean royal court cuisine↗

Koreans traditionally believe that the taste and quality of food depend on its spices and sauces, the essential ingredients to making a delicious meal. Therefore, soybean paste↗, soy sauce↗, gochujang↗ or red pepper paste and kimchi↗ are some of the most important staples in a Korean household.

Korean cuisine was greatly influenced by the geography and climate of the Korean Peninsula, which is known for its cold autumns and winters, therefore there are many fermented dishes and hot soups and stews.

Korean cuisine is probably best known for kimchi↗, a side dish which uses a distinctive fermentation↗ process of preserving vegetables, most commonly cabbage. Kimchi is said to relieve the pores on the skin, thereby reducing wrinkles and providing nutrients to the skin naturally. It is also healthy, as it provides necessary vitamins and nutrients. Gochujang, a traditional Korean sauce made of red pepper is also commonly used, often as pepper (chilli) paste, earning the cuisine a reputation for spiciness.

Bulgogi↗ (roasted marinated meat, usually beef), galbi↗ (marinated grilled short ribs), and samgyeopsal↗ (pork belly) are popular main courses. Fish is also a popular commodity, as it is the traditional meat that Koreans eat. Meals are usually accompanied by a soup or stew, such as galbitang↗ (stewed ribs) or doenjang jjigae↗ (fermented bean paste soup). The center of the table is filled with a shared collection of sidedishes called banchan↗.

Other popular dishes include bibimbap↗, which literally means "mixed rice" (rice mixed with meat, vegetables, and red pepper paste), and naengmyeon↗ (cold noodles).

Instant noodles, or ramyeon↗, is a popular snack food. Koreans also enjoy food from pojangmacha↗s (street vendors), which serve tteokbokki↗, rice cake and fish cake with a spicy gochujang sauce; gimbap↗, made of steamed white rice wrapped in dried green laver↗ seaweed; fried squid; and glazed sweet potato. Soondae↗, a sausage made of cellophane noodles and pork blood, is widely eaten.

Additionally, some other common snacks include "Choco Pie↗", shrimp crackers, "bbeongtwigi" (puffed rice grains), and "nurungji" (slightly burnt rice). Nurungji can be eaten as it is or boiled with water to make a soup. Nurungji can also be eaten as a snack or a dessert.

Korea is unique among Asian countries in its use of metal chopsticks. Metal chopsticks have been discovered in archaeological sites belonging to the ancient Korean kingdoms of Goguryeo, Baekje and Silla.

Sports

Main articles: Sport in South Korea↗ and Sport in North Korea↗ North Korea and South Korea usually compete as two separate nations in international events. There are, however, a few examples of them having competed as one entity↗, under the name Korea.

While association football↗ remains one of the most popular sports in South Korea, the martial art of taekwondo↗ is considered to be the national sport. Baseball↗ and golf↗ are also popular. The board game Go↗, known in Korea as baduk, has also been popular for over a millennium, first arriving from China in the 5th century CE; baduk is played both casually and competitively.

Martial arts

Taekwon-Do

Main article: Taekwondo↗ Taekwon-Do is Korea's most famous martial art and sport. It combines combat techniques, self-defence, sport and exercise. Taekwon-Do has become an official Olympic sport, starting as a demonstration event in 1988↗ (when South Korea hosted the Games in Seoul) and becoming an official medal event in 2000.↗ The two major Taekwon-Do federations, the International Taekwon-Do Federation↗ and the World Taekwondo Federation↗, were founded in Korea.

Hapkido

Main article: Hapkido↗ Hapkido is a modern Korean martial art↗ with a grappling focus that employs joint locks, throws, kicks, punches and other striking attacks like attacks against pressure points. Hapkido emphasizes circular motion, non-resisting movements and control of the opponent. Practitioners seek to gain advantage through footwork and body positioning to employ leverage, avoiding the pure use of strength against strength.

Ssireum

Main article: Ssireum↗ Ssireum is a traditional form of wrestling that has been practised in Korea for thousands of years, with evidence discovered from Goguryeo of Korea's Three Kingdoms Period (57 BCE to 688). Ssireum is the traditional national sport of Korea. During a match, opponents grip each other by sash belts wrapped around the waist and the thigh, attempting to throw their competitor to the sandy ground of the ring. The first opponent to touch the ground with any body part above the knee or to lose hold of their opponent loses the round.

Ssireum competitions are traditionally held twice a year, during the Dano Festival↗ (the 5th day of the fifth lunar month) and Chuseok↗ (the 15th day of the 8th lunar month). Competitions are also held throughout the year as a part of festivals and other events.

Taekkyon

Main article: Taekkyon↗ Taekkyon is a traditional martial art, considered the oldest form of fighting technique of Korea. Practiced for centuries and especially popular during the Joseon↗ period, two forms co-existed: one for practical use, the other for sport. This form was usually practised alongside Ssireum↗ during festivals and competitions between villages. Nonetheless, Taekkyon almost disappeared during the Japanese Occupation↗ and the Korean War↗.

Though lost in North Korea, Taekkyon has enjoyed a spectacular revival from the 1980s in South Korea. It is the only martial art in the world (with Ssireum) recognized as a National Treasure of South Korea↗ and a UNESCO Intangible Cultural Heritage↗.

See also

Inter-Korean summits↗
Korean name↗
Korean natural farming↗
Korean War↗
List of Korean inventions and discoveries↗
List of peninsulas↗
National Treasures of North Korea↗
National Treasures of South Korea↗
North Korea–South Korea relations↗
Korean reunification↗

Notes

References

Citations

Bibliography

Ian Castello-Cortes, ed. North Korea. World Reference Atlas. New York: Dorling Kindersley, 1996. 2nd American ed. ISBN 978-0-7894-1085-6.
Bruce Cumings. Korea's Place in the Sun. Norton, 1997. ISBN 978-0-393-31681-0
Kim and et al.. Women of Korea: A History from Ancient Times to 1945. Ewha Womans University Press, 1976. ISBN 978-89-7300-116-3.
History. Korea. Asian Info.
Top 500 list. CN↗: STJI, 2007
People. Facts. UMSL, 2005.
Tariq Hussain. The Korea Herald. Diamond dilemma, 5 March 2007.
Korea information. Korea Expat Community. WorknPlay.

Further reading

Chun, Tuk Chu. "Korea in the Pacific Community". Social Education 52 (March 1988), 182. EJ 368 177.
Cumings, Bruce↗. The Two Koreas. New York: Foreign Policy Association, 1984.
Don Oberdorfer. The Two Koreas: a Contemporary History. Basic Books, 2001. ISBN 978-0465051625. OCLC 47831650
Focus on Asian Studies. Special Issue: "Korea: A Teacher's Guide". No. 1, Fall 1986.
Gi-Wook Shin. Colonial modernity in Korea. Cambridge, MA↗: Harvard University, Asia Center, 1999. ISBN 978-0-674-14255-8.
Hart, Dennis. From Tradition to Consumption: Construction of a Capitalist Culture in South Korea. Seoul: Jimoondang, 2003.
Sheila Miyoshi Jager↗. Brothers at War – The Unending Conflict in Korea. London: Profile Books, 2013. ISBN 978-1-84668-067-0
Joe, W.J. & Choe, H.A. Traditional Korea: A Cultural History, Seoul: Hollym, 1997.
Joungwon, A.K. Divided Korea: The Politics of Development, Harvard University Press, 1975.
Lee Ki-baik. A New History of Korea. Cambridge: Harvard UP, 1984.
Lee Sang-sup. "The Arts and Literature of Korea". The Social Studies 79 (July–August 1988): 153–60. EJ 376 894.
Keith L Pratt. Everlasting Flower: A History of Korea. London: Reaktion, 2006. ISBN 9781861892737. OCLC 63137295
Tae-Jin, Y. "The Illegality of the Forced Treaties Leading to Japan's Annexation of the Great Han Empire", In the Korean National Commission for UNESCO, Vol. 36, No. 4, 1996.
The Gloucestershire Regiment and The Battle of the Imjin River, Korean War. UK↗: Glosters.
How Does Korea Compare. OECD Health Data. Organisation For Economic Co-operation and Development, 2009.

External links

Wiktionary: Korea↗ Wikivoyage: Korea↗ *

The Republic of Korea↗

38°19′N 127°14′E

Seoul

Seoul, officially Seoul Special Metropolitan City, is the capital↗ and largest city of South Korea↗, and the largest city in the whole of Korea. The broader Seoul Metropolitan Area↗, encompassing Seoul, Gyeonggi Province↗ and Incheon↗, emerged as the world's sixth largest metropolitan economy↗ in 2022, behind New York↗, Tokyo↗, Los Angeles↗, Paris↗, and London↗, and hosts more than half of South Korea's population. Although Seoul's population peaked at over 10 million, it has gradually decreased since 2014, standing at about 9.6 million residents as of 2024.

Seoul's history traces back to 18 BC when it was founded by the people of Baekje↗, one of the Three Kingdoms of Korea. During the Joseon↗ dynasty, Seoul was officially designated as the capital, surrounded by the Fortress Wall of Seoul. In the early 20th century, Seoul was occupied by the Empire of Japan↗, temporarily renamed "Keijō↗" ("Gyeongseong" in Korean). The Korean War↗ brought fierce battles, with Seoul changing hands four times and leaving the city mostly in ruins. Nevertheless, the city has since undergone significant reconstruction and rapid urbanization.

The de facto administrative capital has gradually switched to the planned city↗ of Sejong City↗, which opened in 2012 and is located about 121 kilometers further south. As of 2019, Sejong hosts 10 out of the South Korean government↗'s 18 ministries. Despite this, the Constitutional Court of Korea↗ declared in 2004 that Seoul must remain the national capital due to it being an "unwritten constitutional custom", unless otherwise changed by a nationwide referendum.

Seoul was rated Asia's most livable city, with the second-highest quality of life globally according to Arcadis↗ in 2015 and a GDP per capita (PPP) of approximately $40,000. 15 Fortune Global 500↗ companies, including industry giants such as Samsung↗, LG↗, and Hyundai↗, are headquartered in the Seoul Capital Area, which has major technology hubs, such as Gangnam and Digital Media City. Seoul is ranked seventh in the Global Power City Index↗ and the Global Financial Centres Index↗, and is one of the five leading hosts of global conferences. The city has also hosted major events such as the 1986 Asian Games↗, the 1988 Summer Olympics↗, and the 2010 G20 Seoul summit↗, in addition to three matches at the 2002 FIFA World Cup↗.

Seoul is geographically set in a mountainous and hilly terrain, with Bukhansan↗ positioned on its northern edge. Within the Seoul Capital Area lie five UNESCO World Heritage Sites: Changdeokgung↗, Hwaseong Fortress↗, Jongmyo↗, Namhansanseong↗, and the Royal Tombs of the Joseon dynasty↗. Furthermore, Seoul has witnessed a surge in modern architectural development, with iconic landmarks including the N Seoul Tower↗, the 63 Building↗, the Lotte World Tower↗, the Dongdaemun Design Plaza↗, Lotte World↗, the Trade Tower↗, COEX↗, IFC Seoul↗, and Parc1↗. Seoul was named the World Design Capital↗ in 2010 and has served as the national hub for the music, entertainment, and cultural industries that have propelled K-pop↗ and the Korean Wave↗ to international prominence.

Toponymy

Main article: Names of Seoul↗

Traditionally, seoul (서울) has been a native Korean (as opposed to Sino-Korean↗) common noun↗ simply meaning 'capital city.' The word seoul is believed to have descended from Seorabeol (서라벌; historically transliterated into the Hanja form 徐羅伐), which originally referred to Gyeongju↗, the capital of Silla↗.

Wiryeseong↗ (위례성 / 慰禮城), the capital settlement of Baekje↗, was located within the boundaries of modern-day Seoul. Seoul was also known by other various historical names, such as Bukhansan-gun (북한산군 / 北漢山郡, during the Goguryeo↗ era), Namcheon (남천 / 南川, during the Silla era), Hanyang↗ (한양 / 漢陽, during the Northern and Southern States period↗), Namgyeong (남경 / 南京, during the Goryeo↗ era), and Hanseong (한성 / 漢城, during the Joseon↗ era). The word seoul was used colloquially to refer to the capital as early as the 17th century. Thus, the Joseon capital of Hanseong was widely referred to as the seoul. Due to its common usage, French missionaries called the Joseon capital Séoul (/se.ul/) in their writings, hence the common romanization Seoul in various languages today.

Under subsequent Japanese colonization↗, Hanseong was renamed Keijō (京城, literally 'capital city') by the Imperial authorities to prevent confusion with the hanja↗ 漢 (a transliteration of a native Korean word 한), which may also refer to the Han people↗ or the Han dynasty↗ in Chinese and is associated with China in Japanese context. After World War II↗ and the liberation of Korea↗, Seoul became the official name for the Korean capital. The Standard Korean Language Dictionary↗ still acknowledges both common and proper noun definitions of seoul.

Unlike most place names in Korea, as it is not a Sino-Korean word, Seoul has no inherently corresponding Hanja (Chinese characters↗ used in the Korean language). Instead of phonetically transcribing↗ Seoul to Chinese, in the Chinese-speaking↗ world, Seoul was called Hànchéng (漢城), which is the Chinese pronunciation of Hanseong. On 18 January 2005, the Seoul Metropolitan Government↗ changed Seoul's official Chinese name from the historic Hànchéng to Shǒu'ěr (首爾). Shǒu'ěr is a phono-semantic match↗ incorporating both sound and meaning (through 首 meaning 'head', 'chief', 'first').

History

Main article: History of Seoul↗

Prehistory

There is evidence of human habitation in the area now corresponding to Seoul from 30,000 to 40,000 years before the present. Around 4,000 B.C., people of the area lived in huts with lowered floors called umjip↗. There is evidence of the consumption of cooked grain and fish by 3,000 B.C. Around 1,500 B.C., communities began transitioning into the Bronze Age↗ and farming at scale.

Due to modern Seoul's significant urbanization, Amsa-dong Prehistoric Site↗ is the only known major archaeological site in Seoul where Stone Age↗ materials have been found, although such materials have also been found in minor sites throughout the city (and all around the surrounding Han River↗ basin), often through rescue archaeology↗.

Samhan and Baekje periods

See also: Samhan↗ and Baekje↗ Around the collapse of Wiman Joseon↗ (194–108 B.C.) in the northern part of Korea, numerous refugees went south to the Han River basin, which was then controlled by Jin↗ (4th–2nd century B.C.). These diverse peoples brought with them culture and technology of the Chinese Warring States↗ that accelerated the region's progress into the Iron Age↗. Their arrival destabilized the region; Jin disintegrated, and dozens of statelets↗ emerged that competed for influence in the Han River basin.

Baekje (18 B.C. – 660 A.D.), once one of the statelets in the Mahan confederacy↗, became the dominant local power by the 2nd century A.D. Its capital was in Wiryeseong↗; Wiryeseong specific location is not known with certainty, but it is believed to have been within the bounds of the ramparts P'ungnapt'osŏng↗ and Mongchontoseong↗. This area is now in southeastern Seoul.

Silla period

In July or August 553, Silla↗ took the control of the region from Baekje, and the city became a part of newly established Sin Province (신주 / 新州). Sin (新) has both meaning of "New" and "Silla", thus literally means New Silla Province.

In November 555, Jinheung Taewang made a royal visit to Bukhansan, and inspected the frontier. In 557, Silla abolished Sin Province, and established Bukhansan Province (북한산주 / 北漢山州). The word Hanseong (한성 / 漢城) appears on the stone wall of "Pyongyang Fortress", which was presumably built in the mid to late 6th century AD over period of 42 years, located in Pyongyang, while there is no evidence that Seoul had name Hanseong dating the three kingdoms and earlier period.

In 568, Jinheung Taewang made another royal visit to the northern border, visited Hanseong, and stayed in Namcheon on his way back to the capital. During his stay, he set Jinheung Taewang Stele, abolished Bukhansan Province, and established Namcheon Province (남천주 / 南川州), appointing the city as the provincial capital. Based on the naming system, the actual name of Han River during this time was likely Namcheon (Nam River) itself or should have the word ending with "cheon" (천 / 川) not "gang" (강 / 江) nor "su" (수 / 水). In addition, "Bukhansan" Jinheung Stele clearly states that Silla had possession of Hanseong (modern day Pyongyang↗), thus Bukhansan has to be located north of Hanseong. Modern day Pyongyang was not Pyongyang, Taedong River↗ was likely Han River, and Bukhansan was not Bukhansan during the three kingdoms period. Moreover, Pyongyang was a common noun meaning capital used by Goguryeo and Goryeo dynasties, similar to Seoul.

In 603, Goguryeo attacked Bukhansanseong↗, which Silla ended up winning. In 604, Silla abolished Namcheon Province, and reestablished Bukhansan Province in order to strengthen the northern border. The city lost its provincial capital position and was put under Bukhansan Province once again. This further proves that Bukhansan was located in the North of modern-day Pyongyang as changing the provincial name and objective would not be required if Bukhansan was located within Seoul.

In the 11th century Goryeo↗, which succeeded Unified Silla↗, built a summer palace in Seoul, which was referred to as the "Southern Capital". It was only from this period that Seoul became a larger settlement.

Joseon dynasty

Further information: Joseon dynasty↗, Downtown Seoul↗, and Seongjeosimni↗

Seoul became the planned capital↗ of Korea by Yi Seong-gye↗, the founding father of the Joseon↗ dynasty. After enthroning himself as King↗ at the capital of old Goryeo↗ in 1392, Yi Seong-gye changed the name of his Kingdom from Goryeo to Joseon in 1393 and began his search for a place for a new capital. After several governmental debates, Yi Seong-gye chose Hanyang (Sindo) instead of Muak in September 1394. As Joseon's new capital, Hanyang was planned as a geographic embodiment of Korean Confucianism↗. Construction of the city began in October 1394. During its early construction stages, some major palaces, including Gyeongbokgung↗, were finished in 1395. The Fortress Wall↗ surrounding Hanyang was partially finished around 1396. p. 96–111

The city of Hanyang was governed by the Hanseongbu↗ [ko] (한성부 / 漢城府), an agency of the national government dedicated to affairs on the administration of the capital city. The Hanseongbu divided Hanyang into two major categories: areas inside the Fortress Wall, which were typically named Seong-jung (성중 / 城中) or Doseong-an (도성 안), and areas 10 Ri↗ (Korean mile) around the Fortress Wall, which were named as Seongjeosimni↗ (성저십리 / 城底十里). The Doseong-an area later gained the informal but popular name Seodaemun-an (사대문 안), which literally means 'areas inside of the Four Great Gates↗', and became the one and only downtown (city center) of Hanyang city↗. p. 90–100

In the late 19th century, after hundreds of years of isolation, Seoul opened its gates to foreigners and began modernization. Seoul became the first city in East Asia↗ to introduce electricity in the palace, which was established by the Edison Illuminating Company↗. A decade later the city also implemented electrical street lights.

Korean Empire

Main article: Korean Empire↗

After Gojong↗'s proclamation of Korea as the Korean Empire↗ in 1897, Seoul was temporarily called Hwang Seong (황성 / 皇城). Much of modern development around this era was propelled by trade with foreign countries like France and the United States. For example, the Seoul Electric Company↗, Seoul Electric Trolley Company, and Seoul Fresh Spring Water Company were all joint Korean–U.S. owned enterprises. Through these efforts,There were some modernization efforts by the late 19th century prior to annexation. Seoul became the first city in East Asia to have electricity, trolley cars, water, telephone, and telegraph systems all at the same time,

Japanese annexation of Korea

Main articles: Keijō↗ and Korea under Japanese rule↗

After the annexation treaty↗ in 1910, Japan↗ annexed Korea and renamed the city Gyeongseong↗ ("Kyongsong" in Korean and "Keijō↗" in Japanese). The city saw significant transformation under Japanese colonial rule. Imperial Japan removed the city walls, paved roads, and built Western-style buildings.

Seoul was deprived of its special status as the capital city and downsized under imperial Japan, compared to the traditional notion among people of the Joseon↗ dynasty that Seoul included the area of approximately 4 km radius surrounding the Fortress Wall↗ (i.e., Seongjeosimni; 성저십리 / 城底十里). On October 1, 1910, Imperial Japan demoted Seoul as no different than any other city within the Gyeonggi Province↗. After Imperial Japan's redistricting, Seoul only included the area inside the Fortress Wall↗ and present-day Yongsan District↗. In the 1930s, as part of Imperial Japan's war efforts leading up to the Second Sino-Japanese War↗, Yeongdeungpo District↗ was annexed into Seoul on April 1, 1936, to function as an industrial complex for steel and other metalworking↗ factories.

The city was liberated by U.S. forces at the end of World War II↗.

Contemporary history

In 1945, following the liberation from Japanese colonial rule, the American military assumed control of Korea, including its capital city, then referred to as Kyeongseongbu in line with Japanese nomenclature. The U.S. military government↗ published the Charter of the City of Seoul in the official gazette on October 10 of the following year. The charter declared Seoul as the name of the city and established it as a municipal corporation↗. Seoul's status as a municipal corporation mirrored the independent cities↗ in the United States that do not belong to any county, and Seoul was established as an independent administrative unit, separate from the existing provinces. The Korean version of the Charter translated "municipal corporation" as "special free city" (특별자유시 / 特別自由市), which later became special metropolitan city↗ (or special metropolitan city; 특별시 / 特別市) in the Local Autonomy Act of 1949↗ [ko]. Seoul has retained its status as the only special metropolitan city in South Korea.

The City of Seoul is hereby constituted a municipal corporation to be known as SEOUL. The boundaries of the municipal corporation are the present limits of the City of Seoul consisting of the following eight districts: Chong Koo↗, Chong No Koo↗, Sur Tai Moon Koo↗, Tong Tai Moon Koo↗, Sung Tong Koo↗, Ma Po Koo↗, Yong San Koo↗, and Yang Doung Po Koo↗, and as such may be extended as provided by law.

U.S. Army Military Government in Korea, Charter of the City of Seoul

Seoul under the U.S. military government between 1945 and 1948 was much smaller than it is today. It only covered the Fortress Wall↗, marked by the Eight Gates↗, and the districts incorporated during Japanese rule to prosecute imperial Japan's war efforts.

During the Korean War↗, Seoul changed hands between the Soviet- and Chinese-backed North Korean forces and the American-backed South Korean forces four times: falling to the North Koreans in the June 1950 First Battle of Seoul↗, recaptured by UN forces in the September 1950 Second Battle of Seoul↗, falling to a combined Chinese-North Korean force in the January 1951 Third Battle of Seoul↗, and finally being recaptured once more by UN forces in Operation Ripper↗ during the spring of 1951. The extensive fighting left the city heavily damaged after the war. The capital was temporarily relocated to Busan↗. One estimate of the extensive damage states that after the war, at least 191,000 buildings, 55,000 houses, and 1,000 factories lay in ruins. In addition, a flood of refugees had entered Seoul during the war, swelling the population of the city and its metropolitan area to an estimated 1.5 million by 1955.

Following the war, Seoul began to focus on reconstruction and modernization. As South Korea's economy started to grow rapidly↗ from the 1960s, urbanization↗ also accelerated and workers began to move to Seoul and other larger cities. In 1963, Seoul went through two major expansions that established the shape and size of the present-day Seoul—barring minor adjustments to the borders later in 1973 and 2000. In August 1963, Seoul annexed parts of Yangju-gun↗, Gwangju-gun↗, Siheung-gun↗, Gimpo-gun↗, and Bucheon-gun↗, expanding the northeastern borders of Seoul. In September, Seoul again annexed present-day Gangnam↗. The two consecutive expansions more than doubled the size of Seoul from approximately 268 km² to 613 km².

After annexation, Gangnam↗'s development was spurred by key infrastructure projects: the construction of the Hannam Bridge↗ (1966–1969) and Gyeongbu Expressway↗ (1968–1970). As Seoul's population kept growing, Park↗'s regime focused its development plans on Gangnam. The main hurdle for Gangnam's development was floods because the area is low-lying and prone to flooding. Then Seoul mayor Kim Hyun-ok ordered construction of an expressway that doubled as embankment↗, which became the present-day Gangbyeon Expressway↗. The construction started in March 1967 and completed in September of the same year. Similar projects transformed previously flood-prone areas into usable land for development. Such areas include the current Ichon-dong↗, the Banpo apartment complex↗, Apgujeong-dong↗ and Jamsil-dong↗.

Until 1972, Seoul was claimed by North Korea as its de jure capital, being specified as such in Article 103 of the 1948 North Korean constitution↗.

Seoul was the host city of the 1986 Asian Games↗ and 1988 Summer Olympics↗ as well as one of the venues of the 2002 FIFA World Cup↗.

South Korea's 2019 population↗ was estimated at 51.71 million, and according to the 2018 Population and Housing Census, 49.8% of the population resided in the Seoul metropolitan area. This was up by 0.7% from 49.1% in 2010, showing a distinct trend toward the concentration of the population in the capital. Seoul has become the economic, political and cultural hub of the country, with several Fortune Global 500↗ companies, including Samsung↗, SK Holdings↗, Hyundai↗, POSCO↗ and LG Group↗ headquartered there.

Geography

Seoul is in the northwest of South Korea. Seoul proper comprises 605.25 km², with a radius of approximately 15 km, roughly bisected into northern and southern halves by the Han River↗. The river is no longer actively used for navigation, because its estuary↗ is located at the borders of the two Koreas, with civilian entry barred. There are four main mountains in central Seoul: Bugaksan↗, Inwangsan↗, Naksan↗ and Namsan↗. The Seoul Fortress Wall↗, which historically bounded the city, goes over these mountains. The city is bordered by eight mountains, as well as the more level lands of the Han River plain and western areas.

Parks

Main article: List of parks in Seoul↗

Seoul has a large number of parks. One of the most famous parks is Namsan Park↗, which offers recreational hiking and views of the downtown Seoul↗ skyline, especially via its N Seoul Tower↗. Seoul Olympic Park↗, located in Songpa District↗ and built to host the 1988 Summer Olympics, is the largest park. The areas near the stream Tancheon↗ are popular for exercise. Cheonggyecheon↗ also has spaces for recreation. In 2017 the Seoullo 7017 Skypark↗ opened, spanning diagonally overtop Seoul Station.

There are also many parks along the Han River↗, such as Ichon Hangang Park, Yeouido Hangang Park, Mangwon Hangang Park, Nanji Hangang Park, Banpo Hangang Park, Ttukseom Hangang Park and Jamsil Hangang Park. The Seoul National Capital Area also contains a green belt↗ aimed at preventing the city from sprawling↗ out into neighboring Gyeonggi Province. These areas are frequently sought after by people looking to escape from urban life on weekends and during vacations.

Air quality

See also: Air pollution in South Korea↗

Atmospheric pollution

Air pollution↗ is a major issue in Seoul. According to the 2016 World Health Organization↗ Global Urban Ambient Air Pollution Database, the annual average PM2.5↗ concentration in 2014 was 24 ug/m³, which is 2.4 times higher than that recommended by the WHO Air Quality Guidelines↗ for the annual mean PM2.5. The Seoul Metropolitan Government↗ monitors and publicly shares real-time air quality data.

Since the early 1960s, the Ministry of Environment↗ has implemented a range of policies and air pollutant standards to improve and manage air quality for its people. The "Special Act on the Improvement of Air Quality in the Seoul Metropolitan Area" was passed in December 2003. Its 1st Seoul Metropolitan Air Quality Improvement Plan (2005–2014) focused on improving the concentrations of PM10↗ and nitrogen dioxide↗ by reducing emissions. As a result, the annual average PM10 concentrations decreased from 70.0 μg/m3 in 2001 to 44.4 μg/m3 in 2011 and 46 μg/m3 in 2014. As of 2014, the annual average PM10 concentration was still at least twice than that recommended by the WHO Air Quality Guidelines. The 2nd Seoul Metropolitan Air Quality Improvement Plan (2015–2024) added PM2.5 and ozone↗ to its list of managed pollutants.

Investment in air quality improvement between 2007 and 2020 in the order of US$9 billion on the part of three key local authorities, namely Gyeonggi, Incheon and Seoul, delivered a clear legal framework of responsibility, publicly checkable results and a major focus on reduction of transport pollutants. In July 2020, South Korea, then the 11th largest world economy, announced a US$35 billion position on ending investment in coal. In November 2020, South Korea committed to a carbon-neutral economy by 2050. Between 2005 and 2021 annual concentration levels of small particulate matter (PM10) fell by 30-40 % in Seoul, whilst concentrations of larger particulate matter (PM 2.5) in the same period fell by 19% across the country and more in Seoul and Gyeonggi.

Asian dust↗, emissions from Seoul and in general from the rest of South Korea, as well as emissions from China, all contribute to Seoul's air quality. Besides air quality, greenhouse gas emissions represent hot issues in South Korea since the country is among top-10 strongest emitters in the world. Seoul is the strongest hotspot of greenhouse gas emissions in the country and according to satellite data, the persistent carbon dioxide anomaly over the city is one of the strongest in the world. Air quality is monitored by geo-stationary satellite measurements centred on Korea and its immediate neighbours.

Air pollution inside the Metro system

In January 2024 Seoul Metro↗, whose passengers at the time numbered approximately 7 million a day, announced plans for extensive pollution reduction measures across the network. The target was to cut pollution to over 30% below the legal limit of 50 μg/m3. It was 32 μg/m3 by 2026. The outset actuality was 38.8 μg/m3 average concentration of pollution. Starting in 2024, ₩100 billion annually for three years was earmarked for air pollution reduction measures. These included installation of air conditioning, better ventilation systems and filters, replacement of dust-inducing gravel rail tunnel beds with concrete ones, dust-capture matting at turnstiles, and constant public readings for pollution within the system.

Climate

Main article: Climate of Seoul↗

Seoul has a humid continental↗ (Köppen↗: Dwa) or humid subtropical climate↗ (Cwa, by −3 °C isotherm), influenced by the monsoon↗s; there is great variation in temperature and precipitation throughout the year. The suburbs of Seoul are generally cooler than the center of Seoul because of the urban heat island↗ effect. Summers are hot and humid, with the East Asian monsoon↗ taking place from June until July and typhoon↗s taking place any time between July and September. August, the hottest month, has average high and low temperatures of 30.0 °C and 22.9 °C with higher temperatures possible. Heat index↗ values can surpass 40 °C at the height of summer. Winters are usually cold to freezing with average January high and low temperatures of 2.1 °C and −5.5 °C, and are generally much drier than summers, with an average of 24.9 days of snow annually. Sometimes, temperatures drop dramatically to below −10 °C, and on some occasions as low as −15 °C in the mid winter period of January and February. Temperatures below −20 °C have been recorded.

Government

Main article: Seoul Metropolitan Government↗

The Seoul Metropolitan Government is the local government for Seoul, and is responsible for the administration and provision of various services to the city, including correctional institutions, education, libraries, public safety, recreational facilities, sanitation, water supply, and welfare services. It is headed by a mayor and three vice mayors, and is divided into 25 autonomous districts and 522 administrative neighborhoods.

Administrative districts

Main article: List of districts of Seoul↗

Seoul is divided into 25 "gu↗" (구 / 區) (district). The gu vary greatly in area (from 10 to 47 km²) and population (from fewer than 140,000 to 630,000). Songpa↗ has the most people, while Seocho↗ has the largest area. The government of each gu handles many of the functions that are handled by city governments in other jurisdictions. Each gu is divided into "dong↗" (동 / 洞), or neighborhoods. Some gu have only a few dongs while others like Jongno District have a very large number of distinct neighborhoods. Seoul has 467 administrative dongs (행정동 / 行政洞) in total.

Demographics

Historical populations:

1949: 1,437,670
1960: 2,445,402
1970: 5,433,198
1980: 8,364,379
1990: 10,612,577
2000: 9,895,217
2010: 9,794,304
2020: 9,586,195

Seoul proper is noted for its population density↗, which is almost twice that of New York City↗ and eight times greater than Rome↗. Its metropolitan area was the most densely populated among OECD↗ countries in Asia in 2012, and second worldwide after that of Paris↗.

The population of Seoul has been dropping since the early 1990s, with reasons including high costs of living, especially housing; urban sprawl to Gyeonggi region's satellite cities; and an aging population. Seoul also has an extremely low birth rate. In 2023, Seoul's fertility rate was recorded at 0.55, low even in comparison to the nationwide fertility rate of 0.72.

As of 2016, the number of foreigners living in Seoul was 404,037, 22.9% of the total foreign population in South Korea. As of June 2011, 186,631 foreigners were Chinese↗ citizens of Korean ancestry. This was an 8.84% increase from the end of 2010 and a 12.85% increase from June 2010. The next largest group was Chinese citizens who were not of Korean ethnicity; 29,901 of them resided in Seoul. The next highest group consisted of the 9,999 United States citizens who were not of Korean ancestry. The next highest group were Taiwanese citizens, at 8,717.

Religion

The two major religions in Seoul are Christianity↗ and Buddhism↗. Other religions include Muism↗ (indigenous religion) and Confucianism↗. Seoul is home to one of the world's largest Christian congregations, Yoido Full Gospel Church↗, which has around 830,000 members. According to the 2015 census, 10.8% of the population follows Buddhism and 35% follows Christianity (24.3% Protestantism and 10.7% Catholicism). 53.6% of the population is irreligious. Seoul is home to the world's largest modern university founded by a Buddhist Order, Dongguk University↗. The city also features Seoul Central Mosque↗, opened in 1976.

Education

Further information: Education in South Korea↗ and List of universities in Seoul↗

Compulsory education lasts from grade 1–9 (six years of elementary school and three years of middle school). Students spend six years in elementary school, three years in middle school, and three years in high school. Secondary schools generally require students to wear uniforms. There is an exit exam for graduating from high school and many students proceeding to the university level are required to take the College Scholastic Ability Test↗ that is held every November. Although there is a test for non-high school graduates, called school qualification exam, most Koreans take the test.

Seoul is home to various specialized school↗s, including three science high schools, and six foreign language High Schools. Seoul Metropolitan Office of Education comprises 235 College-Preparatory High Schools, 80 Vocational Schools, 377 Middle Schools, and 33 Special Education Schools as of 2009.

Seoul is home to the majority of South Korea's most prestigious universities, including the three SKY Universities↗: Seoul National University↗, Yonsei University↗ and Korea University↗. Seoul ranked 2nd on the QS Best Student Cities 2023↗. And in 2025, Seoul ranked 1st on the QS Best Student Cities 2026.

Economy

Main article: Economy of Seoul↗

See also: Economy of South Korea↗

Seoul is the business and financial hub of South Korea. Although it accounts for only 0.6 percent of the nation's land area, 48.3 percent of South Korea's bank deposits were held in Seoul in 2003, and the city generated 23 percent of the country's GDP overall in 2012. In 2008 the Worldwide Centers of Commerce↗ Index ranked Seoul No.9. The Global Financial Centres Index↗ in 2015 listed Seoul as the 6th financially most competitive city in the world. The Economist Intelligence Unit↗ ranked Seoul 15th in the list of "Overall 2025 City Competitiveness" regarding future competitiveness of cities.

Manufacturing

See also: Manufacturing in South Korea↗ The traditional, labor-intensive manufacturing industries have been continuously replaced by information technology↗, electronics↗ and assembly-type of industries; however, food and beverage production, as well as printing and publishing remained among the core industries. Major manufacturers are headquartered in the city, including Samsung↗, LG↗, Hyundai↗, Kia↗ and SK↗. Notable food and beverage companies include Jinro↗, whose soju↗ is the most sold alcoholic drink in the world, beating out Smirnoff↗ vodka↗; top selling beer producers Hite↗ (merged with Jinro) and Oriental Brewery↗. It also hosts food giants like Seoul Dairy Cooperative↗, Nongshim Group↗, Ottogi, CJ↗, Orion, Maeil Holdings, Namyang Dairy Products↗ and Lotte↗.

Business and finance

See also: Yeouido↗ and Korea Exchange↗

According to the Global Financial Centerss Index report↗ released in 2024, Seoul ranked 10th. The city ranked 13th in business environment and financial sector development, seventh in human capital, 10th in infrastructure and 12th in reputation.

Seoul has three central business districts↗; the Downtown Seoul↗(CBD), Gangnam↗(GBD), and Yeouido↗(YBD). The Downtown Seoul, which has 600 years of history as unparalleled business district in entire Korea, is now a densely concentrated area around Gwanghwamun↗ and Cheonggyecheon↗ with headquarters of major companies, foreign financial institutions, largest news agencies and law firms. Other two business districts are developed in 1970s and have different characteristic; while Gangnam is well known for tech, luxury and private education industries, Yeouido is famous for securities exchange and asset management.

In 2023, the city announced plans to invest $44.7 million over six years to create a dedicated area to attract foreign investment.

Commerce

Main article: Shopping in Seoul↗

The largest wholesale and retail market in South Korea, the Dongdaemun Market↗, is located in Seoul. Myeongdong↗ is a shopping and entertainment area in downtown Seoul↗ with mid- to high-end stores, fashion boutiques and international brand outlets. The nearby Namdaemun Market↗, named after the Namdaemun Gate↗, is the oldest continually running market in Seoul.

Insadong↗ is the cultural art market of Seoul, where traditional and modern Korean artworks, such as paintings, sculptures and calligraphy are sold. Hwanghak-dong Flea Market↗ and Janganpyeong Antique Market also offer antique products. Some shops for local designers have opened in Samcheong-dong↗, where numerous small art galleries are located. While Itaewon↗ had catered mainly to foreign tourists and American soldiers based in the city, Koreans now comprise the majority of visitors to the area. The Gangnam district↗ is one of the most affluent areas in Seoul and is noted for the fashionable and upscale Apgujeong-dong↗ and Cheongdam-dong↗ areas and the COEX Mall↗. Wholesale markets include Noryangjin Fisheries Wholesale Market↗ and Garak Market↗.

The Yongsan Electronics Market↗ is the largest electronics market in Asia. Electronics markets are Gangbyeon station metro line 2 Techno mart, ENTER6 MALL & Shindorim station Technomart mall complex. Times Square↗ is one of Seoul's largest shopping malls, and contains the world's largest permanent 35 mm↗ cinema screen, the CGV Starium↗.

Korea World Trade Center Complex, which comprises COEX mall, congress center, 3 Inter-continental hotels, Business tower (Asem tower), Residence hotel, Casino and City airport terminal was established in 1988 in time for the Seoul Olympics↗. The 2nd World trade trade center is being planned at Seoul Olympic stadium complex as MICE HUB by Seoul. Ex-Kepco head office building was purchased by Hyundai motor group with 9billion USD to build 115-storey Hyundai GBC & hotel complex until 2021. Now ex-kepco 25-storey building is under demolition. Further information about the logistics and shipping company: Ilyang Logistics↗

Technology

See also: South Korean robotics↗ Seoul has been described as the world's "most wired city", ranked first in technology readiness by PwC↗'s Cities of Opportunity report. Seoul has a very technologically advanced infrastructure↗.

Seoul is among the world leaders in Internet connectivity, being the capital of South Korea, which has the world's highest fiber-optic↗ broadband penetration and highest global average internet speeds of 26.1 Mbit/s. Since 2015, Seoul has provided free Wi-Fi access in outdoor spaces through a 47.7 billion won ($44 million) project with Internet access at 10,430 parks, streets and other public places. Internet speeds in some apartment buildings reach up to 52.5 Gbit/s with assistance from Nokia, and though the average standard consists of 100 Mbit/s services, providers nationwide are rapidly rolling out 1Gbit/s↗ connections at the equivalent of US$20 per month. In addition, the city is served by the KTX↗ high-speed rail↗ and the Seoul Subway↗, which provides 4G LTE↗, Wi-Fi, and DMB↗ inside subway cars. 5G will be introduced commercially in March 2019 in Seoul.

Culture

Architecture

See also: List of tallest buildings in Seoul↗ and Architecture of South Korea↗ The traditional heart of Seoul is the old Joseon dynasty city, now the downtown area↗, where most palaces, government offices, corporate headquarters, hotels, and traditional markets are located. Cheonggyecheon↗, a stream that runs from west to east through the valley before emptying into the Han River, was for many years covered with concrete, but was recently restored by an urban revival project in 2005. Jongno↗ street, meaning "Bell Street", has been a principal street and one of the earliest commercial streets of the city, on which one can find Bosingak↗, a pavilion containing a large bell.

Seoul has many historical and cultural landmarks. In Amsa-dong Prehistoric Settlement Site↗, Gangdong District↗, neolithic remains were excavated and accidentally discovered by a flood in 1925.

Urban and civil planning was a key concept when Seoul was first designed to serve as a capital in the late 14th century. The Joseon dynasty built the "Five Grand Palaces" in Seoul—Changdeokgung↗, Changgyeonggung↗, Deoksugung↗, Gyeongbokgung↗ and Gyeonghuigung↗—all of which are located in the Jongno and Jung Districts. Among them, Changdeokgung was added to the UNESCO World Heritage↗ List in 1997 as an "outstanding example of Far Eastern palace architecture and garden design". The main palace, Gyeongbokgung, underwent a large-scale restoration project. UNESCO also recognizes Seoul as a "Design City↗".

Seoul has been surrounded by walls that were built to regulate visitors from other regions and protect the city in case of an invasion. Pungnap Toseong↗ is a flat earthen wall built at the edge of the Han River, which is widely believed to be the site of Wiryeseong↗. Mongchon Toseong↗ is another earthen wall built during the Baekje period that is now located inside the Olympic Park↗. The Fortress Wall↗ of Seoul was built early in the Joseon dynasty for protection of the city. After many centuries of destruction and rebuilding, about 2/3 of the wall remains, as well as six of the original eight gates↗. These gates include the south gate Namdaemun↗ and the east gate Dongdaemun. Namdaemun was the oldest wooden gate until a 2008 arson attack, and was re-opened after complete restoration in 2013.

Museums

Main article: List of museums in Seoul↗

See also: List of museums in South Korea↗

Seoul is home to 115 museums, including four national and nine official municipal museums. The National Museum of Korea↗ has a collection of 220,000 artifacts. The National Folk Museum↗ is located on the grounds of Gyeongbokgung and focuses on the daily life of historical Koreans. Bukchon Hanok Village↗ and Namsangol Hanok Village↗ are old residential districts consisting of hanok↗ (traditional Korean houses).

The War Memorial↗ covers the history of wars that Korea has been involved with, especially the Korean War↗. Seodaemun Prison↗ is a former prison built during the Japanese occupation, and is used as a historic museum. The Seoul Museum of Art↗, Leeum, Samsung Museum of Art↗, and Ilmin Museum of Art↗ are art museums in the city.

Festivals

See also: List of South Korean festivals↗

In October 2012, KBS Hall↗ in Seoul hosted major international music festivals – First ABU TV and Radio Song Festivals within frameworks of Asia-Pacific Broadcasting Union↗ 49th General Assembly. Seoul Street Art Festival↗ is a seasonal cultural festival held four times a year every spring, summer, autumn, and winter in Seoul, South Korea since 2003. It is based on the "Seoul Citizens' Day" held on every October since 1994 to commemorate the 600 years history of Seoul as the capital of the country. The festival is arranged under the Seoul Metropolitan Government↗. As of 2012, Seoul has hosted Ultra Music Festival↗ Korea, an annual dance music festival that takes place on the 2nd weekend of June.

Media

Further information: Media of South Korea↗

Seoul is home of the major South Korean networks KBS↗, SBS↗, and MBC↗. The city is also home to the major South Korean newspapers The Chosun Ilbo↗, The Dong-A Ilbo↗, JoongAng Ilbo↗, and Hankook Ilbo↗. In Seoul, there is a digital news operation for the New York Times↗. It can accommodate up to 50 employees. It has about 20 editors and staff. The Washington Post↗ Seoul Hub is one of the key bases of the Wall Street Journal along with that of London.

Sports

Main article: Sports in Seoul↗

Seoul is a major center of South Korean sports↗, and has the largest number of professional sports teams and facilities in the country. In the history of South Korea's major professional sports league championships, which include the K League↗, KBO League↗, KBL↗ and V-League↗, Seoul had multiple championship winners during the same season twice; in 1990, when Lucky-Goldstar FC↗ (currently FC Seoul↗) won the 1990 K League↗ and the LG Twins↗ won the 1990 KBO League, and in 2016, when FC Seoul won the 2016 K League Classic↗ and the Doosan Bears↗ won the 2016 KBO League↗.

Seoul hosted the 1986 Asian Games↗, also known as Asiad↗, 1988 Olympic Games↗, and Paralympic Games↗. It also served as one of the host cities of the 2002 FIFA World Cup↗. Seoul World Cup Stadium↗ hosted the opening ceremony and first game of the tournament. Taekwondo↗ is South Korea's national sport and Seoul is the location of the Kukkiwon↗, the world headquarters of taekwondo, as well as the World Taekwondo Federation↗.

Transportation

Main article: Transportation in Seoul↗

Seoul has a well developed transportation network. Its system dates back to the era of the Korean Empire↗, when the first streetcar lines were laid and a railroad linking Seoul and Incheon was completed. Seoul's most important streetcar line ran along Jongno until it was replaced by Line 1 of the subway system in the early 1970s. Other notable streets in downtown Seoul↗ include Euljiro↗, Teheranno↗, Sejongno↗, Chungmuro↗, Yulgongno, and Toegyero. There are nine major subway lines stretching for more than 250 km, with one additional line planned. As of 2010, 25% of the population has a commute time of an hour or longer.

Bus

Main article: Seoul Buses↗

Seoul's bus system is operated by the Seoul Metropolitan Government (S.M.G.), with four primary bus configurations available servicing most of the city. Seoul has many large intercity/express bus terminals. These buses connect Seoul with cities throughout South Korea. The Seoul Express Bus Terminal, Central City Terminal and Seoul Nambu Terminal are located in the district of Seocho District↗. In addition, East Seoul Bus Terminal in Gwangjin District↗ and Sangbong Terminal in Jungnang District↗ handles traffics mainly from Gangwon and Chungcheong provinces.

Urban rail

Main article: Seoul Metropolitan Subway↗

Seoul has a comprehensive urban railway↗ network of 21 rapid transit↗, light metro↗ and commuter↗ lines that interconnects every district of the city and the surrounding areas of Incheon↗, Gyeonggi province↗, western Gangwon Province↗, and northern South Chungcheong Province↗. With more than 8 million passengers per day, the subway is one of the busiest subway systems in the world and the largest in the world, with a total track length of 940 km. In addition, in order to cope with the various modes of transport, Seoul metropolitan government employs several mathematicians to coordinate the subway, bus, and traffic schedules into one timetable. The various lines are run by Korail↗, Seoul Metro↗, NeoTrans Co. Ltd.↗, AREX↗, and Seoul Metro Line 9 Corporation.

Train

Seoul is connected to every major city in South Korea by rail. Most major South Korean cities are linked via the KTX↗ high-speed train, which has a normal operation speed of more than 300 km/h. The Mugunghwa and Saemaul trains also stop at all major stations. Major railroad stations include:

Seoul Station↗, Yongsan District↗: Gyeongbu line (KTX↗/ITX-Saemaeul↗/Nuriro↗/Mugunghwa-ho↗)
Yongsan station↗, Yongsan District↗: Honam line (KTX/ITX-Saemaeul/Nuriro/Mugunghwa), Jeolla/Janghang lines (Saemaul/Mugunghwa)
Yeongdeungpo station↗, Yeongdeungpo District↗: Gyeongbu/Honam/Janghang lines (KTX/ITX-Saemaeul/Saemaul/Nuriro/Mugunghwa)
Cheongnyangni station↗, Dongdaemun District↗: Gyeongchun/Jungang/Yeongdong/Taebaek lines (ITX-Cheongchun↗/ITX-Saemaul/Mugunghwa)
Suseo station↗ (HSR), Gangnam District↗: Suseo HSR↗ (SRT)

Airports

Seoul is served by two international airports, Incheon International Airport↗ and Gimpo International Airport↗.

Gimpo International Airport↗ opened in 1939 as an airfield for the Japanese Imperial Army↗ and opened for civil aircraft in 1957. Since the opening of Incheon International, Gimpo International handles domestic flights along with some short haul international flights to Tokyo Haneda↗, Osaka Kansai↗, Taipei Songshan↗, Shanghai Hongqiao↗, and Beijing Capital↗ although flights to Osaka Kansai↗ and Beijing Capital↗ also operate from Incheon International.

Incheon International Airport↗ opened in March 2001 in Yeongjong↗ island. It is now responsible for major international flights. Incheon International Airport is Asia's eighth busiest airport in terms of passengers, the world's fourth busiest airport↗ by cargo traffic, and the world's eighth busiest airport↗ in terms of international passengers in 2014. In 2016, 57,765,397 passengers used the airport. Incheon International Airport opened terminal 2 on 18 January 2018.

Incheon and Gimpo are linked to Seoul by expressway↗, and to each other by the AREX↗ to Seoul Station↗. Intercity bus services are available to various destinations around the country.

Cycling

Cycling↗ is becoming increasingly popular in Seoul and in the entire country. Both banks of the Han River have cycling paths that run all the way across the city along the river. In addition, Seoul introduced in 2015 a bicycle-sharing system↗ named Ddareungi↗ (and named Seoul Bike in English).

International relations

See also: List of diplomatic missions in South Korea↗ Seoul is a member of the Asian Network of Major Cities 21↗ and the C40 Cities Climate Leadership Group↗. In addition, Seoul hosts many embassies of countries it has diplomatic ties with.

Sister cities

See also: List of twin towns and sister cities in South Korea↗ Seoul has 25 sister cities↗:

See also

Economy of Seoul↗
Geography of South Korea↗
List of cities in South Korea↗
List of most populous cities↗
List of tallest buildings in Seoul↗

Notes

References

Sources

Seoul Historiography Institute, December 20, 2015. ISBN 9788994033839
Seoul Historiography Institute, December 20, 2015. ISBN 9788994033846

External links

Wikivoyage: Seoul↗

Official sites

* *

Tourism and living information

i Tour Seoul – The Official Seoul Tourism Guide Site

Sejong the Great

Sejong (세종 / 世宗; May 15, 1397 – April 8, 1450), commonly known as Sejong the Great (세종대왕 / 世宗大王), was the fourth monarch of the Koreanic state Joseon↗. He ruled from 1418 to his death in 1450. He is widely regarded as the greatest king in Korean history, and is particularly remembered for the creation of Hangul↗, the native alphabet of the Korean language↗.

Sejong was born the third son of the future King Taejong↗ (r. 1400–1418). He was regarded as gifted, moreso than the troubled crown prince Grand Prince Yangnyŏng↗. In mid-1418, Yangnyŏng was deposed and Sejong made the crown prince. Months later, Taejong abdicated and Sejong was crowned king. Taejong served as king emeritus↗ until his death in 1422.

Sejong's reign was marked by major developments in science, technology, medicine, agriculture, and the arts. Many such efforts Sejong not only oversaw, but actively participated in. In 1420, Sejong had the government research organization Hall of Worthies↗ reestablished. It oversaw such projects as the creations of the first native Korean calendar Ch'ilchŏngsan↗ [ko], the 365-volume medical text Ŭibangyuch'wi↗ [ko], and the agricultural text Nongsa chiksŏl↗.

In 1419, Sejong launched the successful Ōei Invasion↗ against the Japanese Tsushima Island↗. This was followed by decades of peace and trade between Korea and Japan. Sejong also expanded the northern borders of Korea to roughly its current extent by launching military campaigns against and assimilating the raiding Jurchens↗, although this region would remain problematic. He also maintained positive relations with Joseon's suzerain Ming↗ while still asserting Korean autonomy. Sejong made significant tax and land reforms, which resulted in increases in agricultural production and a reduction in tax rates, without significant impact to tax income. He also led a massive expansion in the influence of Confucianism in Korea↗ and decrease in the influence of Buddhism↗. Despite his anti-Buddhist policies, he was privately Buddhist and increasingly vocalized his faith, which put him at odds with the Confucianists of his court.

Sejong had recurring and worsening health issues for much of his life. Beginning in 1445, he had the crown prince, the future King Munjong↗ (r. 1450–1452), handle the daily affairs of government. Sejong died at the age of 52 in 1450 and is buried in the tomb Yeongneung↗.

Sejong is regarded as an icon of Korean culture↗ in South Korea, where he has received numerous tributes. Sejong City↗ bears his name. Several North Korean texts reportedly skeptically evaluate Sejong as a feudal oppressor.

Names and titles

"Sejong" is the name by which he is most widely known. It is a temple name↗: a posthumous title that was given to him on the 19th day, 3rd month of 1450. Historian Gari Ledyard↗ roughly translates its meaning as "epochal ancestor". Sejong's birth name was Yi To (이도 / 李祹). In the 2nd month of 1408, Yi To was granted the name "Ch'ungnyŏng" (충녕 / 忠寧) and the title "Prince" (군 / 君). In the 5th month of 1413, Ch'ungnyŏng was granted the title "Grand Prince" (대군 / 大君). On the 27th day, 6th month of 1418, Ch'ungnyŏng was granted the courtesy name↗ "Wŏnjŏng" (원정 / 元正).

After his death, Ming↗ granted him the title of Changhŏn (장헌 / 莊憲; Pinyin↗: Zhuāngxiàn). His full posthumous title was Great King Changhŏn Yŏngmun Yemu Insŏng Myŏnghyo (장헌 영문 예무 인성 명효 대왕 / 莊憲英文睿武仁聖明孝大王).

Sejong was reportedly popularly called the "Yao-Shun East of the Sea" (해동요순 / 海東堯舜). The name references the legendary wise Chinese sage kings Yao↗ and Shun↗. "East of the Sea" refers to Korea.

Early life

Yi To was born on the 10th day, 4th month of 1397 in Chunsubang, Hanyang↗ (Seoul), Joseon↗ as the third son of father Grand Prince Chŏngan↗ and Princess Chŏngnyŏng↗. Yi To's father was the fifth son of the founding and reigning king of Joseon, Taejo↗ (r. 1392–1398).

Yi To was born five years after the founding of Joseon. His father, Grand Prince Chŏngan, had played a major role in the dynasty's establishment. In 1398, Chŏngan became embroiled in a succession crisis. He launched the First Strife of the Princes↗ [ko], which resulted in the installment of one of his brothers as King Jeongjong↗ (r. 1398–1400). After suppressing a coup in the Second Strife of the Princes↗ [ko], Jeongjong abdicated the throne in favor of Chŏngan, who became King Taejong (r. 1400–1418).

Very little is known of Yi To's early life; few records were made of him, as it had seemed unlikely that he would ascend to the throne until just before he did. One anecdote has it that the young Yi To read so much that his father became concerned for his health and took away his books; one book (the Koso sugan↗ [ko]) that was missed Yi To read several times over. Several historians have evaluated this anecdote as possibly fanciful, but Ledyard argued it was plausible given Yi To's lifelong academic interests. In 1413, Taejong told Yi To (who by then was called Ch'ungnyŏng): "you have nothing to do in particular, so you should just enjoy your life in peace". At this point, Ch'ungnyŏng was already considered to be bright and skilled at the arts, including calligraphy, the gayageum↗ (traditional Korean string instrument), and painting. That year, he began to be tutored by scholar-official Yi Su↗ [ko].

Heir to the throne

By 1406, Taejong had decided that he wished to eventually abdicate the throne to a successor while he was still alive, to reduce the probability of a succession crisis upon his death. Taejong had twelve sons, the oldest of which was Grand Prince Yangnyŏng↗. Yangnyŏng was designated the successor.

A number of anecdotes indicate that Yangnyŏng was considered to have behavioral issues. Yangnyŏng disobeyed the king frequently, neglected studying, and womanized. Taejong strictly and sternly managed Yangnyŏng's education. Historian Kim Young Soo argued that this may have pushed Yangnyŏng away from studying. The king also disliked the companions of the grand prince; on several occasions they were banned from the palace for their behavior. By contrast, various anecdotes in the Veritable Records of Taejong↗ [ko] indicate that Ch'ungnyŏng was seen as intelligent and studious by the king and various members of the court. The king frequently praised Ch'ungnyŏng and compared him favorably to Yangnyŏng, to the latter's chagrin. On several occasions, Ch'ungnyŏng chastised the misbehavior of Yangnyŏng, which only fueled the latter's resentment, although on several occasions Yangnyŏng acknowledged his brother's better judgement. The two developed a bitter rivalry.

In early 1417, it emerged that Yangnyŏng had had an affair with a woman named Ŏri (어리 / 於里), a concubine of scholar-official Kwak Sŏn↗ (곽선 / 郭璇). The incident enraged and embarrassed Taejong. Yangnyŏng angrily accused Ch'ungnyŏng of having informed their father of the affair.

In early 1418, the younger brother of Ch'ungnyŏng, Grand Prince Sŏngnyŏng↗ [ko], was deathly ill. Ch'ungnyŏng reportedly stayed by his brother's bed day and night, reading medical texts and helping with the treatment. Sŏngnyŏng died on the 4th day, 2nd month of that year. Afterwards, Taejong went to Kaesong↗ and nominally left Yangnyŏng in charge of the capital in his absence. He quietly ordered that Yangnyŏng be functionally isolated and monitored; he wished to see if Yangnyŏng would change his ways. In his father's absence, Yangnyŏng brought Ŏri back into the palace, where she gave birth to their child. When Taejong learned of this, he wept and confided to several ministers that he had little faith in Yangnyŏng's ability to govern. Historian Yoon Jeong argues that, around this time, Taejong worked on building consensus among his cabinet to have Yangnyŏng removed from his position. Their relationship reached its lowest point in the 5th month of that year, after Yangnyŏng sent a letter to his father in which he defended his actions and questioned his father's judgment.

On the 3rd day, 6th month of 1418, Taejong and his ministers held a meeting on whether to depose Yangnyŏng. The topic was contentious as it required overriding the stable practice of primogeniture↗. Despite some opposition from the queen and several in the court, it was decided that Yangnyŏng would be demoted and exiled to Gwangju↗. It was also decided that they would select the new successor based on their merits. Taejong described his second son, Grand Prince Hyoryŏng↗, as weak and overly agreeable. He then nominated Ch'ungnyŏng, whom he praised as studious and wise. The court reportedly enthusiastically agreed with Taejong's nomination. There is an anecdote that these decisions weighed heavily on Taejong, and that he wept after making them. Yangnyŏng took the news of his deposal calmly and quickly became detached from politics. Kim argued that Yangnyŏng had likely anticipated this happening. He was eventually invited back to the capital by his brother and the two got along well.

Early reign

On the 10th day, 8th month of 1418, Taejong abdicated and 21-year-old Ch'ungnyŏng (henceforth Sejong) ascended the throne at the hall Geunjeongjeon↗ in the palace Gyeongbokgung↗. Taejong, as king emeritus↗, would continue to exert great influence over Sejong until the former's death on the 10th day, 5th month of 1422. Taejong had veto power on all decisions and maintained tight control over the military. On the 26th day, 10th month of 1421, Sejong designated his son Yi Hyang as crown prince.

A number of historians have argued that Sejong's successful reign was made possible by the stability created by Taejong's competent statecraft. Historian Djun Kil Kim argued that Sejong also benefitted from being surrounded by experienced military officials that had worked under his father. By the time that Sejong took the throne, bureaucratic institutions had been in place for around 15 years.

In 1420, Sejong designed and reestablished the Hall of Worthies↗. Modern historians have likened the institution to a think tank↗; it oversaw major cultural and intellectual pursuits, especially for issues of governance, as well as the education of the king and crown prince. In 1426, he ordered that the institution began a practice called saga toksŏ↗ [ko]: allowing scholars to independently research without participating in government work; this has been likened to modern research grants.

In 1421, Sejong made Gyeongbokgung his primary palace. In 1426, he had many major gates and bridges of the palace named. By 1427, he officially moved out of the secondary palace Changdeokgung↗ and into Gyeongbokgung, although he would continue to move between the two often. Sejong greatly renovated and expanded the palace. It was during Sejong's reign that Gyeongbokgung became fully-fledged and functional; it would remain in much the same state from his reign for around a hundred years afterwards.

Science, mathematics, and technology

Sejong oversaw one of the most productive eras in Korean science. Several historians have described his reign as a "golden age" for the field.

Astronomy, meteorology, calendars, and timekeeping

Sejong oversaw significant research into astronomy↗. In 1432, a solar eclipse↗ occurred two days later than predicted; this motivated Sejong to commission the research and development of astronomical instruments↗ such as globes, planispheres↗, and sun dials. An armillary sphere↗ was created in 1433. A water clock↗ was designed by Chang Yŏngsil in 1434. In 1434 or 1438, the observatory Ganuidae↗ [ko] was established in Gyeongbokgung by order of Sejong. In 1441, Prince Yi Hyang (the future King Munjong↗) led Korean scientists Yi Ch'ŏn↗ [ko] and Chang Yŏngsil in inventing the ch'ŭgugi↗: a rain gauge↗, the likes of which would not be invented in Europe until Benedetto Castelli↗'s invention in 1639. In 1442, ch'ŭgugi were distributed around Joseon. They fell out of use in the late 16th century, but were brought back in 1770 and saw continued use until the end of the Joseon period. The sup'yo↗ (수표 / 水標), a stream gauge↗, was invented in 1442.

Under Sejong, Korea began to develop its own indigenous calendar tradition for the first time. Prior to Sejong's reign, Korea was not able to accurately calculate dates or the positions of major heavenly bodies; it instead relied on calculations and calendars from China↗. These calculations were dependent on China's position on the Earth and were thus ill-suited for use in Korea. The use of Chinese calendars was in part political; it was seen as obligatory for Joseon to defer to the use of the calendar of its suzerain, Ming. In addition, Ming guarded the calculation methods for their calendar systems. In 1433, studies on calendar systems from China and elsewhere were launched. Sejong ordered that such studies be kept secret from Ming. In 1444, Sejong's court devised a new calendar: "Ch'ilchŏngsan↗ [ko]". It used Seoul as its reference point. It allowed them to accurately predict lunar and solar eclipses in 1447. It was revised beginning in 1448, due to inconsistencies with the Chinese calendar. Historian Park Kwon Soo argued the inconsistencies were not mistakes, and were instead merely due to the differing locations of Beijing and Seoul. Nevertheless, Sinocentric Korean scholars expressed concerns about departing from Chinese calculations.

Medicine

Sejong also oversaw significant advances in Korean medicine. Historian of Korean medicine Kim Dujong argued that Sejong created "the foundation of medicine in Joseon". Sejong attempted to systematize both medical research and practice, with the latter grounded in the former. Historians Tae-jin Yi and Sang-Woon Jeon argue that innovations in medicine in Sejong's reign contributed to a multiplying of population growth between the 13th and 15th centuries.

Sejong took personal interest in medical education. In 1421, he had the medical school Ŭisŏ sŭptokkwan↗ (의서습독관 / 醫書習讀官) established. In 1427, he ordered that medical students be given support so that they can focus on their studies. In 1430, he ordered that the ŭigwa↗ [ko] (medical examination) be reformed; major texts on traditional Chinese medicine↗ and even veterinarian studies were added to the curriculum.

In 1433, the 56-volume medical text Hyangyakchipsŏngbang↗ [ko] was compiled. It became a major medical text; it was intended to serve as a comprehensive medical guide and was multiple times larger than its predecessor Hyangyak chesaeng chipsŏngbang↗ [ko]. It described hundreds of symptoms and over 10,000 treatments. The work was based on research on traditional medicine throughout Korea, and included comparisons to Chinese medicine. It became a prized source of information in Ming as well. In 1445 or 1447, the 365-volume medical text Ŭibangyuch'wi↗ [ko] was completed. Medical historian Kim Seongsu argues the text's scale dwarfs that of contemporary Chinese medical texts, and that it was possibly among the largest research projects in East Asia at the time. Kim also argued that this text may have also been applied to Sejong's treatment, as Sejong ordered that it be consulted months before he died.

In 1443, he ordered that the palace pharmacy Naeyakbang (내약방 / 內藥房) be reorganized into the royal medical agency Naeŭiwŏn↗. Sejong also made efforts to lower the cost of medicine. He implemented price controls, established a fund that subsidized more expensive medicines, and attempted to substitute expensive foreign ingredients for domestic. In 1423 and 1430, he had Korean medical researchers visit China and work with Chinese researchers to determine what native Korean ingredients could serve as adequate substitutes for Chinese ingredients. This research resulted in the creation of the 1431 medical text Hyangyak ch'aech'wi wŏllyŏng↗ (향약채취월령 / 鄕藥採取月令).

Movable type

Sejong's reign was a high point in innovations in Korean movable type↗ technology. In 1420, Sejong ordered the casting of new kyŏngja types↗ (경자자 / 庚子字). The previously used kyemi types↗ (계미자 / 癸未字) required the use of adhesive beeswax↗ to secure type to plate↗; this process was laborious and slow. The kyŏngja types instead relied on faster mechanical methods of typesetting, and allowed multiple times more pages to be printed per day. In 1434, Sejong's court cast a set of more than 200,000 kabin types↗ (갑인자 / 甲寅字) that were made of copper. The kabin types were as twice as efficient to use as kyŏngja types. Kabin type were manufactured five, six, or seven additional times in the future. After 1437, lead types began to be used. The use of such types was also regulated. Punishments were established for mistakes and poor worksmanship.

Agriculture

Sejong oversaw a notable increase in agricultural productivity. In 1429, the agricultural treatise Nongsa chiksŏl↗ was completed under order of Sejong. The work was meant to be more directly suited to Korean agriculture than Chinese works. The text contains anecdotes from experienced farmers around Korea and remained a foundational work in Korean agriculture studies until the 17th century. It contributed to a multiplication of agricultural output by the end of the reign of King Seongjong↗ (r. 1469–1494). Sejong took personal charge of an experiment on palace land on crop management in bad weather. Advancements in irrigation and the sericulture↗ were also made. Innovations in other fields during Sejong's reign, including the development of rain gauges, more accurate calendars, and tax reform, also contributed to agriculture.

Mathematics

Sejong was a significant advocate for the study and use of mathematics in Joseon. At the time, mathematics was seen as a field for lower-level bureaucrats and not Confucian scholars, especially not rulers. Sejong went against this social norm by studying mathematics himself. Sejong said of mathematics:

It is said that mathematics is nothing more than a mechanical skill, but it is indispensable to the administration of the state. But for the participation of Yi Sunji↗ [ko], Kim Tam↗ and others in the recent cadastral↗ survey, it is questionable the land could have been measured properly. By all means devise measures to ensure the maximum development of mathematics throughout the land.

In 1431, Sejong sent promising mathematicians to China for study. In 1433, a 100-volume treatise on mathematics was printed, and in 1438 five mathematics texts were added to curriculums of technical colleges; afterwards mathematics became around half their curriculum. Unlike under some other monarchs when mathematics was neglected, Sejong encouraged the use of mathematics in government; people skilled in math were employed to administer taxes, take the census, and manage currency and accounting.

Cartography

Sejong's administration also made advances in cartography↗. In 1424, Sejong ordered that a national geography be compiled. In 1432 or 1434, a collection of maps of Korea called "Sinch'an p'alto chiriji" (신찬팔도지리지 / 新撰八道地理志) was prepared based on records and surveying efforts. This work was eventually incorporated into a 1454 larger collection of maps called "Sejong sillok chiriji↗ [ko]". These maps served as foundation and reference for later maps and works.

Weaponry

Sejong commissioned the 1448 text Ch'ongt'ong tŭngnok↗ (총통등록 / 銃筒騰錄), which covered the manufacture and deployment of firearms. Sin'gijŏn↗ (fire arrow rockets) were developed and first attested to in 1448, during Sejong's reign.

Arts and culture

Music

Sejong and his administration had a major influence in Korean court music↗. Sejong observed the aak↗ genre music of the Korean court and felt that it had degenerated from ancient Chinese ideals. He and several scholars consulted Chinese texts and attempted to rejuvenate Korean practice.

From 1420 to 1425, Sejong had new court music produced. From 1423 to 1430, Sejong's chief musicologist Pak Yŏn↗ oversaw the creations of hundreds of court music instruments. In 1430, after consulting ancient Chinese musicology texts, Sejong ordered that Pak Yŏn, Chŏng Inji, and others develop new music for Confucian rites. These efforts resulted in the recreations of several ancient Chinese instruments and a musical treatise that would be appended to the Veritable Records of Sejong. Reforms on court music continued, with new songs performed in 1433. Under Sejong's reign, the first mensural notation↗ scheme in Asia was developed.

Beginning in 1433, focus shifted away from the emulation of Chinese practice to the development of native Korean practice. That year, he called for folk music↗ from around Korea be gathered, although it is unknown if this project was completed.

Research conducted on Chinese musicology in Sejong's reign was eventually compiled into the 1493 text Akhak kwebŏm↗. This work has been evaluated as an extremely valuable source of information on traditional Sino-Korean music.

Sejong composed music himself. He composed Yŏmillak↗. In 1447, he created the pieces Pot'aep'yŏng↗ (보태평 / 保太平) and Chŏngdaeŏp↗ (정대업 / 定大業). These two pieces were adapted and continued to be performed until the end of the Joseon period. He also composed the music for the 1449 Buddhist text Sari yŏngŭnggi↗ (사리영응기 / 舍利靈應記).

Ceremonial rites

In the practice of ceremonial rites, Sejong attempted to preserve Korean tradition while also introducing ancient Chinese tradition. In 1444, Sejong ordered that research on the Five Rites↗ [lt=Five Rites] be completed. Historian Martina Deuchler↗ argued that it is clear Sejong supervised the compilation and gave his own input. Once completed in 1451, a copy of the work was appended to the Veritable Records of Sejong.

Art and calligraphy

Sejong's reign is considered a high point in the history of Korean painting. Significant quantities of art were sponsored and produced during this period. Major artists of this period include literati painter↗ Kang Hŭian↗, Ch'oe Kyŏng↗ [ko], Yi Sangjwa↗ [ko], and An Kyŏn↗. In 1447, An produced the landmark painting Mongyudowŏndo↗ [ko], which is said to be based on a dream of Sejong's third son Grand Prince Anp'yŏng↗ [ko]. Calligraphy also florished; that grand prince was himself a renowned calligrapher.

Literature

Sejong has been described as a "bibliophile↗". Anecdotes indicate that Sejong enjoyed reading as well as the collection and preservation of rare books. In 1442, he ordered governors in the southern provinces to gather information on his father's past exploits in suppressing Japanese pirates; these stories were developed into the work Yongbiŏch'ŏn'ga↗. That work then became the first major piece of literature in Hangul, after its Korean poems were completed around 1447.

Domestic policy

Sejong attempted to govern primarily by Confucian principles. According to historian Christopher Lovins, Sejong's reign is widely viewed as the "full flowering of Confucianism in Korea".

Sejong believed that deliberation was important to good governance. Although Sejong was one of the most powerful Joseon monarchs, he and other Joseon monarchs were generally strongly checked by the high bureaucracy. Several historians have evaluated Sejong as open, in part intentionally, to vigorous debate and even criticism. He very frequently asked questions and advice of others. Historian James Palais↗ argued that Sejong was not a despot; he said that while Sejong was "subjected to criticism and restraint that in other monarchies would be regarded as lèse-majesté↗", he was "able to control [his critics] by besting them at their own game rather than by resorting to force and punishment". Ledyard wrote of Sejong's policymaking, "in everything [Sejong] seems to have had an evenness of judgment, a fairness, common sense, a lack of prejudice".

Sejong maintained the policy of sinmun'go↗ [ko], wherein commoners with grievances were allowed to beat a drum at the magistrate's office and have their complaint heard.

Unlike his predecessors, Sejong regularly and even enthusiastically attended the Confucian lectures meant for the king↗ [lt=Confucian lectures meant for the king]. On one occasion, he insisted on attending the lectures even while mourning the death of his father, in order to set an example for future rulers on how important the lectures were. He attended it every day for nearly 22 of his 32 years as king. He assigned around 10 academicians of the Hall of Worthies to research, develop, and deliver the lectures. He also performed his own research and gave input on the curriculum. According to Ledyard's analysis, Sejong's academic interests did not distract from his administrative duties. Sejong opened the court daily at dawn, and after receiving ceremonial visits, went straight into state meetings.

Sejong had a significant impact on curricula for crown princes of Joseon. In 1421, the crown prince began attending the royal lectures with his father. In 1428, he had the Chonghak↗ [ko] established. This institution was directly focused on the education of the royal family, whereas previously, their education was handled by a variety of institutions.

Sejong mostly maintained his father's policy of honoring the former royal House of Wang↗, which had ruled Goryeo. By Sejong's reign, the surviving members of that family were all female. Sejong allowed them to remain aristocrats and live freely. He ordered that the tombs of the former Goryeo monarchs be properly maintained. When several Wang women were involved in legal disputes, Sejong showed amnesty to them. Still, Sejong and his court viewed the women with some suspicion.

Sejong ordered the compilations or revisions of the Veritable Records of his three predecessors. Under his administration, key practices around the production of the Veritable Records began, including the practice of making four extra copies of the records for distribution around Korea. This practice would end up saving the Veritable Records for modern historical use, as most copies were destroyed by the Japanese in 1592, during the Imjin War.

Legal system

Historian Young Kyun Oh argued Sejong attempted to relatively strictly abide by the Great Ming Code↗, the Chinese legal code adopted as the basis of Joseon's laws in 1392. Oh evaluated Sejong's deviations from the code as reluctant and minor. Park evaluated Sejong as resistant to suggestions of punishing people for what he viewed as minor offenses.

Sejong actively participated in revising Joseon's supplementary legal code. In 1420 or 1422, Sejong ordered that the legal code Joseon had been using, the Kyŏngje yukchŏn↗ [ko], be revised. The first draft of the revised code was completed in 1426. Another revision, called the Sinsok yukchŏn↗ (신속육전 / 新續六典) was completed in 1428. It was revised again and published in 1433 as the Sinch'an kyŏngjesok yukchŏn (신찬경제속육전 / 新撰經濟續六典). A revised version was published in 1435.

Sejong made policies that sought to improve living conditions of prisoners. He ordered that prisoners should be kept in clean prisons, fed regular meals, and not be put in conditions that are excessively cold or hot. He forbade imprisonment of people over 70 or under 15. He also had autopsy↗ practices reformed in order to provide more accurate information in legal cases.

Taxation and economics

Sejong significantly reformed the tax system of Joseon. The taphŏm sonsilpŏp↗ (답험손실법 / 踏驗損實法) tax system that had been implemented under his father's reign inadvertantly put excess strain on peasants, especially as tax officials abused the system for their own benefit. In 1421, Sejong ordered that peasants be allowed to report their own assessments of crop yields, in order to prevent tax officials from making false reports.

Work on designing a new tax system, which would eventually be called kongpŏp↗ (공법 / 貢法), began in 1427. In 1430, Sejong ordered that an extensive public opinion survey on tax policies be conducted across the social classes. Over 170,000 people were polled on; they voted on various issues and proposals, and reasons for voting against Sejong's proposals were thoroughly documented. The survey was completed that year. Afterwards, Sejong had his ministers debate the merits of each idea. The populace voted in favor of Sejong's ideas, but some of his ministers strongly rejected them. The topic was contentious and the debate lasted for 17 years. Sejong was apprehensive of making a sudden change to the tax system, in fear that he could ruin many lives. The new system was completed in 1444. It was to be gradually rolled out from localities to larger regions over the following decades. The land tax rate was lowered from 10% of the harvest to 5%. Historians have argued that this tax change improved the quality of life in the country without harming tax income, as confiscations of Buddhist temple land and increases in agricultural productivity helped offset the difference. The Hall of Worthies also formulated a variable tax rate that depended on land yields and rainfall conditions.

Sejong continued his father's work in reorganizing the Korean feudal system, in order to improve taxation and the state's ability to mobilize manpower. The organization of the hojŏk↗ (family registration system) resulted in double the amount of adult males accounted for by the state than during his father's reign.

Sejong attempted to improve access to and use of currency↗, to limited success. In 1424, Sejong had the copper coin Joseon Tongbo↗ minted, but this failed to supplant the predominant practice of bartering cloth and grain. Under Sejong, weights and measures were standardized to promote fairness in trading.

In 1445, Sejong consolidated the various records of sujoji (land given to government officials in place of salaries), previously managed by various government offices, and placed them under the administration of the Ministry of Taxation↗ (Hojo) to improve transparency in Joseon's fiscal policies.

Social issues

Sejong made multiple attempts to elevate marginalized social groups in Korea, to limited success. In 1423, Sejong attempted to elevate the severely marginalized ch'ŏnmin↗ class by dubbing them paekchŏng↗ and granting them farmland. Historians have the attempt as unsuccessful; the ch'ŏnmin continued to be marginalized and work in their hereditary marginalized sectors. The term paekchŏng began to apply to lower-class people in humble occupations. in 1432, Sejong ordered that the paekchŏng be allowed to enroll in county schools. Sejong once declared a national amnesty for those imprisoned of minor crimes. He banned slaveholders from arbitrary punishments of slaves.

In 1426, Sejong enacted a law that granted government serf (nobi↗) women 100 days of maternity leave↗ after childbirth. In 1430, this was expanded to include one month before childbirth. In 1434, he also granted the husbands 30 days of paternity leave. In 1431, Sejong issued a set of laws that set the maximum size of houses for each social class.

Sejong argued that medical treatment should not be limited to the privileged, and that even criminals deserved treatment.

Around Sejong's reign, there was a prohibition on alcohol consumption↗ for non-ceremonial purposes. Even though he was often sick, Sejong refused all medicinal liquors and took only salt water, in order to set a temperate↗ example for the populace.

The issue of whether the state should encourage the playing of the sport polo↗ was a controversial matter. Bureaucrats saw the sport as emblematic of the excesses of the Goryeo era. Spectators would become drunk and rowdy. Sejong argued that, while the sport had indeed been played excessively before, it should be kept for military examinations, as he admired the skill and agility required of its players. Ledyard argued Sejong's answer showed judiciousness and nuance. In 1425, a polo requirement was officially adopted in military examinations.

Samganghaengsilto

In 1428, a legal case was brought to Sejong's attention. A man named Kim Hwa↗ (김화 / 金禾) murdered his father↗. This was seen as an egregious offense against a fundamental Confucian relationship. Minister Hŏ Cho↗ [ko] proposed that Sejong apply the older and more draconian Tang Code↗, in order to exact a harsher punishment on Kim. Sejong refused this proposal, although the matter concerned him deeply. He brought the matter to the Hall of Worthies and explored how Confucian values could be better reinforced in the populace.

It was decided that a book providing examples of Confucian ethics could help educate the public. This resulted in the creation of the 1434 book Samganghaengsilto↗ [ko]. The text was meant to improve the lives and morals of the general populace. It compiled Chinese and Korean stories and anecdotes that illustrated ethical Confucian behavior. It also included large pictures for the sake of the illiterate. The text was initially published in Hanja and later translated into Hangul. The Hangul translation efforts later sparked backlash from Hall of Worthies scholars, including Chŏng Ch'angson↗ [ko] and Ch'oe Malli↗. Its Hangul translation was completed in 1481, decades after Sejong's death.

Buddhism

While Sejong and his predecessors privately practiced Buddhism, their policies restricted the power and influence of Buddhist institutions.

Joseon's predecessor Goryeo had been deeply Buddhist. But around the Goryeo–Joseon transition in the late 14th-century, anti-Buddhist sentiment had grown to new heights among Confucianists. Confucianists criticized the financial impact of the religion on the state (Buddhist temples were significant land and slaveholders and monks were seen as unproductive), as well as its philosophical foundations. Many of these Confucianists became significant members of the new Joseon bureaucracy. Many in Sejong's court were actively hostile to Buddhism. Yun Hoe↗ [ko], deputy director of the Hall of Worthies, wrote in 1424 to Sejong that "[w]e consider the harm of Buddhists to be prevalent still. Since the Han period the reverence for Buddha has been increasingly fervent, yet neither happiness nor profit has been gained... We think of all the heterodox teachings, Buddhism is the worst". On the other hand, a significant majority of people outside the government actively practiced Buddhism.

Unlike the Confucianists, Sejong believed that Buddhism and Confucianism could coexist, although he was critical of the economic impact that the religion was having on Joseon. Sejong's policies significantly restricted the influence of Buddhism on Joseon. Historian Pu Namchul argued that Sejong's restrictions were mainly focused on the worldly and secular impact of the religion, and were not restrictions on the religion itself. Grayson argued that by the end of Sejong's rule, Joseon became significantly more Confucianist. Sejong's restrictions on Buddhist land ownership caused the amount of productive farmland to rise from 1.2 million kyŏl↗ [ko] (unit of measurement for area of farmland) in Taejong's reign to 1.72 million. On the 5th day, 4th month of 1424, Sejong commanded that the seven Buddhist schools be reduced to two↗ [lt=seven Buddhist schools be reduced to two]: Seon↗ and Kyo↗ [lt=Kyo]. In addition, each sect was only allowed to have 18 temples each; all other temples were forced to close. The temples were additionally restricted to having fewer than 4,000 monks, slaves, and workers combined. Metal Buddhist bells and statues were melted down for weapon making. Sejong also introduced a ban on monks from entering the capital. This ban would last until the late 19th century. On the other hand, Sejong pushed back on some anti-Buddhist policies, for example the abolition of the Buddhist lantern festival↗, prohibitions on monastic institutions, and prohibitions on Buddhist rituals.

Over time, Sejong increasingly vocalized his affinity for Buddhism. Each event was met with protest and alienated him from his court. In 1418, shortly after taking the throne, Sejong established a Buddhist shrine called Naebultang↗ (내불당 / 內佛堂) on the grounds of Gyeongbokgung. In 1420, two years after Sejong ascended the throne, Sejong's mother Queen Wŏn'gyŏng↗ died. Sejong requested that a Buddhist monastery be built next to her grave out of filial respect. Taejong polled the ministers on whether the request should be accepted; implicitly, this forced the ministers to side with either Taejong or Sejong. In the end, the request was rejected. That same year, Sejong invited renowned Buddhist monk Kihwa↗ to stay and lecture in the temple Taejaam↗ (대자암 / 大慈庵) at the previous royal palace at Kaesong. Sejong also privately believed in the healing power of Buddhism. In 1420, he prayed and had others pray to the medicine Buddha Bhaisajyaguru↗ after the queen took ill. In 1423, he requested that Buddhist books from around Korea be sent to him. In 1426, it was requested that Sejong remove a dharani↗ (Buddhist inscription) on the rafters of his throne room. He accepted the request. In 1428, he had Buddhist monks enter the palace on his birthday.

To quell anti-Buddhist criticisms of him, Sejong denied his faith to others a number of times. For example, in 1439, Sejong authorized the repair of the Buddhist temple Heungcheonsa↗ in Seoul. In protest, a petition signed by 648 Confucianist students and scholars was delivered to Sejong, in which they accused Sejong of supporting Buddhism. Sejong submitted to the pressure and assured the protestors that he "had never worshipped the Buddha". In 1441, he said, "Since the Han and Tang dynasties, monarchs of China have all believed in Buddhism. I do the same".

Familial deaths in the mid-1440s deepened Sejong's devotion to Buddhism. Sejong's sons Grand Prince Kwangp'yŏng↗ [ko] and Grand Prince P'yŏngwŏn↗ [ko] died in 1444 and 1445 respectively. Queen Sohŏn died in 1446. A 1449 record says, "His Majesty has lost two princes in succesion, as well as the queen. Grief-stricken, He has come to let belief in karma↗ fill the void in his heart". Sejong had temples hold memorial ceremonies for Sohŏn. By 1445, he was practicing Buddhist vegetarianism↗. In 1448 and 1449, Sejong had a Buddhist shrine built on the palace grounds. In 1449, when Sejong fell ill, he invited the monk Sinmi↗ to conduct Buddhist services in the palace. The following year, Sinmi was granted honorary titles of respect. Grayson wrote that Sejong "died in the bosom of Buddhism".

Other religions

Sejong, like most other Joseon kings, disapproved of Korean shamanism↗. Beginning with the reign of Sejong, Korean shamans↗ were barred from entering the capital. However, he appointed some shamans to posts in the public health organization outside the capital Hwarinsŏ↗ [ko].

In 1427, Sejong issued a decree against the Huihui (Korean Muslim↗) community that had enjoyed special status and stipends↗ since the Yuan dynasty↗'s rule over Goryeo↗. The Huihui were forced to abandon their headgear, close down their ceremonial hall—a mosque↗ in Gaegyeong, present-day Kaesong↗—and worship like everyone else.

Foreign policy

Sejong continued the Tang↗ and Goryeo tradition of xianghua↗ (향화 / 向化; "submitting-foreigner status"). This was a semi-hereditary set of designations for foreigners that allowed them to reside in Korea, with certain tax and civil exemptions for at least one generation; their descendents were eventually naturalized. The status's intent was to encourage peaceful, eventual naturalization and assimilation. For settlers around the capital, Sejong had the designation limited to one generation after the original immigrants. Joseon, under Sejong, also had separate pathways for naturalization of foreigners, including the granting of clan seats↗.

Sejong also continued the practice of allowing systematized forms of tribute↗ from foreigners, namely Jurchens and Japanese people. Depending on group and status, a limited number of tributes were allowed to be given to the monarchy in exchange for political favor.

Japan–Korea relations

See also: History of Japan–Korea relations↗

Sejong and his administration caused a decrease in raids from Japanese pirates (called wokou↗) and increase in trade with Japan. Due to the peaceful contact and trade, historian James B. Lewis described the 15th century encompassing Sejong's reign as "the peak of peaceful Japanese contact with Korea prior to the end of the twentieth century".

Although pirates from Tsushima Island↗ raided Joseon's shores with declining frequency by the late Goryeo period, they still posed a threat by Sejong's reign. The pirates would steal materials, boats, and Korean people for enslavement. In 1418, a famine and the death of Tsushima leader Sō Sadashige↗ [ja] led to increased raids on Joseon. In retaliation for this, in 1419, Sejong, under his father's guidance, launched the punitive Ōei Invasion↗ against Tsushima. Joseon forces consisted of 227 ships and some 17,000 soldiers under command of Yi Chongmu↗. After 15 days of fighting, the lord of Tsushima surrendered. During this conflict, Japanese people that fled Tsushima were allowed to settle in Joseon as hyanghwa.

Joseon attempted to incorporate Tsushima into its own territory. Ten days before Joseon's punitive attack on Tsushima, Taejong claimed that Tsushima once belonged to Korea. Seven months afterwards, in 1420, the Korean court accepted a request of Tsushima lord Sō Sadamori↗ (or someone claiming to represent Sadamori) that Tsushima be absorbed into Joseon. The Joseon court then considered Tsushima to be under the administrative boundaries of Gyeongsang Province↗. This absorption was later rejected by Sadamori. Ultimately, the absorption failed to occur.

Under Sejong, Joseon successfully incentivized Japanese leaders to discourage piracy in exchange for valuable trade access. Through this strategy, Joseon was able to change its focus from security to trade management. From Taejong's reign to Sejong's, raids dropped from 4.3 invasions per year to 1.8 and trade missions increased from 20.4 per year to 31.3. Japanese traders were restricted to all but three ports of Joseon↗ [ko]; the third port was opened under Sejong in 1426. Japanese traders were also made to follow specific routes on specific days to reach the capital. In 1423, government warehouses were created for Japanese traders in the ports. In 1438, Joseon granted Tsushima lord Sō Sadamori↗ a monopoly on issuing documents of passage for Japanese people to visit Joseon. This also benefitted Joseon in that it allowed them to offshore this administrative process and the possible associated backlash from rebuffed Japanese traders. In 1439, some limited exceptions to the monopoly were granted to other Japanese lords. In the 1443 Treaty of Kyehae↗, Joseon limited the number of ships at these ports from Japan to 50 per year.

Scholars have debated how Joseon under Sejong treated Japan. Several have argued that Joseon treated parts of Japan as if they were subordinate to Joseon. Envoys from even the shogun↗ were symbolically ceremonially treated as if the shogun was a subject of Joseon. Japanese leaders were made to request copper seals (도서 / 圖書) in order to access Joseon. Japanese leaders that showed greater aptitude in preventing piracy were granted greater rank and trade with Joseon. Historian Kenneth R. Robinson argued that Joseon had a unique and flexible relationship with the fractured "Japan" (Japan was not a strongly unified political entity by this time) that changed over time. He argued Joseon borrowed elements of China's tributary system for its own purposes.

Japanese leaders frequently requested Buddhist gifts from Joseon. For example, the Ōuchi clan↗ persistently requested the wood printing blocks of the Tripitaka Koreana↗, to the chagrin of Sejong's Confucianist court. The blocks were valuable and expensive to produce copies of. Eventually, the Ōuchi clan was given printed copies of the Tripitaka instead, which were still expensive to produce.

Northern frontier and Jurchen relations

Sejong continued the work of his predecessors in pacifying and conquering the northern frontier. It was under Sejong that Korea's northern borders were expanded to reach their approximate current extent. The northern frontier was of strategic importance, as it served as the border between Korea and China, and because the local Jurchens↗ would frequently raid Korean settlements. In 1432, the Hulun Udeha tribe (Eastern Jurchens) attacked Joseon.

Sejong launched military campaigns against the Jurchens and established garrison forces to pacify local populations. He sent one such campaign in 1433, with Ch'oe Yundŏk↗ [ko] and Yi Ch'ŏn↗ [ko] in command, and another in 1437 under Kim Chongsŏ↗. The latter campaign resulted in the creation of six garrisons in the region↗ [lt=six garrisons in the region] and the current northern borders of Korea.

Sejong also opened trade with Jurchens in order to discourage raids. This was possibly, in part, motivated by their previous successes in using trade to discourage Japanese piracy. From 1437 to 1443, the Hulun Udeha tribe that had previously attacked Joseon sent at least 127 trade missions to the Joseon court. Over time, restrictions and limits were applied on Jurchen trade missions to Joseon. Such trade was intended to provide Jurchens economic alternatives to raiding. Jurchens that aided Joseon were rewarded with rank and access to trade. His administration also moved Korean settlers to conquered regions and encouraged intermarriage between Jurchens and Koreans to deter conflict. During Sejong's reign, the entire population of Hamgyong Province↗ north of Tanchon↗ was described as the descendants of Jurchen hyanghwa. They eventually became full citizens of Joseon. Jurchens were also granted nominal appointments to the Korean military. These appointments did not require military service; they were instead meant to assimilate by integrating Jurchens into the Joseon bureaucracy.

Historians have evaluated Sejong's efforts in settling and pacifying the region as having mixed success. Korean settlers struggled to make a living in the frontier and often abandoned the land. The northern regions would continue to pose threats to Joseon's security after Sejong's reign.

China–Korea relations

See also: History of Sino-Korean relations↗ and Tributary system of China↗

Historian Shih-Shan Henry Tsai argued that the reign of Sejong saw an improvement in Sino-Korean relations and that "Sino-Korean borders became marketplaces instead of war zones". Sejong and the Ming Yongle Emperor↗ often exchanged books and letters on various topics, including religion, philosophy, history, science, and technology. In 1423 alone, Sejong sent 10,000 tribute horses to Yongle. In return, Sejong received a huge quantity of silver, brocade↗, and silk↗. Sejong had the gate Yŏngŭnmun↗ erected in Seoul in 1429 as a symbolic place of greeting for arriving Chinese envoys.

Sejong sought to balance the Joseon policy of sadae↗ (Confucian deference to China) with the need for flexible governance and Korean autonomy. For example, a number of historians have argued that the semi-tributary relationships Sejong maintained with Japanese and Jurchen groups were technically forbidden by the Chinese tributary system. Under that system, tributaries to China could only interact with each other as equals, but Sejong chose to forego strict adherence to this for Joseon's benefit. Also, in at least one occasion early in his reign, Sejong expressed reluctance to perform ritual sacrifices to pray for rain; such rituals were seen as only appropriate for the Chinese emperor. Despite this, he eventually began performing the rituals. By the end of his reign, he stopped this practice. Sejong had a scholar write an essay that said that Korean kings also had the Mandate of Heaven↗, which was normally exclusively claimed by China. In 1449, when Ming requested that Joseon send 100,000 Korean troops to the Liaodong↗ area of Manchuria↗, Joseon declined.

The anti-Buddhist policies under Sejong put Joseon at odds with Ming; in dealings with China, the Joseon court attempted to allay concerns that it was suppressing Buddhism. Around that time, Buddhism enjoyed significant support among the Ming court and gentry. Korean Buddhist monks escaped to Ming: 30 during the reign of Taejong and 9 during the reign of Sejong. Sejong asked the Yongle Emperor, a devout Buddhist, if those monks could be repatriated. Fearing what would happen to the monks, the Yongle Emperor declined.

Hangul

Main articles: Origin of Hangul↗ and Hangul↗

Sejong was responsible for the development of Hangul, the native alphabet for the Korean language. It is debated to what extent Sejong was personally involved in its creation, although most scholars believe he was significantly involved. A minority of scholars believe that Sejong was the sole author. All contemporary documentary evidence suggests that he was, but many scholars argue Sejong would have been too busy to develop Hangul on his own.

Before the invention of Hangul, Korea had been using Hanja↗ (Chinese characters↗), as well as related systems like Idu↗ and Hyangchal↗, since antiquity. The difficulty of the systems limited their use to mostly upper-class people; commoners were largely illiterate. Also, the scripts are not well suited for representing the Korean language↗; the Chinese and Korean languages are not closely related↗ and differ in significant ways. Korean pronunciation and ideas could only be indirectly represented.

Due to a lack of records on the topic, it is not known when work on Hangul first began. A number of scholars have argued that the creation of the 1434 Samganghaengsilto caused Sejong to become interested in universal literacy. Also, Sejong long had a personal interest in linguistics and languages. He took a personal interest in the activities of the Bureau of Interpreters↗, and himself took Chinese lessons from early on in his reign. A 1435 record claimed that Sejong practiced colloquial spoken Chinese every other day and took lessons from famed linguist Yi Pyŏn↗ [ko]. Hangul was possibly developed in secret, in anticipation of the backlash that it eventually received, although this is debated.

The script was revealed, likely mostly completed, to Sejong's court in the 12th month of 1443. In the 2nd month of 1444, a major faction in the Hall of Worthies led by Ch'oe Malli↗ made a famous rebuke of the script. Ch'oe and several others argued that Hangul was anti-Confucian, as they felt it was too far a departure from Chinese civilization. Sejong rebutted that he felt the script was Confucian, as it was created out of a desire to benefit his subjects. Anti-Hangul sentiment was also partially motivated by elitism; literacy in Hanja was then seen as a status symbol, and promoting general literacy could be seen as harming the social positions of the elite. The script was initially dubbed ŏnmun (언문 / 諺文), which developed an elitist connotation of "vulgar writing". Sejong had Ch'oe and several others imprisoned for a single day.

At some point, Sejong recruited young men of the Hall of Worthies for a new office dedicated to Hangul that was dubbed Ŏnmunch'ŏng↗ [ko] (). It worked on developing official documentation for Hangul. It also worked on several major literary projects related to Hangul, including the 1447 rhyme dictionary Tongguk chŏngun↗ and the first major piece of Hangul literature Yongbiŏch'ŏn'ga↗.

In the 9th month of 1446, Hangul's documentation was completed and published in the texts Hunminjeongeum↗ and its companion commentary text Hunminjeongeum Haerye↗. The Hunminjeongeum was penned by Sejong himself, while the Haerye was compiled by a group of scholars of the Ŏnmunch'ŏng led by Chŏng Inji↗. The Hunminjeongeum begins with this now-famous quote:

The sounds of our country's language are different from those of the Middle Kingdom↗ and are not confluent with the sounds of characters. Therefore, among the ignorant people, there have been many who, having something they want to put into words, have in the end been unable to express their feelings. I have been distressed because of this, and have newly designed twenty-eight letters, which I wish to have everyone practice at their ease and make convenient for their daily use.

preface

Sejong attempted to lightly pressure his detractors and subjects into accepting the script, to limited success. Ledyard argues that Sejong intentionally did not aggressively force the script on others as to avoid more severe backlash. Ledyard evaluated this hypothesized strategy favorably and said it likely contributed to Hangul's eventual success. He attempted to integrate Hangul into bureaucratic examinations and the curricula of government schools like the Sŏnggyun'gwan↗, although such integrations were often removed after his death.

Despite Sejong's efforts, Hangul continued to be looked down upon until the end of the Joseon period, over 400 years later. It was only officially adopted by the government in 1894, during the Kabo Reform↗.

Later life and death

Sejong reported to having recurring and worsening health issues for much of his life; a number of these complaints were recorded in the Veritable Records. One of the earliest records of his complaints was made when he was 22 years old; he then claimed to have knee and back pain. In his 30s, he complained of back pain and began reporting problems with his vision, excess thirst↗, and excess urination↗. In his 40s, he complained of his vision problems with greater frequency. He had a reputation for enjoying the consumption of meat and having a sedentary lifestyle. Beginning in 1445, he was practicing Buddhist vegetarianism↗.

Scholars have attempted to infer what diseases he had based on historical evidence↗. The predominant hypotheses are that Sejong had either type 1↗ or type 2 diabetes↗. Medical researcher JiHwan Lee disputes that diagnosis and argues that Sejong's symptoms more closely resemble those of ankylosing spondylitis↗ (a type of arthritis). Lee argues that either type of diabetes would have been lethal to him sooner, and that Sejong did not have a clear family history of diabetes.

Beginning in 1437, Sejong began asking his ministers if lesser governmental affairs could be delegated to the crown prince, as he was feeling unwell. Historian Martina Deuchler↗ argued Sejong asked this because he intended to ease the crown prince into politics to make the succession smoother. His ministers dismissed his health concerns then and multiple times over for years onwards, including in 1438, 1439, and 1442. In 1439, he stopped attending the royal lectures due to his health issues. Finally, apparently frustrated with the lack of progress, Sejong issued an edict in 1443 in which he declared the crown prince would handle minor state affairs for the last half of each month, and that all ministers must proclaim their loyalty to him. This sparked furious protest from across the government. Some ministers balked at the idea of being presided over by the crown prince, and others expressed concerns that the division of royal authority could destabilize the state. After years of debate and compromise, in 1445, the crown prince began to handle the routine affairs of government. Historian Kim Jongmyung argues that Sejong then devoted himself wholeheartedly to working on Hangul.

In his last years, Sejong spent much of his time in his study, writing poetry. Even while in deep pain, Sejong reportedly insisted on learning and attending lectures, and would even stay up past midnight to do so. In 1446, after the promulgation of Hangul, he said to his ministers that he was "suffering from various illnesses and just waiting in the palace for death". In the last months of his life, his pains grew more serious. On the 22nd day, 1st month of 1450, he moved into the residence of Grand Prince Hyoryŏng↗ to receive treatment for his illnesses. He died on the 17th day, 2nd month of 1450 at the age of 52, in the residence of Grand Prince Yŏngŭng↗ [ko] in Gyeongbokgung's East Palace. He was the first Joseon king to die while in office. He is buried in the tomb Yeongneung↗. That tomb was originally located in what is now Seocho District↗ in Seoul, but in 1469 it was moved to what is now Yeoju↗ after it was determined that the geomantic properties of the new site were superior. He is buried alongside Queen Sohŏn↗.

Reception and legacy

Sejong has been evaluated by a number of historians as the greatest monarch in Korean history. His reign has been described as a Golden Age↗ by various historians. Of all kings of Joseon, his name is mentioned the most throughout the Veritable Records: over 2000 times. Sejong has since served as a legendary figure in Korean science. His successors venerated and made attempts to revive Sejong-era science and practice. A 2024 survey by Gallup Korea↗ of 1,777 South Koreans found that Sejong was named the second most times as their most respected historical figure, after Yi Sun-sin↗. Sejong's creation of the Korean alphabet is celebrated every 9 October as Hangul Day↗, a national holiday.

Multiple places in South Korea, including Sejong Street↗, Sejong–Pocheon Expressway↗, and Sejong City↗, South Korea's de facto administrative capital, are named after him. Various institutes such as King Sejong Station↗, the King Sejong Institute↗, the Sejong Center for the Performing Arts↗, Sejong Science High School↗, and Sejong University↗ also bear his name. A 9.5 m bronze statue of King Sejong↗, unveiled in 2009 in celebration of the 563rd anniversary of the invention of the Korean alphabet, now sits on a concrete pedestal on the boulevard of Gwanghwamun Square↗ and directly in front of the Sejong Center for the Performing Arts↗ in Seoul. The pedestal contains one of the several entrances to the 3,200 m2 underground museum exhibit entitled "The Story of King Sejong". The Sejong the Great-class destroyers↗ are also named for him. Since 1973, a portrait of Sejong has been on the South Korean 10,000-won bank note↗, along with various scientific tools invented under his reign. He was previously depicted on the 1000-hwan↗ bill and 500-hwan bill until they were decommissioned in 1962.

In North Korea, Sejong is discussed much less than in the South and more pessimistically than elsewhere. According to South Korean researcher of North Korea Lee Kyu-Duk, one North Korean history book Chosŏn t'ongsa (조선통사) claims that Hangul was invented in order to facilitate feudal exploitation of the peasantry. While the book evaluates Hangul's linguistic features positively, it downplays the contributions of Sejong in developing the script and instead attributes its development to the intellect of the masses. Lee argued the following quote from a North Korean history work was representative of North Korean writings on Sejong:

During his 30-year reign, Sejong played a major role in repelling foreign invasions, reclaiming the old territories of Goguryeo and Balhae, and developing feudal culture. However, as the monarch of a feudal state, everything he did was in service of consolidating feudalism. Thus, even during his reign, which was dubbed "an era of peace", peasant uprisings against feudal oppression and exploitation occurred several times.

Chosŏn ryŏksa sangsik (조선력사상식)

Family

Ancestry

Consorts and issue

Officially, Sejong had 18 sons and 4 daughters. He also had a 19th son, Prince Tang↗ (1442–?), that died in childhood and was never included in the family genealogy book↗.

Queen Sohŏn↗ of the Cheongsong Sim clan↗ [ko] (1395–1446)
Princess Chŏngso↗ [ko] (1412–1424)
King Munjong↗ (1414–1452), first son
Princess Chŏngŭi↗ [ko] (1414 or 1415 – 1477)
King Sejo↗ (1417–1468), second son
Grand Prince Anpyeong↗ (1418–1453), third son
Grand Prince Imyŏng↗ (1420–1469), fourth son
Grand Prince Kwangp'yŏng↗ [ko] (1425–1444), fifth son
Grand Prince Kŭmsŏng↗ [ko] (1426–1456), seventh son
Grand Prince P'yŏngwŏn↗ [ko] (1427–1445), ninth son
Grand Prince Yŏngŭng↗ [ko] (1434–1467), fifteenth son
Royal Noble Consort Sin↗ [ko] of the Cheongpung Kim clan↗ [ko] (1406–1464)
Two daughters, both died young
Prince Kyeyang↗ (1427–1464), eighth son
Prince Ŭich'ang↗ [ko] (1428–1460), tenth son
Prince Milsŏng↗ [ko] (1430–1479), twelfth son
Prince Ikhyŏn↗ [ko] (1431–1463), fourteenth son
Prince Yŏnghae↗ [ko] (1435–1477), seventeenth son
Prince Tamyang↗ [ko] (1439–1450), eighteenth son
Royal Noble Consort Hye↗ [ko] of the Cheongju Yang clan↗ (?–1455)
Prince Hannam↗ [ko] (1429–1459), eleventh son
Prince Such'un↗ [ko] (1431–1455), thirteenth son
Prince Yŏngp'ung↗ [ko] (1431–1463), sixteenth son
Royal Noble Consort Yŏng↗ [ko] of the Jinju Kang clan↗ [ko] (?–1483)
Prince Hwaŭi↗ (1425–?), sixth son
Royal Consort Pak of the Miryang Park clan↗ [ko]
Royal Consort Ch'oe↗ [ko] of the Jeonju Choe clan↗ [ko]
Royal Consort Cho (숙의 조씨 / 淑儀曺氏)
Consort Hong↗ [ko] (?–1452)
Consort Yi↗ [lt=Consort Yi]
Princess Chŏngan↗ [ko] (?–1461)
Lady Song↗ [ko] (1396–1463)
Princess Chŏnghyŏn↗ [ko] (1425–1480)
Lady Ch'a↗ [ko] (?–1444)
Daughter (1430–1431)

] The Placenta Chambers of King Sejong's Sons↗ [ko] in Seongju County↗ is a Historic Site of South Korea↗. It was built from 1438 to 1442. The plot contains nineteen placenta chambers↗ [lt=placenta chambers] (chambers that hold the placenta↗ of newborn children). Eighteen of the chambers belong to Sejong's sons and a nineteenth belongs to Sejong's grandson, King Danjong↗.

In popular culture

Television series and films

Video games

Sejong is the leader of the Korean civilization in the 2022 Leader Pass DLC of Civilization VI↗, Sid Meier's Civilization V↗, and Civilization Revolution 2↗.
Sejong is the leader of Korea in the 2022 Ara: History Untold↗.

See also

Sejong the Great-class destroyer↗
UNESCO King Sejong Literacy Prize↗

Notes

References

Sources

In English

Books

Joseon's Royal Heritage: 500 Years of Splendor. Korea Foundation↗, 2011. ISBN 978-89-91913-87-5
Adam Bohnet. Turning toward Edification: Foreigners in Chosŏn Korea. University of Hawaiʻi Press↗, 2020. ISBN 978-0-8248-8450-5 🔓
Martina Deuchler. The Confucian Transformation of Korea: A Study of Society and Ideology. Harvard University Asia Center↗, 1992. ISBN 978-0-674-16089-7
Martina Deuchler. Under the Ancestors' Eyes: Kinship, Status, and Locality in Premodern Korea. Harvard University Asia Center↗, 2015. 1 ed. ISBN 978-0-674-50430-1
John B. Duncan. The Origins of the Chosŏn Dynasty. University of Washington Press↗, October 2000. ISBN 9780295979854
James Huntley Grayson↗. Korea: A Religious History. Routledge↗, October 25, 2002. 1st ed. ISBN 978-0-7007-1605-0
Sang-woon Jeon. A History of Korean Science and Technology. NUS Press↗, 2011. ISBN 978-9971-69-402-9
Duk-kyu Jin. Historical Origins of Korean Politics. Seoul: Jisik-sanup Publications Co., Ltd., 2005. ISBN 978-89-423-3063-8
Jae-eun Kang. The Land of Scholars: Two Thousand Years of Korean Confucianism. Homa & Sekey Books, 2006a. ISBN 978-1-931907-37-8
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Indiana University Press↗, 2012-11-05. ISBN 978-0-253-00024-8
Zong-Su Kim. The History and Future of Hangeul: Korea's Indigenous Script. Brill Publishers↗, 2005. ISBN 978-90-04-21369-2
Young-Key Kim-Renaud, ed. King Sejong the Great: The Light of Fifteenth Century Korea. International Circle of Korean Linguistics, 1992. ISBN 978-1-882177-00-4
Mark Peterson↗. "The Sejong Sillok". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Yersu Kim. "Confucianism under King Sejong". In Kim-Renaud 1992
S. Robert Ramsey↗. "The Korean Alphabet". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Pokee Sohn. "King Sejong's Innovations in Printing". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Robert C. Provine. "King Sejong and Music". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Hwi-joon Ahn. "The Arts under King Sejong". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Tae-jin Yi, Sang-Woon Jeon, and Don Baker. "The Arts under King Sejong". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Won Sik Hong and Quae Jung Kim. "The Arts under King Sejong". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Byung-ho Park. "Sejong's Contributions to the Development of Legal Institutions". In Kim-Renaud 1992
Young-Key Kim-Renaud, ed. The Korean Alphabet: Its History and Structure. University of Hawai'i Press↗, 1997. ISBN 978-0-8248-1989-7
Ki-Moon Lee↗. "The Inventor of the Korean Alphabet". In Kim-Renaud 1997
Gari Ledyard↗. "The International Linguistic Background of the Correct Sounds for the Instruction of the People". In Kim-Renaud 1997
Gari Keith Ledyard↗. The Korean Language Reform of 1446: The Origin, Background, and Early History of the Korean Alphabet. 신구문화사
Ki-baik Lee. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. ISBN 0-674-61575-1
Ki-Moon Lee↗ and S. Robert Ramsey↗. A History of the Korean Language. Cambridge University Press↗, 2011. ISBN 9780511974045
James B. Lewis. Frontier Contact Between Choson Korea and Tokugawa Japan. Routledge↗, 2003. ISBN 0-203-98732-2
Jongtae Lim and Francesca Bray, ed. Science and Confucian Statecraft in East Asia. Brill Publishers↗, 2019-03-27. ISBN 978-90-04-39290-8
Kwon Soo Park. "Calendar Publishing and Local Science in Chosŏn Korea". In Lim and Bray 2019
Jongtae Lim. "Measuring the Rainfall in an East Asian State Bureaucracy: the Use of Rain-Measuring Utensils in Late Eighteenth-Century Korea". In Lim and Bray 2019
Joong-Yang Moon. "From Local Calendar (hyangnyŏk) to Eastern Calendar (tongnyŏk): the Aspiration for an Independent Calendar of the Kingdom in Late Chosŏn Korea". In Lim and Bray 2019
Andrew C. Nahm. Korea: Tradition & Transformation. Hollym International Corporation↗, 1996. 2nd ed. ISBN 1-56591-070-2
Young Kyun Oh. Engraving Virtue: The Printing History of a Premodern Korean Moral Primer. Brill Publishers↗, 2013-05-24. ISBN 978-90-04-25196-0
Eugene Y. Park. A Genealogy of Dissent: The Progeny of Fallen Royals in Chosŏn Korea. Stanford University Press↗, 2018-12-25. ISBN 978-1-5036-0208-3
Eugene Y. Park. Korea: A History. Stanford University Press↗, 2022. ISBN 978-1-5036-2946-2
Eugene Y Park, ed. The Routledge Handbook of Early Modern Korea. London: Routledge↗, 2025. 1st ed. ISBN 9781003262053
Andrew David Jackson. "Discontent". In Park 2025
Juhn Y. Ahn. "Buddhism". In Park 2025
CedarBough T. Saeji. "Performing Arts". In Park 2025
Mark Peterson↗ and Phillip Margulies. A Brief History of Korea. Facts On File↗, 2010. ISBN 978-0-8160-5085-7
Keith Pratt↗. Everlasting Flower: A History of Korea. Reaktion Books↗, 2007. ISBN 978-1861893352
Michael J. Seth. A History of Korea: From Antiquity to the Present. Rowman & Littlefield Publishers, Inc., 2010-10-16. ISBN 978-0-7425-6717-7
Michael D. Shin, ed. Everyday Life in Joseon-Era Korea: Economy and Society. Economy and Society. Brill Publishers↗, 2014-01-09. ISBN 978-90-04-26115-0
Michael D. Shin. "An Introduction to the Joseon Period". In Shin 2014
Yeon-sik Chung. "Liquor and Taverns". In Shin 2014
Ho-Min Sohn↗. The Korean Language. Cambridge University Press↗, 2001. ISBN 978-0-521-36943-5
Ho-jung Song, Deog-jae Jeon, Ki-hwan Lim, In-ho Kim, Kang-hahn Lee, E-don Choi, Yeon-sik Chung, and Young-hee Suh. A History of Korea. Academy of Korean Studies↗, 2019. ISBN 979-11-5866-604-0
Jae Jung Song. The Korean Language: Structure, Use and Context. Routledge↗, 2006. ISBN 978-1-134-33590-9
Sixiang Wang. The Sounds of Our Country: Interpreters, Linguistic Knowledge, and the Politics of Language in Early Chosŏn Korea. Rethinking East Asian Languages, Vernaculars, and Literacies, 1000–1919. Brill, 2014-01-01. p. 58–95. ISBN 978-90-04-27927-8
Sixiang Wang. Boundless Winds of Empire: Rhetoric and Ritual in Early Choson Diplomacy with Ming China. Columbia University Press↗, July 2023. ISBN 978-0-231-55601-9
Kenneth M. Wells. Korea: Outline of a Civilisation. Brill Publishers↗, 2015-06-29. ISBN 978-90-04-30005-7

Academic articles

Harald Haarmann↗. The emergence of the Korean script as a symbol of Korean identity. The Earliest Stage of Language Planning. De Gruyter Mouton, 1993. p. 143–158. ISBN 978-3-11-084898-4
Jae-Hoon Jung. "Royal Education of Princes in the Reign of King Sejong". The Review of Korean Studies. 2006-09-01, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 133–152. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓
Sook Ja Kang. "The Role of King Sejong in Establishing the Confucian Ritual Code". The Review of Korean Studies. 2006-09-01, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 71–102. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓
Chin W. Kim. "The Legacy of King Sejong the Great". Studies in the Linguistic Sciences. 2000, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 3–12. ISSN 0049-2388 🔓
Hwansoo Kim. "Buddhism during the Chosŏn Dynasty (1392–1910): A Collective Trauma?". The Journal of Korean Studies↗. 2017, vol. 22, no. 1, pp. 101–142. doi:10.1215/21581665-4153349. JSTOR 48664095. ISSN 0731-1613
Jongmyung Kim. "King Sejong's Buddhist Faith and the Invention of the Korean Alphabet: A Historical Perspective". Korea Journal↗. September 2007, vol. 47, no. 3, pp. 134–159. doi:10.25024/kj.2007.47.3.134 🔓
Seongsu Kim. "Health Policies under Sejong: The King who Searched for the Way of Medicine". The Review of Korean Studies. June 2019, vol. 22, no. 1, pp. 135–171. doi:10.25024/review.2019.22.1.005. ISSN 1229-0076 🔓
Yung Sik Kim. "Problems and Possibilities in the Study of the History of Korean Science". Osiris↗. 1998, vol. 13, pp. 48–79. doi:10.1086/649280. JSTOR 301878. ISSN 0369-7827
Young-Key Kim-Renaud. "Sejong's Theory of Literacy and Writing". Studies in the Linguistic Sciences. 2000, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 13–45. ISSN 0049-2388 🔓
Yŏnung Kwŏn. "The Royal Lecture and Confucian Politics in Early Yi Korea". Korean Studies↗. 1982, vol. 6, pp. 41–62. JSTOR 23717630. ISSN 0145-840X
Gari Keith Ledyard↗. "The Cultural Work of Sejong the Great". November 2002. p. 7–18 🔓
Jee Kyoung Lee. "The Aggressive National Defense Posture Taken during the Reign of King Sejong of the Joseon Dynasty". The Review of Korean Studies. 2006-09-01, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 153–180. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓
JiHwan Lee. "Did Sejong the Great have ankylosing spondylitis? The oldest documented case of ankylosing spondylitis". International Journal of Rheumatic Diseases. 2021, vol. 24, no. 2, pp. 203–206. doi:10.1111/1756-185X.14025. ISSN 1756-185X
Ki-Moon Lee↗. "Reflections on the Invention of the Hunmin jeongeum". Scripta. September 2009, vol. 1, pp. 1–34. ISSN 2092-7215 🔓
Christopher Lovins. "Monarchs, Monks, and Scholars: Religion and State Power in Early Modern England and Korea". Journal of Asian History↗. 2019, vol. 53, no. 2, pp. 267–285. doi:10.13173/jasiahist.53.2.0267. JSTOR 10.13173/jasiahist.53.2.0267. ISSN 0021-910X
Doohyeon Paek. "Hunmin jeongeum: Dissemination Policy and Education". Scripta. September 2011, vol. 2, pp. 1–23. ISSN 2092-7215 🔓
Hyun-mo Park. "King Sejong's Deliberative Politics: With Reference to the Process of Tax Reform". The Review of Korean Studies. 2005-09-01, vol. 8, no. 3, pp. 57–90. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓
Namchul Pu. "Buddhism and Confucianism in King Sejong's State Administration: Tension and Unity between Religion and Politics". The Review of Korean Studies. 2005-09-01, vol. 8, no. 3, pp. 25–46. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓
Kenneth R. Robinson. "From Raiders to Traders: Border Security and Border Control in Early Chosŏn, 1392–1450". Korean Studies↗. 1992, vol. 16, pp. 94–115. JSTOR 23720024. ISSN 0145-840X
Kenneth R. Robinson. "The Tsushima Governor and Regulation of Japanese Access to Chosŏn in the Fifteenth and Sixteenth Centuries". Korean Studies↗. 1996, vol. 20, pp. 23–50. JSTOR 23719601. ISSN 0145-840X
Kenneth R. Robinson. "Organizing Japanese and Jurchens in Tribute Systems in Early Chosŏn Korea". Journal of East Asian Studies↗. 2013, vol. 13, no. 2, pp. 337–360. doi:10.1017/S1598240800003969. JSTOR 23418780. ISSN 1598-2408
Robert C. Provine. "The Treatise on Ceremonial Music (1430) in the Annals of the Korean King Sejong". Ethnomusicology. 1974, vol. 18, no. 1, pp. 1–29. doi:10.2307/850057. JSTOR 850057. ISSN 0014-1836
Giovanni Volpe. "Reading at the Joseon Court: The Practice and Representation of Reading in the Sejong sillok (1418–1450)". Seoul Journal of Korean Studies. 2023, vol. 36, no. 1, pp. 251–275. doi:10.1353/seo.2023.a902141. ISSN 2331-4826
Giovanni Volpe. "The Power of Sound: Rethinking the Invention of the Korean Vernacular Script". Sungkyun Journal of East Asian Studies. 2025-05-01, vol. 25, no. 1, pp. 51–74. doi:10.1215/15982661-11631558. ISSN 1598-2661 🔓
Mi-rim Yoo. "King Sejong's Leadership and the Politics of Inventing the Korean Alphabet". The Review of Korean Studies. 2006-09-01, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 7–38. ISSN 2733-9351 🔓

In Korean

Books

King Sejong the Great Heritage Management Office, 2020-10-08. ISBN 978-89-299-1952-8 🔓
이강근. Cultural Heritage Administration↗, August 2007 🔓
Yi-sup Hong↗. King Sejong the Great Memorial Society↗, 2004-05-15. 8th ed. ISBN 89-8275-660-4

Academic articles

Pyong-hi Ahn↗. "世宗의 訓民正音 創製와 그 協贊者". 국어학. 2004, no. 44, pp. 3–39 🔓
Young Soo Kim. "The Transfer of Power and Succession in Joseon: Focusing on the Dethronement of Crown Prince Yangnyŏng and the Enthronement of Prince Ch'ungnyŏng". 민족문화논총. December 2014, no. 58, pp. 409–441 🔓
Jeong Yoon. "Taejong's Move to the Gaeseong/開城 city, and Subsequent Return to the Han'yang Capital : The Political Meaning of the Replacement of the Crown prince, and the Enthronement of King Sejong". 서울학연구. February 2013, vol. 50, no. 50, pp. 109–144. doi:10.17647/jss.2013.02.50.109. ISSN 1225-746X

History of Korea

The Lower Paleolithic↗ era on the Korean Peninsula and in Manchuria↗ began roughly half a million years ago. The earliest known Korean pottery dates to around 8000 BC and the Neolithic↗ period began thereafter, followed by the Bronze Age↗ by 2000 BC, and the Iron Age↗ around 700 BC. The Paleolithic↗ people are likely not the direct ancestors of the present Korean people, but their direct ancestors are thought to be the Neolithic People of about 2000 BC.

According to the mythic account recounted in the Samguk yusa↗ (1281), the Gojoseon↗ kingdom was founded in northern Korea and southern Manchuria↗ in 2333 BC. The first written historical record on Gojoseon can be found from the text Guanzi↗. The Jin state↗ was formed in southern Korea by the 3rd century BC. In the late 2nd century BC, Gojoseon eventually fell to↗ the Han dynasty↗ of China, which led to succeeding warring states, the Proto–Three Kingdoms↗ period.

From the 1st century BC, Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗ grew to control the peninsula and Manchuria as the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ (57 BC–668 AD), until unification by Silla↗ in 676. In 698, Dae Jo-young↗ established Balhae↗ in the old territories of Goguryeo, which led to the Northern and Southern States period↗ (698–926) with Balhae and Silla coexisting.

In the late 9th century, Silla was divided into the Later Three Kingdoms↗ (892–936), which ended with the unification by Wang Kŏn↗'s Goryeo↗ dynasty. Meanwhile, Balhae fell after invasions by the Khitan↗-led Liao dynasty↗; fleeing refugees including the last crown prince↗ emigrated to Goryeo, where he was absorbed into the ruling family, thus unifying the two successor states of Goguryeo. During the Goryeo period, laws were codified↗, a civil service↗ system was introduced, and culture influenced by Buddhism↗ flourished. However, Mongol invasions↗ in the 13th century brought Goryeo under the influence of the Mongol Empire↗ and the Yuan dynasty↗ of China until the mid-14th century.

In 1392, General Yi Seong-gye↗ established the Joseon dynasty↗ (1392–1897) after a coup d'état↗ in 1388 that overthrew the Goryeo dynasty. King Sejong the Great (1418–1450) implemented numerous administrative, social, scientific, and economic reforms, established royal authority in the early years of the dynasty, and personally created Hangul↗, the Korean alphabet.

After enjoying a period of peace for nearly two centuries, the Joseon dynasty↗ faced foreign invasions from 1592 to 1637. Most notable of these were the Japanese invasions of Korea↗. The combined force of the Ming dynasty↗ of China and the Joseon dynasty (whose naval fleet was successfully led by Admiral Yi Sun-sin↗) repelled these Japanese invasions, but at a cost to both countries. Henceforth, Joseon gradually became more and more isolationist↗ and stagnant with frequent internal strifes.

By the mid 19th century, with the country unwilling to modernize, and under encroachment by European powers↗, Joseon Korea was forced to sign unequal treaties↗ with foreign powers. After the assassination of Empress Myeongseong↗ by Japanese mercenaries in 1895, the Donghak Peasant Revolution↗, and the Gabo Reforms of 1894 to 1896↗, the Korean Empire↗ (1897–1910) came into existence, heralding a brief but rapid period of social reform and modernization. However, in 1905, the Korean Empire was forced to sign a protectorate treaty↗ and in 1910, Japan effectively annexed the Korean Empire↗; the treaties involved were later confirmed to be null and void. Korea then became a de facto Japanese colony from 1910 to 1945. Korean resistance↗ manifested in the widespread March First Movement↗ of 1919. Thereafter the resistance movements↗, coordinated by the Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea↗ in exile, became largely active in neighboring Manchuria, China proper↗, and Siberia↗.

After the end of World War II↗ in 1945, the Allies divided the country↗ into a northern area↗ (protected by the Soviets↗) and a southern area↗ (protected primarily by the United States↗). In 1948, when the great powers failed to agree on the formation of a single government, this partition became the modern states of North and South Korea. The peninsula was divided at the 38th Parallel↗: the "Republic of Korea↗" was created in the south, with the backing of the US and Western Europe, and the "Democratic People's Republic of Korea↗" in the north, with the backing of the Soviets and the communist People's Republic of China↗. The new premier of North Korea, Kim Il Sung↗, launched the Korean War↗ in 1950 in an attempt to reunify the country↗ under Communist rule↗. After immense material and human destruction, the conflict ended with a ceasefire in 1953. In 1991, both states were accepted into the United Nations↗. In 2018, the two nations agreed to work toward a final settlement↗ to formally end the Korean conflict↗ and promote the common prosperity and reunification of Korea.

While both countries were essentially under authoritarian rule after the war, South Korea↗ eventually liberalized↗. Since 1987 it has had a competitive electoral system. The South Korean economy has prospered↗, and the country is now considered to be fully developed. North Korea↗ has maintained a totalitarian↗ militarized rule↗, with a personality cult↗ constructed around the Kim family↗. Economically, North Korea has remained heavily dependent on foreign aid↗.

Prehistory

Main article: Prehistoric Korea↗

Paleolithic

No fossil proven to be Homo erectus↗ has been found in the Korean Peninsula, though a candidate has been reported. Tool-making artifacts from the Paleolithic↗ period have been found in present-day North Hamgyong↗, South Pyongan↗, Gyeonggi↗, and north and south Chungcheong↗ provinces, which dates the Paleolithic Age to half a million years ago, though it may have begun as late as 400,000 years ago or as early as 600,000–700,000 years ago.

Neolithic

Main articles: Jeulmun pottery period↗ and Mumun pottery period↗

The earliest known Korean pottery↗ dates back to around 8000 BC, and evidence of Mesolithic↗ Pit–Comb Ware culture↗ (or Yunggimun pottery↗) is found throughout the peninsula, such as in Jeju Island↗. Jeulmun pottery↗, or "comb-pattern pottery", is found after 7000 BC, and is concentrated at sites in west-central regions of the Korean Peninsula, where a number of prehistoric settlements, such as Amsa-dong↗, existed. Jeulmun pottery bears basic design and form similarities to that of Mongolia↗, the Amur↗ and Songhua↗ river basins of Manchuria↗, the Jōmon↗ culture in Japan, and the Baiyue↗ in Southern China↗ and Southeast Asia↗.

Archaeological evidence demonstrates that agricultural societies and the earliest forms of social-political complexity emerged in the Mumun pottery period↗ (c. 1500–300 BC).

People in southern Korea adopted intensive dry-field and paddy-field↗ agriculture with a multitude of crops in the Early Mumun Period (1500–850 BC). The first societies led by big-men or chiefs emerged in the Middle Mumun (850–550 BC), and the first ostentatious elite burials can be traced to the Late Mumun (c. 550–300 BC). Bronze production began in the Middle Mumun and became increasingly important in ceremonial and political society after 700 BC. Archeological evidence from Songguk-ri↗, Daepyeong↗, Igeum-dong↗, and elsewhere indicate that the Mumun era was the first in which chiefdoms rose, expanded, and collapsed. The increasing presence of long-distance trade, an increase in local conflicts, and the introduction of bronze and iron metallurgy are trends denoting the end of the Mumun around 300 BC.

In addition, 73 tombs similar to the ones found in Japan, estimated to date back to Gojoseon (100 BC), have been found in the southern tip of the Korean peninsula, and the discovery of jar burial↗s, suggest a close relationship with Japan and Gojoseon, proving that Gojoseon and Yayoi period Japan maintained close relations with one another even during the ancient times.

Bronze Age

The Bronze Age in Korea↗ is often held to have begun around 900–800 BC, though the transition to the Bronze Age may have begun as far back as 2300 BC. Bronze daggers, mirrors, jewelry, and weaponry have been found, as well as evidence of walled-town polities. Rice, red beans, soybeans and millet were cultivated, and rectangular pit-houses and increasingly larger dolmen↗ burial sites are found throughout the peninsula. Contemporaneous records suggest that Gojoseon transitioned from a feudal federation of walled cities into a centralised kingdom at least before the 4th century BC. It is believed that by the 4th century BC, iron culture↗ was developing in Korea by northern influence via today's Russia's Maritime Province↗.

Ancient Korea

Main articles: Gojoseon↗, Jin (Korean state)↗, and Four Commanderies of Han↗

Gojoseon

See also: Dangun↗, Gija Joseon↗, and Wiman Joseon↗

Gojoseon↗ was the first Korean kingdom, located in the north of the peninsula and Manchuria, later alongside the state of Jin↗ in the south of the peninsula.

The founding legend of Gojoseon, which is recorded in the Samguk yusa↗ (1281) and other medieval Korean books, states that the country was established in 2333 BC by Dangun↗, said to be descended from heaven. While no evidence has been found that supports whatever facts may lie beneath this, the account has played an important role in developing Korean national identity.

In the 12th century BC, Gija↗, a prince from the Shang dynasty↗ of China, purportedly founded Gija Joseon↗. In pre-modern Korea, Gija represented the authenticating presence of Chinese civilization, and until the 20th century, Koreans commonly believed that Dangun bestowed upon Korea its people and basic culture, while Gija gave Korea its high culture—and presumably, standing as a legitimate civilization. However, due to contradicting historical and archaeological evidence, its existence was challenged in the 20th century, and today no longer forms the mainstream understanding of this period.

The historical Gojoseon kingdom was first mentioned in the Chinese record in a text called Guanzi↗. By about the 4th century BC, Gojoseon had developed to the point where its existence was well known in China, and around this time, its capital moved to Pyongyang↗.

In 194 BC, the King of Gojoseon was overthrown by Wi Man↗ (also known as Wei Man), a Korean-Chinese refugee from the Han vassal state of Yan↗. Wi Man then established Wiman Joseon↗.

In 128 BC, Nan Lü (南閭), a leader of Ye who was receiving pressure from Wiman Joseon↗, surrendered to the Han dynasty↗ and became the Canghai Commandery↗.

Chinese commanderies

In 108 BC, the Chinese Han dynasty↗ defeated Wiman Joseon↗ and installed four commanderies↗ in the northern Korean peninsula. Three of the commanderies fell or retreated westward within a few decades, but the Lelang Commandery↗ remained as a center of cultural and economic exchange with successive Chinese dynasties for four centuries, until it was conquered by Goguryeo↗ in 313 AD.

Jin State

Around 300 BC, a state called Jin↗ arose in the southern part of the Korean peninsula. Very little is known about Jin, but it established relations with Han China and exported artifacts to the Yayoi↗ of Japan↗. Around 100 BC, Jin evolved into the Samhan↗ confederacies.

Many smaller states sprang from the former territory of Gojoseon such as Buyeo↗, Okjeo↗, Dongye↗, Goguryeo↗, and Baekje↗. The Three Kingdoms↗ refer to Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗, although Buyeo and the Gaya confederacy↗ existed into the 5th and 6th centuries respectively.

Proto–Three Kingdoms

Main article: Proto–Three Kingdoms of Korea↗

The Proto-Three Kingdoms period, sometimes called the Several States Period (열국시대,列國時代), is the time before the rise of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, which included Goguryeo↗, Silla↗, and Baekje↗, and occurred after the fall of Gojoseon↗. This time period consisted of numerous states that sprang up from the former territories of Gojoseon. Among these states, the largest and most influential were Eastern Buyeo↗ and Northern Buyeo↗.

Northern states

Main articles: Buyeo↗, Okjeo↗, and Eastern Ye↗

After the fall of Gojoseon↗, Buyeo↗ arose in today's North Korea and southern Manchuria↗, from about the 2nd century BC to 494 AD. Its remnants were absorbed by Goguryeo↗ in 494, and both Goguryeo and Baekje↗, two of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, considered themselves its successor.

Although records are sparse and contradictory, it is thought that in 86 BC, Dongbuyeo↗ (Eastern Buyeo) branched out, after which the original Buyeo is sometimes referred to as Bukbuyeo↗ (Northern Buyeo). Jolbon Buyeo↗ was the predecessor to Goguryeo↗, and in 538, Baekje renamed itself Nambuyeo (Southern Buyeo).

Okjeo↗ was a tribal-state that was located in the northern Korean Peninsula, and was established after the fall of Gojoseon. Okjeo had been a part of Gojoseon↗ before its fall. It never became a fully developed kingdom due to the intervention of its neighboring kingdoms. Okjeo became a tributary of Goguryeo, and was eventually annexed into Goguryeo by Gwanggaeto the Great↗ in the 5th century.

Dongye↗ (Eastern Ye) was another small kingdom that was situated in the northern Korean Peninsula. Dongye bordered Okjeo↗, and the two kingdoms faced the same fate of becoming tributaries of the growing empire of Goguryeo↗. Dongye was also a former part of Gojoseon↗ before its fall.

Southern states

Main articles: Samhan↗, Mahan confederacy↗, Jinhan confederacy↗, and Byeonhan confederacy↗

Sam-han (삼한 / 三韓) refers to the three confederacies of Mahan↗, Jinhan↗, and Byeonhan↗. The Samhan were located in the southern region of the Korean Peninsula. The Samhan countries were strictly governed by law, with religion playing an important role. Mahan was the largest, consisting of 54 states, and assumed political, economic, and cultural dominance. Byeonhan and Jinhan both consisted of 12 states, bringing a total of 78 states within the Samhan. The Samhan were eventually conquered by Baekje↗, Silla↗, and Gaya↗ in the 4th century.

Three Kingdoms of Korea

Main article: Three Kingdoms of Korea↗

Goguryeo

Main article: Goguryeo↗ See also: Military history of Goguryeo↗

Goguryeo↗ was founded in 37 BC by Jumong↗ (posthumously given the royal title Dongmyeongseong). Later, King Taejo↗ centralized the government. Goguryeo was the first Korean kingdom to adopt Buddhism as the state religion in 372, in King Sosurim↗'s reign.

Goguryeo (also spelled as Koguryŏ) was also known as Goryeo (also spelled as Koryŏ), and it eventually became the source of the modern name of Korea.

The 3rd and 4th centuries were characterized by territorial competition with the Chinese and Xianbei, resulting in both losses and gains. Goguryeo initiated the Goguryeo–Wei War↗ by attacking a Chinese fortress in 242 in an attempt to cut off Chinese access to its territories in Korea. Cao Wei↗ of the Three Kingdoms of China↗ retaliated by invading and destroying Hwando↗ in 244. This forced the king to flee with Cao Wei in pursuit and broke Goguryeo's rule over the Okjeo and Ye, damaging its economy. The king eventually settled in a new capital, and Goguryeo focused on rebuilding and regaining control. In the early 4th century Goguryeo once again attacked the Chinese (now Sima Jin↗) to cut off their access to Korea and this time succeeded, and soon afterward conquered Lelang and Daifang ending the Chinese presence in Korea. However Goguryeo's expansion led to confrontation with the rising Xianbeis. The Xianbeis devastated Goguryeo's capital in the mid 4th century and the king retreated. Goguryeo eventually regrouped and began striking back in the late 4th century by King Gogukyang, culminating with the conquests of Gwanggaeto the Great.

Goguryeo reached its zenith in the 5th century, becoming a powerful empire and one of the great powers in East Asia, when Gwanggaeto the Great↗ and his son, Jangsu↗, expanded the country into almost all of Manchuria, parts of Inner Mongolia, parts of Russia, and took the present-day city of Seoul from Baekje. Goguryeo experienced a golden age under Gwanggaeto and Jangsu, who both subdued Baekje and Silla during their times, achieving a brief unification of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ and becoming the most dominant power of the Korean peninsula. Jangsu's long reign of 79 years saw the perfecting of Goguryeo's political, economic and other institutional arrangements.

Goguryeo was a highly militaristic state; in addition to contesting for control of the Korean Peninsula, Goguryeo had many military conflicts↗ with various Chinese dynasties, most notably the Goguryeo–Sui War↗, in which Goguryeo defeated a huge force traditionally said to number over a million men, and contributed to the Sui dynasty↗'s fall.

In 642, the powerful general Yŏn Kaesomun↗ led a coup and gained complete control over Goguryeo. In response, Emperor Taizong of Tang China↗ led a campaign against Goguryeo↗, but was defeated and retreated. After the death of Taizong, his son Gaozong↗ allied with the Korean kingdom of Silla↗ and invaded Goguryeo again, but was unable to overcome Goguryeo's stalwart defenses and was defeated in 662. However, Yŏn Kaesomun died of natural causes in 666 and Goguryeo was thrown into chaos and weakened by a succession struggle among his sons and younger brother, with his eldest son defecting to Tang↗ and his younger brother defecting to Silla. The Tang–Silla alliance mounted a fresh invasion in 667, aided by the defector Yeon Namsaeng, and was finally able to conquer Goguryeo↗ in 668.

After the collapse of Goguryeo, Tang and Silla ended their alliance and fought over control of the Korean Peninsula. Silla succeeded in gaining control over most of the Korean Peninsula, while Tang gained control over Goguryeo's northern territories. However, 30 years after the fall of Goguryeo, a Goguryeo general by the name of Dae Jo-yeong↗ founded the Korean-Mohe state of Balhae↗ and successfully expelled the Tang presence from much of the former Goguryeo territories.

Baekje

Main article: Baekje↗

Baekje was founded by Onjo↗, a Goguryeo prince and the third son of Jumong, the founder of Goguryeo, in 18 BC. Baekje and Goguryeo shared founding myths and originated from Buyeo↗. The Records of the Three Kingdoms↗ mentions Baekje as a member of the Mahan confederacy↗ in the Han River↗ basin (near now Seoul). It expanded into the southwest (Chungcheong↗ and Jeolla↗ provinces) of the peninsula and became a significant political and military power. In the process, Baekje came into fierce confrontation with Goguryeo and the Chinese commanderies in the vicinity of its territorial ambitions.

At its peak in the 4th century during the reign of King Geunchogo↗, Baekje absorbed all of the Mahan states and subjugated most of the western Korean peninsula (including the modern provinces of Gyeonggi↗, Chungcheong↗, and Jeolla↗, as well as part of Hwanghae↗ and Gangwon↗) to a centralized government. Baekje acquired Chinese culture and technology through maritime contacts with the Southern dynasties↗ during the expansion of its territory.

Baekje was a great maritime power; its nautical skill, which made it the Phoenicia↗ of East Asia, was instrumental in the dissemination of Buddhism throughout East Asia and continental culture to Japan. Baekje played a fundamental role in transmitting cultural developments, such as Chinese characters↗, Buddhism↗, iron-making, advanced pottery↗, and ceremonial burial to ancient Japan↗. Other aspects of culture were also transmitted when the Baekje court retreated to Japan after Baekje was conquered by the Silla–Tang alliance.

Baekje was once a great military power on the Korean Peninsula, especially during the time of Geunchogo↗, but was critically defeated by Gwanggaeto the Great and declined. Ultimately, Baekje was defeated by a coalition of Silla and Tang↗ forces in 660.

Silla

Main article: Silla↗

According to legend, the kingdom of Silla↗ began with the unification of six chiefdoms of the Jinhan confederacy↗ by Park Hyeokgeose↗ in 57 BC, in the southeastern area of Korea. Its territory included the present-day port city of Busan↗, and Silla later emerged as a sea power responsible for destroying Japanese pirates, especially during the Unified Silla↗ period.

Silla artifacts, including unique gold metalwork, show influence from the northern nomadic steppes and Iranian peoples↗ and especially Persians↗, with less Chinese influence than is shown by Goguryeo and Baekje. Silla expanded rapidly by occupying the Nakdong River↗ basin and uniting the city-states.

By the 2nd century, Silla was a large state, occupying and influencing nearby city-states. Silla gained further power when it annexed the Gaya confederacy↗ in 562. Silla often faced pressure from Goguryeo, Baekje and Japan, and at various times allied and warred with Baekje and Goguryeo↗.

Silla was the smallest and weakest of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, but it used cunning diplomatic means to make opportunistic pacts and alliances with the more powerful Korean kingdoms, and eventually Tang China, to its great advantage.

In 660, King Muyeol of Silla↗ ordered his armies to attack Baekje. General Kim Yu-shin↗, aided by Tang↗ forces, conquered Baekje. In 661, Silla and Tang moved on Goguryeo↗ but were repelled. King Munmu↗, son of Muyeol and nephew of Kim, launched another campaign in 667, and Goguryeo fell in the following year.

Gaya

Main article: Gaya confederacy↗

Gaya↗ was a confederacy of small kingdoms in the Nakdong River↗ valley of southern Korea since AD 42, growing out of the Byeonhan confederacy↗ of the Samhan↗ period. Gaya's plains were rich in iron, so export of iron tools was possible and agriculture flourished. In the early centuries, the Confederacy was led by Geumgwan Gaya↗ in the Gimhae↗ region. However, its leading power changed to Daegaya↗ in the Goryeong↗ region after the 5th century.

Constantly engaged in war with the three kingdoms surrounding it, Gaya was not developed to form a unified state, and was ultimately absorbed into Silla↗ in 562.

North and South States

Main article: North–South States Period↗

The term North-South States refers to Unified Silla↗ and Balhae↗, during the time when Silla controlled the majority of the Korean peninsula while Balhae expanded into Manchuria↗. During this time, culture and technology significantly advanced, especially in Unified Silla.

Unified Silla

Main article: United Silla↗ See also: Silla–Tang War↗

After the unification wars, the Tang dynasty↗ established outposts in the former Goguryeo↗, and began to establish and administer communities in Baekje↗. Silla attacked Tang forces in Baekje and northern Korea in 671. Tang then invaded Silla in 674 but Silla drove the Tang forces out of the peninsula by 676 to achieve unification of most of the Korean peninsula.

Unified Silla was a golden age of art and culture. During this period, long-distance trade between Unified Silla and the Abbasid Caliphate↗ was documented by Persian geographer Ibn Khordadbeh↗ in the Book of Roads and Kingdoms↗. Buddhist monasteries such as the World Heritage Site↗s Bulguksa↗ Temple and Seokguram↗ Grotto are examples of advanced Korean architecture and Buddhist influence. Other state-sponsored art and architecture from this period include Hwangnyongsa↗ Temple and Bunhwangsa↗ Temple. Unified Silla carried on the maritime prowess of Baekje↗, which acted like the Phoenicia↗ of medieval East Asia↗, and during the 8th and 9th centuries dominated the seas of East Asia and the trade between China, Korea and Japan, most notably during the time of Chang Pogo↗; in addition, Silla people made overseas communities in China on the Shandong Peninsula↗ and the mouth of the Yangtze River↗. Unified Silla was a prosperous and wealthy country, and its metropolitan capital of Gyeongju↗ was the fourth largest city in the world.

Buddhism flourished during this time, and many Korean Buddhists gained great fame among Chinese Buddhists and contributed to Chinese Buddhism, including: Woncheuk↗, Wonhyo↗, Uisang↗, Musang↗, and Kim Gyo-gak↗, a Silla prince whose influence made Mount Jiuhua↗ one of the Four Sacred Mountains↗ of Chinese Buddhism.

Silla began to experience political troubles in late 8th century. This severely weakened Silla and soon thereafter, descendants of the former Baekje established Later Baekje↗. In the north, rebels revived Goguryeo, beginning the Later Three Kingdoms↗ period.

Unified Silla lasted for 267 years until King Gyeongsun↗ surrendered the country to Goryeo↗ in 935, after 992 years and 56 monarchs.

Balhae

Main article: Balhae↗

Balhae↗ was founded only thirty years after Goguryeo had fallen, in 698. It was founded in the northern part of former lands of Goguryeo by Dae Jo-yeong↗, a former Goguryeo general or chief of Sumo Mohe. Balhae controlled the northern areas of the Korean Peninsula, much of Manchuria (though it didn't occupy Liaodong Peninsula↗ for much of history), and expanded into present-day Russian Primorsky Krai↗. It also adopted the culture of Tang dynasty↗, such as the government structure and geopolitical system.

In a time of relative peace and stability in the region, Balhae flourished, especially during the reigns of King Mun↗ and King Seon↗. Balhae was called the "Prosperous Country in the East". However, Balhae was severely weakened and eventually conquered by the Khitan↗-led Liao dynasty↗ in 926. Large numbers of refugees, including Dae Gwang-hyeon↗, the last crown prince of Balhae, were welcomed by Goryeo. Dae Gwang-hyeon↗ was included in the imperial family of Wang Kŏn↗, bringing a national unification between the two successor nations of Goguryeo.

No historical records from Balhae have survived, and the Liao left no histories of Balhae. Goryeo↗ absorbed some Balhae territory, welcomed between 100,000 and 200,000 Balhae refugees including its Crown Prince Dae Gwang-hyeon↗, and maintained hostile relations with the Liao for destroying Balhae. However, Goryeo's official historical record, the Samguk sagi↗ ("History of the Three Kingdoms"), includes passages on Balhae, but did not include a dynastic history of Balhae. Balhae was first included in Korean history by Goryeo scholar Yi Seung-hyu's Jewang ungi↗ in 1287. The 18th century Joseon↗ dynasty historian Yu Deuk-gong↗ advocated the proper study of Balhae as part of Korean history, and coined the term "North and South States Period" to refer to this era.

Later Three Kingdoms

Main article: Later Three Kingdoms↗ The Later Three Kingdoms period (892–936) consisted of Unified Silla↗ and the revival of Baekje↗ and Goguryeo↗, known historiographically as "Later Baekje" and "Later Goguryeo". During the late 9th century, as Silla declined in power and exorbitant taxes were imposed on the people, rebellions erupted nationwide and powerful regional lords rose up against the waning kingdom.

Later Baekje↗ was founded by the general Kyŏn Hwŏn↗ in 892, and its capital was established in Wansanju (modern Jeonju↗). The kingdom was based in the southwestern regions in the former territories of Baekje. In 927, Later Baekje attacked Gyeongju↗, the capital of Unified Silla, and placed a puppet on the throne. Eventually, Kyŏn Hwŏn was ousted by his sons due to a succession dispute and escaped to Goryeo, where he served as a general in the conquest of the kingdom he personally founded.

Later Goguryeo↗ was founded by the Buddhist monk Kung Ye↗ in 901, and its original capital was established in Songak (modern Kaesong↗). The kingdom was based in the northern regions, which were the strongholds of Goguryeo refugees. Later Goguryeo's name was changed to Majin in 904, and Taebong in 911. In 918, Wang Kŏn↗, a prominent general of Goguryeo descent, deposed the increasingly despotic and paranoid Kung Ye, and established Goryeo↗. By 936, Goryeo conquered its rivals and achieved the unification of the Later Three Kingdoms.

Goryeo dynasty

Main article: Goryeo↗ See also: Goryeo military regime↗ and Korea under Yuan rule↗

Goryeo↗ was founded by Wang Kŏn↗ in 918 and became the ruling dynasty of Korea by 936. It was named "Goryeo" because Wang Kŏn, who was of Goguryeo descent, deemed the nation as the successor of Goguryeo↗. Wang Kŏn made his hometown Kaesong↗ (in present-day North Korea) the capital. The dynasty lasted until 1392, although the government was controlled by military regime leaders↗ between 1170 and 1270. Goryeo (also spelled as Koryŏ) is the source of the English name "Korea".

During this period, laws were codified and a civil service system was introduced. Buddhism↗ flourished and spread throughout the peninsula. The development of celadon↗ pottery flourished in the 12th and 13th centuries. The production of the Tripitaka Koreana↗ onto 81,258 wooden printing blocks, and use of metal movable type↗ attest to Goryeo's cultural achievements.

In 1018, the Liao dynasty↗, which was the most powerful empire of its time, invaded Goryeo but was defeated by General Kang Kam-ch'an↗ at the Battle of Kuju↗ to end the Goryeo–Khitan War↗. After defeating the Khitan Empire, Goryeo experienced a golden age that lasted a century, during which the Tripitaka Koreana↗ was completed, and there were great developments in printing and publishing, promoting learning and dispersing knowledge on philosophy, literature, religion, and science; by 1100, there were 12 universities that produced famous scholars and scientists.

In 1231, the Mongols↗ began their invasions of Korea↗ during seven major campaigns and 39 years of struggle, but were unable to conquer Korea. Exhausted after decades of fighting, Goryeo sent its crown prince↗ to the Dadu↗ to swear allegiance to the Yuan dynasty↗; Kublai Khan↗ accepted, and married one of his daughters to the Korean crown prince, and for the following 80 years Goryeo existed under the overlordship↗ of the Mongol-ruled Yuan dynasty↗ in China↗. The two nations became intertwined for 80 years as all subsequent Korean kings married Mongol princesses, and the last empress↗ of the Yuan dynasty was a Korean woman.

In the 1350s, the Yuan dynasty declined rapidly due to internal struggles, enabling King Gongmin↗ to reform the Goryeo government. Gongmin had various problems that needed to be dealt with, including the removal of pro-Yuan aristocrats and military officials, the question of land holding, and quelling the growing animosity between the Buddhists and Confucian scholars. During this tumultuous period, Goryeo momentarily conquered Liaoyang↗ in 1356, repulsed two large invasions by the Red Turbans↗ in 1359 and 1360, and defeated the final attempt by the Yuan to dominate Goryeo when General Ch'oe Yŏng↗ defeated an invading Yuan tumen↗ in 1364. During the 1380s, Goryeo turned its attention to the Wokou↗ menace and used naval artillery↗ created by Ch'oe Mu-sŏn↗ to annihilate hundreds of pirate ships.

The Goryeo dynasty lasted until 1392. Yi Seong-gye↗, the founder of the Joseon↗ dynasty, took power in a coup in 1388 and after serving as the power behind the throne for two monarchs, established the Joseon dynasty in 1392.

Joseon dynasty

Main article: Joseon↗

Political history

In 1392, the general Yi Seong-gye↗, later known as Taejo, established the Joseon↗ dynasty (1392–1897), named in honor of the ancient kingdom Gojoseon↗, and founded on idealistic Confucianism↗-based ideology. The prevailing philosophy throughout the Joseon dynasty was Neo-Confucianism↗, which was epitomized by the seonbi↗ class, scholars who passed up positions of wealth and power to lead lives of study and integrity.

Taejo moved the capital to Hanyang (modern-day Seoul) and built the palace Gyeongbokgung↗. In 1394 he adopted Neo-Confucianism↗ as the country's official religion, and pursued the creation of a strong bureaucratic state. His son and grandson, King Taejong↗ and Sejong the Great, implemented numerous administrative, social, and economic reforms and established royal authority in the early years of the dynasty.

During the 15th and 16th centuries, Joseon enjoyed many benevolent rulers who promoted education and science. Most notable among them was Sejong the Great (r. 1418–50), who personally created and promulgated Hangul↗, the Korean alphabet. This golden age saw great cultural and scientific advancements, including in printing, meteorological observation↗, astronomy, calendar science, ceramics↗, military technology, geography, cartography, medicine, and agricultural technology, some of which were unrivaled elsewhere.

Internal conflicts within the royal court, civil unrest and other political struggles plagued the nation in the years that followed, worsened by the Japanese invasion of Korea↗ between 1592 and 1598. Toyotomi Hideyoshi↗ marshalled his forces and tried to invade the Asian continent through Korea, but was eventually repelled by the Korean military, with the assistance of the righteous armies↗ and Chinese Ming dynasty↗. This war also saw the rise of the career of Admiral Lee Sun-sin↗ with the turtle ship↗. As Korea was rebuilding, it had to repel invasions by the Manchu in 1627↗ and 1636↗. Internal politics were bitterly divided and settled by violence. Historian JaHyun Kim Haboush↗, in the summary by her editor William Haboush in 2016, interpreted the decisive impact of the victories against the Japanese and Manchu invaders: :Out of this great war at the end of the 16th century and the Manchu invasions of 1627 and 1636–1637, Koreans emerged with a discernible sense of themselves as a distinct ethnic united by birth, language, and belief forged by this immense clash of the three great powers of East Asia ... Korea arrived at the brink of the seventeenth century as a nation.

After the second Manchu invasion and stabilized relations with the new Qing dynasty↗, Joseon experienced a nearly 200-year period of external peace. However internally, the bitter and violent factional battles↗ raged on. In the 18th century, King Yeongjo↗ (r. 1724–76) and his grandson King Jeongjo↗ (r. 1776–1800) led a new renaissance. Yeongjo and Jeongjo reformed the tax system which grew the revenue stream into the treasury, strengthened the military and sponsored a revival of learning. The printing press was rejuvenated by using movable metal type; the number and quality of publications sharply increased. Jeongjo sponsored scholars from various factions to work in the Kyujanggak↗, or Inner Royal Library, established in 1776.

19th century

Corruption in government and social unrest prevailed after 1776. The government attempted sweeping reforms in the late 19th century, but adhered to a strict isolationist policy, earning Korea the nickname "Hermit Kingdom↗". The policy had been established primarily for protection against Western imperialism↗, but soon the Joseon dynasty was forced to open trade, beginning an era leading into Japanese rule↗.

The destabilization of the Korean nation may be said to have begun in the period of Sedo Jeongchi (세도정치 / 勢道政治) whereby, on the death of King Jeongjo of Joseon↗ (r. 1776–1800), the 10-year-old Sunjo of Joseon↗ (r. 1800–34) ascended the Korean throne, with the true power of the administration residing with his regent, Kim Jo-sun, as a representative of the Andong Kim clan↗. As a result, the disarray and blatant corruption in the Korean government, particularly in the three main areas of revenues – land tax, military service, and the state granary system – heaped additional hardship on the peasantry. Of special note is the corruption of the local functionaries (Hyangni), who could purchase an appointment as an administrator and so cloak their predations on the farmers with an aura of officialdom. Yangban↗ families, formerly well-respected for their status as a noble class and being powerful both "socially and politically", were increasingly seen as little more than commoners unwilling to meet their responsibilities to their communities. Faced with increasing corruption in the government, brigandage of the disenfranchised (such as the mounted fire brigands, or Hwajok, and the boat-borne water brigands or Sujok) and exploited by the elite, many poor village folk sought to pool their resources, such as land, tools, and production, to survive. Despite the government effort in bringing an end to the practice of owning slaves in 1801, slavery in Korea remained legal until 1894.

At this time, Catholic and Protestant missions were well tolerated among the nobles, most notably in and around the area of Seoul. Animus and persecution by more conservative elements, the Pungyang Jo clan↗, took the lives of priests and followers, known as the Korean Martyrs↗, dissuading membership by the upper class. The peasants continued to be drawn to Christian egalitarianism, though mainly in urban and suburban areas. Arguably of greater influence were the religious teachings of Choe Je-u↗, (최제우, 崔濟愚, 1824–64) called "Donghak↗", which literally means Eastern Learning, and the religion became especially popular in rural areas. Themes of exclusionism (from foreign influences), nationalism, salvation and social consciousness were set to music, allowing illiterate farmers to understand and accept them more readily. Along with many other Koreans, Choe was alarmed by the intrusion of Christianity and the Anglo-French occupation of Beijing during the Second Opium War↗. He believed the best way to counter foreign influence in Korea was to introduce democratic and human rights reforms internally. Nationalism and social reform struck a chord among peasant guerrillas, and Donghak spread all across Korea. Progressive revolutionaries organized the peasants into a cohesive structure. Arrested in 1863 following the Jinju uprising↗ led by Yu Kye-chun, Choe was charged with "misleading the people and sowing discord in society". Choe was executed in 1864, sending many of his followers into hiding in the mountains.

Gojong of Korea↗ (r. 1864–1907), enthroned at the age of 12, succeeded Cheoljong of Joseon↗ (r. 1849–63). King Gojong's father, Heungseon Daewongun↗ (Yi Ha-ung; 1820–98), ruled as the de facto regent and inaugurated far-ranging reforms to strengthen the central administration. Of special note was the decision to rebuild palace buildings and finance the project through additional levies on the population. Further inherited rule by a few elite ruling families was challenged by the adoption of a merit system for official appointments. In addition, Sowon – private academies – which threatened to develop a parallel system to the corrupt government and enjoyed special privileges and large landholdings, were taxed and repressed despite bitter opposition from Confucian scholars. Lastly, a policy of steadfast isolationism was enforced to staunch the increasing intrusion of Western thought and technology. He was impeached in 1873 and forced into retirement by the supporters of Empress Myeongseong↗, also called "Queen Min".

Culture and society

Korea's culture was based on the philosophy of Neo-Confucianism↗, which emphasizes morality, righteousness, and practical ethics. Wide interest in scholarly study resulted in the establishment of private academies and educational institutions. Many documents were written about history, geography, medicine, and Confucian principles. The arts flourished in painting, calligraphy, music, dance, and ceramics↗.

The most notable cultural event of this era is the creation and promulgation of the Korean alphabet Hunmin jeongeom↗ (later called Hangul↗) by Sejong the Great in 1446. This period also saw various other cultural, scientific and technological advances.

During Joseon dynasty, a social hierarchy system existed that greatly affected Korea's social development. The king and the royal family were atop the hereditary system, with the next tier being a class of civil or military officials and landowners known as yangban↗, who worked for the government and lived off the efforts of tenant farmers and slaves.

A middle class, jungin↗, were technical specialists such as scribes, medical officers, technicians in science-related fields, artists and musicians. Commoners, sangmin↗, constituted the largest class in Korea. They had obligations to pay taxes, provide labor, and serve in the military. By paying land taxes to the state, they were allowed to cultivate land and farm. The lowest class, cheonmin↗, included tenant farmers, slaves, entertainers, craftsmen, prostitutes, laborers, shamans, vagabonds, outcasts, and criminals. Although slave↗ status was hereditary, they could be sold or freed at officially set prices, and the mistreatment of slaves was forbidden.

This yangban focused system started to change in the late 17th century as political, economic and social changes came into place. By the 19th century, new commercial groups emerged, and the active social mobility caused the yangban class to expand, resulting in the weakening of the old class system. The Korea government ordered the freedom of government slaves in 1801. The class system of Korea was completely banned in 1894.

Foreign relationships

Main articles: Japanese invasions of Korea (1592–1598)↗ and Second Manchu invasion of Korea↗

Korea dealt with a pair of Japanese invasions from 1592 to 1598↗ (Imjin War or the Seven Years' War). Prior to the war, Korea sent two ambassadors to scout for signs of Japan's intentions of invading Korea. However, they came back with two different reports, and while the politicians split into sides, few proactive measures were taken.

This conflict brought prominence to Admiral Yi Sun-sin↗ as he contributed to eventually repelling the Japanese forces with the innovative use of his turtle ship↗, a massive, yet swift, ramming/cannon ship fitted with iron spikes. The use of the hwacha↗ (a rocket-launched arrow battery) was also highly effective in repelling the Japanese invaders from the land.

Subsequently, Korea was invaded in 1627↗ and again in 1636↗ by the Manchus, who went on to conquer China and establish the Qing dynasty↗, after which the Joseon dynasty recognized Qing↗ suzerainty. Though Joseon respected its traditional tributary position to China, there was persistent loyalty for the perished Ming China↗ and disdain for the Manchus, who were regarded as barbarians.

During the 19th century, Joseon tried to control foreign influence by closing its borders to all nations. In 1853 the American whaleship South America↗ visited Busan↗ for 10 days and had amiable contact with local officials. Several Americans shipwrecked on Korea in 1855 and 1865 were also treated well and sent to China for repatriation. The Joseon court was aware of the foreign invasions and treaties involving Qing China, as well as the First↗ and Second Opium War↗s, and followed a cautious policy of slow exchange with the West.

In 1866, reacting to greater numbers of Korean converts to Catholicism despite several waves of persecutions, the Joseon court clamped down on them, massacring French Catholic missionaries and Korean converts alike. In response France invaded↗ and occupied portions of Ganghwa Island. The French army occupied Ganghwa Island↗, an island near Seoul, and tried to advance to Seoul, but failed due to strong resistance from the Korean army, and then withdrew from the island.

The SS General Sherman, a privately American-owned armed merchant marine sidewheel schooner, illegally attempted to open Korea to trade in 1866. Due to a miscalculation of water depth, the ship ran aground Pyongyang. After being ordered to leave on pain of execution by the Korean officials, the American crewmen sent out a dinghy↗ to forage. They took hostages from the junk↗ that intercepted them. Sporadic fighting ensued, resulting in the deaths of eight Koreans, the destruction of the Sherman by fire ship↗, and the killing of the crew. This incident is celebrated by the DPRK as a precursor to the capture of the USS Pueblo↗ in 1968. The Korean government did not inform the United States about the incident. In 1871, the United States expedition to Korea↗ (Shinmiyangyo) set out to determine the fate of the Sherman. This incident is called the Shinmiyangyo↗ in Korea. American warships, also with an agenda to open Korea to trade, sailed up the Han River against the will of the Korean government, attracting fire from a fort defending the capital. As punishment, the Americans attacked local military installations, provoking the Battle of Ganghwa↗. They killed around 243 to 350 Koreans on Ganghwa Island↗ before withdrawing. This angered the Korean government and had the unintended effect of temporarily increasing isolationism and military strength.

In 1876, Korea was forced by warships to sign a trade treaty with Japan, the first formal treaty between the two nations in 433 years, since the 1443 Treaty of Gyehae↗. This unequal treaty↗ compelled the Joseon to open up Korean ports, as well as granting extraterritoriality↗ within Korea to the Meiji government↗ and her people. In 1882 signed a treaty with the United States, in a few years ending centuries of isolation.

Conflict between the conservative court and a reforming faction led to the Gapsin Coup↗ in 1884. The reformers sought to reform Korea's institutionalized social inequality, by proclaiming social equality and the elimination of the privileges of the yangban↗ class. The reformers were backed by Japan, and were thwarted by the arrival of Qing troops, invited by the conservative Queen Min↗. The Chinese troops departed but the leading general Yuan Shikai↗ remained in Korea from 1885 to 1894 as Resident, directing Korean affairs.

In 1885, British Royal Navy↗ occupied Geomun Island↗, and withdrew in 1887.

Korea became linked by telegraph to China in 1888 with Chinese controlled telegraphs. China permitted Korea to establish embassies with Russia (1884), Italy (1885), France (1886), the United States, and Japan. China attempted to block the exchange of embassies in Western countries, but not with Tokyo. The Qing government provided loans. China promoted its trade in an attempt to block Japanese merchants, which led to Chinese favour in Korean trade. Anti-Chinese riots broke out in 1888 and 1889 and Chinese shops were torched. Japan remained the largest foreign community and largest trading partner.

A rapidly modernizing Meiji Japan↗ successfully challenged China in the First Sino-Japanese War↗ (1894–1895) triggered by the Donghak Peasant Movement↗, forcing it to abandon its long-standing claims to deference by Korea. Modernization began in Korea when Japan forced it to open its ports in 1876. However, at first, the forces of modernization met strong opposition not only from the traditionalism of the ruling Korean elite but from the population at large, which supported the traditional Confucian system of government by gentlemen, therefore no major modernization processes occurred until the establishment of the Korean Empire↗ in 1897. Japan used modernization movements to gain more and more control over Korea.

In 1895, Japanese agents carried out the assassination of Empress Myeongseong↗, who had sought Russian help, and the Russians were forced to retreat from Korea for the time.

Pro-Japanese government grew, while anti-Japanese politicians were either killed or fled for their survival. On 11 February 1896, King Gojong↗ and his crown prince fled from the Gyeongbokgung↗ to the Russian↗ legation in Seoul, from where they governed for about one year, an event known as Gojong's internal exile to the Russian legation↗.

Modern history

Korean Empire (1897–1910)

Main article: Korean Empire↗ Further information: Gwangmu Reform↗

As a result of the First Sino-Japanese War↗ (1894–1895), the 1895 Treaty of Shimonoseki↗ was concluded between China and Japan. It stipulated the abolition of subordinate relationships Korea had with China, in which Korea was a client state of China since the Imo Incident↗ in 1882.

In 1897, Joseon was renamed the Korean Empire↗, and King Gojong became Emperor Gojong↗. The imperial government aimed to become a strong and independent nation by implementing domestic reforms, strengthening military forces, developing commerce and industry, and surveying land ownership. Organizations like the Independence Club↗ also rallied to assert the rights of the Joseon people, but clashed with the government which proclaimed absolute monarchy and power.

Russian influence was strong in the Empire until being defeated by Japan in the Russo-Japanese War↗ (1904–1905). Korean Empire effectively became a protectorate↗ of Japan on 17 November 1905, the 1905 Protectorate Treaty↗ having been promulgated without Emperor Gojong's required seal or commission.

Following the signing of the treaty, many intellectuals and scholars set up various organizations and associations, embarking on movements for independence. In 1907, Gojong was forced to abdicate after Japan learned that he sent secret envoys↗ to the Second Hague Conventions↗ to protest against the protectorate treaty, leading to the accession of Gojong's son, Emperor Sunjong↗. Immediately after Sunjong ascended the throne, Empire of Japan forcibly concluded the Japan–Korea Treaty of 1907↗ in order to further strengthen the authority of the Resident-General, appointing Japanese vice-ministers in each department of the Korean Empire's government and openly interfering in the empire's internal affairs (vice-ministerial politics), and forcibly disbanded the army through a secret agreement.

Soldiers who opposed this joined the Righteous army↗, and the movement expanded into a nationwide Righteous army war. However, on July 12, 1909, Empire of Japan took away the Korean Empire's judicial and police powers through the Japan–Korea Memorandum of 1909, and suppressed the resistance of the Righteous army nationwide with force through the 60-day South Korea big suppression operation. At this operation, about 17,000 Righteous army and civilians were massacred.

In 1909, independence activist An Jung-geun↗ assassinated Itō Hirobumi↗, former Resident-General of Korea↗, for Ito's intrusions on the Korean politics. This prompted the Japanese to ban all political organizations and proceed with plans for annexation.

Japanese rule (1910–1945)

Main articles: Korea under Japanese rule↗ and Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea↗

In 1910, the Empire of Japan↗ effectively annexed Korea↗ through the Japan–Korea Annexation Treaty↗. Along with all other previously signed treaties between Korea and Japan, the annexation treaty was confirmed to be null and void in 1965. While Japan asserted that the treaty was concluded legally, Korea disputed the legality of the treaty, because the treaty was not signed by the Emperor of Korea as required and it violated the international convention on external pressures regarding treaties. Many Koreans formed the Righteous army↗ to fight against Japanese rule.

Korea was controlled by Japan↗ under a Governor-General of Chōsen↗ from 1910 until Japan's unconditional surrender to the Allied Forces↗ on 15 August 1945. De jure sovereignty was deemed to have passed from the Joseon dynasty↗ to the Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea↗.

After the annexation, Japan set out to suppress many traditional Korean customs, including eventually even the Korean language itself. Economic policies were implemented primarily for Japanese benefit. European-style transport↗ and communication↗ networks were constructed across the nation in order to extract resources and exploit labor. The banking system was consolidated and the Korean currency abolished.

The Japanese removed the Joseon↗ hierarchy and gave the census register to the baekjeong↗ and nobi↗ who were not allowed to have the census register during Joseon period, The palace Gyeongbokgung↗ was mostly destroyed, and replaced with the Government-General of Chōsen Building↗.

After Emperor Gojong↗ died in January 1919, with rumors of poisoning, independence rallies against the Japanese colonizers took place nationwide on 1 March 1919 (the March First Movement↗). This movement was suppressed by force and about 7,000 persons were killed by Japanese soldiers and police. An estimated two million people took part in peaceful, pro-liberation rallies, although Japanese records claim participation of less than half a million. This movement was partly inspired by United States President Woodrow Wilson↗'s speech of 1919, declaring support for right of self-determination and an end to colonial rule after World War I.

The Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea↗ was established in Shanghai↗, China, in the aftermath of the March 1 Movement, which coordinated the liberation effort and resistance against Japanese rule. Some of the achievements of the Provisional Government included the Battle of Chingshanli↗ of 1920 and the ambush of Japanese military leadership in China↗ in 1932. In 1920, Imperial Japanese Army massacred somewhere from 5,000 to tens of thousands of Korean civilians at Gando in retaliation to loss at Battle of Chingshanli↗. This incident is called Gando Massacre↗. The Provisional Government is considered to be the de jure government of the Korean people between 1919 and 1948. The legitimacy of the provisional government is enshrined into the preamble of the constitution↗ of the Republic of Korea↗.

Primary and secondary education in Korea were classified as being for "those habitually using the Korean language", and for "those habitually using the Japanese language". Ethnic Koreans could thus attend the schools primarily for Japanese, and vice versa.

As of 1926, the Korean language was taught for four hours a week for the first and second year of a six-year course, and three hours a week for the rest of the course. Both Japanese and Koreans paid school fees, without exception. The average fee in a common school was about 25 cents a month. In 1923, Koreans paid on average 20 cents per capita and Japanese in Korea about 3.30 dollars per capita.

The literacy rate↗ of Korea reached 22% in 1945. The school curriculum was radically modified to eliminate teaching of the Korean language and history. The Korean language was banned, and Koreans were forced to adopt Japanese names, and newspapers were prohibited from publishing in Korean. Numerous Korean cultural artifacts were destroyed or taken to Japan. According to an investigation by the South Korean government, 75,311 cultural assets were taken from Korea.

Some Koreans↗ left the Korean Peninsula for exile in China, the United States, and elsewhere. Koreans in Manchuria formed resistance groups known as Dongnipgun↗ (Liberation Army); they would travel in and out of the Sino-Korean border, fighting guerrilla warfare↗ with Japanese forces. Some of them would group together in the 1940s as the Korean Liberation Army↗, which took part in allied action in China and parts of South East Asia. Tens of thousands of Koreans also joined the People's Liberation Army↗ and the National Revolutionary Army↗.

The expulsion of the Japanese in 1945 removed practically all administrative and technical expertise. While the Japanese only comprised 2.6% of the population in 1944, they were an urban elite. The largest 50 cities contained 71% of the Japanese but only 12% of the Koreans. They largely dominated the ranks of the well-educated occupations. Meanwhile, 71% of the Koreans worked on farms.

Division and Korean War (1945–1953)

Main article: Division of Korea↗

At the Cairo Conference↗ on November 22, 1943, the US, UK, and China agreed that "in due course Korea shall become free and independent"; at a later meeting in Yalta↗ in February 1945, the Allies agreed to establish a four-power trusteeship over Korea. On August 14, 1945, Soviet↗ forces entered Korea by amphibious landings, enabling them to secure control in the north. Japan surrendered to the Allied Forces on August 15, 1945.

The unconditional surrender of Japan brought about the liberation of Korea. However, the fundamental shifts in global politics and ideology in the post-war world led to the division of Korea into two occupation zones, effectively starting on September 8, 1945. The United States↗ administered the southern half of the peninsula and the Soviet Union↗ took over the area north of the 38th parallel↗. The Provisional Government was ignored, mainly due to American belief that it was too aligned with the communists. This division was meant to be temporary and was intended to return a unified Korea back to its people after the United States, United Kingdom↗, Soviet Union↗, and Republic of China↗ could arrange a single government.

Post-Liberation Korea and the Division

Following the unconditional surrender of the Japanese Empire on August 15, 1945, Korea experienced a temporary liberation. However, the post-war global situation rapidly devolved into the Cold War system centered around the two superpowers: the United States (US) and the Soviet Union (USSR). This Cold War dynamic became visibly apparent on the Korean Peninsula.

The United States was wary of the potential influence of the Soviet Union's powerful ground forces on the Korean Peninsula and the larger East Asian region. Consequently, the US proposed a division of the peninsula along the 38th parallel into two zones—North and South—to be governed under a trusteeship administration, to which the Soviet Union agreed.

The Moscow Conference and the Trusteeship Controversy

On December 16, 1945, after the Three Foreign Ministers' Conference involving the US, USSR, and the United Kingdom, US Secretary of State James F. Byrnes submitted a document titled 'the united administration for Korea' the following day. The core of this document was a detailed trusteeship plan.

This plan stipulated that, instead of being governed by a Korean government, the peninsula would be administered by the four governing powers—acting on behalf of the UN and the Korean people—who would assume administrative, legislative, judicial, and executive functions for five years, until Korea could independently carry out these functions. However, the Soviet Union initially objected to this proposal, advocating instead that a provisional government should first be established within Korea, after which the Trusteeship should be implemented.

The compromise between the US and Soviet positions led to the joint communiqué of the Moscow Foreign Ministers' Conference (December 27) and the subsequent establishment of the US-Soviet Joint Commission.

Anti-Trusteeship (Ban-Tak) and Pro-Trusteeship (Chan-Tak) Movements

In Korea, the proposal for Trusteeship was widely viewed as a continuation of Japanese colonial rule. This sentiment fueled the Anti-Trusteeship (Opposition to Trusteeship, Ban-Tak) campaign.This movement was primarily led by right-wing political forces, including the Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea (PGROK) in Shanghai and figures like Syngman Rhee, who sought to establish a unified and sovereign national government immediately.

Conversely, left-wing forces, generally aligned with the Soviet Union, advocated for Pro-Trusteeship (Support for Trusteeship, Chan-Tak) The two camps failed to reconcile their views and remained in fierce opposition, a fundamental conflict that paved the way for the permanent division of the Korean Peninsula.

Failure of unification efforts and establishment of two Koreas

The provisional government in Shanghai was ultimately not recognized as the legitimate government by the United States Army Military Government in Korea (USAMGIK). Furthermore, the US-Soviet Joint Commission collapsed due to insurmountable differences in opinion between the two countries. In September 1947, the US submitted the Korean issue to the United Nations (UN).

Leaders of the Provisional Government, such as Kim Gu and Kim Kyu-sik, continued to oppose a separate general election in the South and the establishment of two separate governments. They attempted to hold talks with the North in a final effort to establish a unified nation, but these efforts were unsuccessful.

Ultimately, under the supervision of the UN Temporary Commission on Korea (UNTCOK), a separate election (the May 10 general election) was held in South Korea. The Government of the Republic of Korea (South Korea) was established on August 15, 1948. Subsequently, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (North Korea) was established in the North on September 9, 1948, formalizing the existence of two states on the peninsula. On December 12, 1948, the UN General Assembly recognized the Republic of Korea as the only lawful government in Korea.

On June 25, 1950, the Korean War↗ broke out when North Korea breached the 38th parallel line to invade the South, ending any hope of a peaceful reunification for the time being. After the war, the 1954 Geneva conference↗ failed to adopt a solution for a unified Korea. Approximately 3 million people died in the Korean War, with a higher proportional civilian death toll than World War II↗ or the Vietnam War↗, making it perhaps the deadliest conflict of the Cold War era. In addition, virtually all of Korea's major cities were destroyed by the war.

Modern Korea (1951–present)

On April 27, 2018, both North and South Korea signed the Panmunjom Declaration↗ on ending the conflict between the two countries to reunify Korea in the future. The declaration was suspended by North Korea in 2023 and by South Korea in 2024.

South Korea

Main article: History of South Korea↗

In 1951, under pressure of the United States, the government of South Korea began diplomatic discussions with Japan. This was the first international interaction between Korea and Japan since the end of World War II↗. President Harry S. Truman↗, under the doctrine of the Bamboo curtain↗, deemed it urgent for Japan and South Korea to ally with each other to create a stronger western hegemon in the East.

This proved to be much more of an onerous process than expected by American diplomats. The trauma from the Korea under Japanese rule↗ period was manifold and resented. The cultural distrust between Korea and Japan in political life can be traced as far back as the Imjin War↗ in the 1590s. Diplomats of the ROK drew out discussions till June 1965, where they agreed to sign the treaty on basic relations↗.

Beginning with Syngman Rhee↗ in 1948, a series of autocratic governments took power in South Korea with American support and influence.

With the coup of Park Chung Hee↗ in 1961, a new economic policy began. In order to promote economic development, a policy of export-oriented industrialization↗ was applied. President Park developed the South Korean economy through a series of highly successful Five-Year Plans↗. South Korea's economic development was spearheaded by the chaebol↗, family conglomerates such as Samsung↗, Hyundai↗, SK Group↗ and LG Corporation↗. The chaebols received state backing via tax breaks and cheap loans, and took advantage of South Korea's inexpensive labor to produce exportable products. The government made education a very high priority to create a well-educated populace capable of productively contributing to the economy. Despite occasional political instability, the Korean economy subsequently saw enormous growth for nearly forty years, in a period known as the Miracle on the Han River↗. The unparalleled economic miracle brought South Korea from one of the poorest states in the world after the Korean War into a fully developed country↗ within a generation.

South Korea eventually transitioned into a market-oriented democracy in 1987 largely due to popular demand for political reform, and then hosted the 1988 Summer Olympics↗, the second Summer Olympic Games↗ to be held on the Asian continent, in the following year.

Moving on from cheap, lower-value light industry exports, the South Korean economy eventually moved onto more capital-intensive, higher-value industries, such as information technology↗, shipbuilding↗, auto manufacturing, and petroleum refining. Today, South Korea is a leading economy and a technological powerhouse, rivaling even countries such as the United States in information and communications technology↗. South Korean pop culture has also boomed abroad in recent years, in a phenomenon known as the Korean Wave↗.

North Korea

Main article: History of North Korea↗

North Korea began their first ever diplomatic missions to Japan in 1955 to establish a "General Association of Korean Residents", an international organization led by Koreans in Japan who identified as belonging to the North Korean government, or ethnically North Korean; effectively to establish an embassy in Japan without initiating formal amity. The office was created in Tokyo↗.

Kim Il Sung↗ denounced the 1965 Treaty on Basic Relations↗ between Japan and South Korea. Throughout the 1970s, North Korea eagerly supported and harbored members of the Japanese Red Army↗, which was recognized as a terrorist group by the Japan and United States government in 1971. The DPRK also gave diplomatic support to the Japan Socialist Party↗.

Due to Soviet influence, North Korea established a communist government with a hereditary succession of leadership, with ties to China and the Soviet Union. Kim Il Sung↗ became the supreme leader until his death in 1994, after which his son, Kim Jong Il↗ took power. Kim Jong Il's son, Kim Jong Un↗, is the current leader, taking power after his father's death in 2011. After the Soviet Union's dissolution in 1991, the North Korean economy went on a path of steep decline, and it is currently heavily reliant on international food aid and trade with China.

See also

Korean monarchs' family trees: Silla↗; Goryeo↗; Joseon↗
Korean influence on Japanese culture↗
List of monarchs of Korea↗
Military history of Korea↗
National Treasure of South Korea↗
Prehistoric Korea↗
South Korea–United States relations↗
Timeline of Korean history↗
Korean Reunification↗

References

Bibliography

Surveys

Association of Korean History Teachers. Korea through the Ages, Vol. 1 Ancient. Seoul: Academy of Korean Studies↗, 2005a. ISBN 978-89-7105-545-8
Association of Korean History Teachers. Korea through the Ages, Vol. 2 Modern. Seoul: Academy of Korean Studies↗, 2005b. ISBN 978-89-7105-546-5
Adrian Buzo. The Making of Modern Korea. Routledge, 2002
Cha, Victor, and Ramon Pacheco Pardo. Korea: A New History of South and North (Yale UP, 2023).
Bruce Cumings. Korea's Place in the Sun: A Modern History. W W Norton, 2005. 2nd ed
Carter J. Eckert and Ki-Baik Lee. Korea, old and new: a history. Published for the Korea Institute, Harvard University by Ilchokak, 1990. ISBN 978-0-9627713-0-9
James Huntley Grayson. Korea: a religious history. Clarendon Press, 1989. ISBN 978-0-19-826186-5
James Hoare and Susan Pares. Korea: an introduction. New York: Routledge, 1988. ISBN 978-0-7103-0299-1
Kyung-moon Hwang. A History of Korea, An Episodic Narrative. Palgrave Macmillan, 2010. p. 328. ISBN 978-0-230-36453-0
Jager, Sheila Miyoshi. The Other Great Game: The Opening of Korea and the Birth of Modern East Asia (Harvard University Press, 2023). ISBN 9780674983397
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea. Greenwood Press, 2005. ISBN 978-0-313-03853-2 Via Internet Archive
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea. ABC-CLIO, 2014. 2nd ed. ISBN 978-1-61069-582-4. OCLC 890146633
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Indiana University Press, 2012. ISBN 978-0-253-00078-1
Korea National University of Education. Atlas of Korean History (2008)
Kenneth B. Lee. Korea and East Asia: The Story of a Phoenix. Greenwood Publishing Group, 1997. ISBN 978-0-275-95823-7
Ki-baik Lee. A New History of Korea. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1984. ISBN 978-0-674-61576-2
Hyun-hee Lee, Sung-soo Park, and Nae-hyun Yoon. New History of Korea. Paju: Jimoondang, 2005. ISBN 978-89-88095-85-0
Narangoa Li and Robert Cribb. Historical Atlas of Northeast Asia, 1590-2010: Korea, Manchuria, Mongolia, Eastern Siberia. Columbia University Press, 2016. ISBN 978-0-231-16070-4
Andrew C. Nahm. A Panorama of 5000 Years: Korean History. Seoul: Hollym International Corporation, 2005. 2nd revised ed. ISBN 978-0-930878-68-9
Andrew C. Nahm and James Hoare. Historical dictionary of the Republic of Korea. Lanham: Scarecrow Press, 2004. ISBN 978-0-8108-4949-5
Sarah M. Nelson. The archaeology of Korea. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press, 1993. p. 1013. ISBN 978-0-521-40783-0
Eugene Y. (2022) Park. Korea: A History. Stanford: Stanford University Press, 2022. p. 432. ISBN 978-1-503-62984-4
Mark Peterson and Phillip Margulies. A Brief History of Korea. Infobase Publishing, 2009. p. 328. ISBN 978-1-4381-2738-5
Keith Pratt. Everlasting Flower: A History of Korea. Reaktion Books, 2007. p. 320. ISBN 978-1-86189-335-2
Michael Edson Robinson. Korea's twentieth-century odyssey. Honolulu: U of Hawaii Press, 2007. ISBN 978-0-8248-3174-5
Michael J. Seth. A Concise History of Korea: From the Neolithic Period Through the Nineteenth Century. Lanham, MD: Rowman & Littlefield, 2006. ISBN 978-0-7425-4005-7
Michael J. Seth. A History of Korea: From Antiquity to the Present. Lanham, MD: Rowman & Littlefield, 2010. p. 520. ISBN 978-0-7425-6716-0
Michael J. Seth. A History of Korea: From Antiquity to the Present. Lanham, MD: Rowman & Littlefield, 2011. ISBN 978-0-7425-6715-3. OCLC 644646716
Hyong-sik Sin. A Brief History of Korea. Seoul: Ewha Womans University↗ Press, 2005. 2nd ed. ISBN 978-89-7300-619-9

Historiography

Henry H. Em. The Great Enterprise: Sovereignty and Historiography in Modern Korea. Duke University Press, 2013. p. 272. ISBN 978-0-8223-5372-0

Examines how Korean national ambitions have shaped the work of the country's historians.

Hong Sung-gi. "Trends in Western historiography on Korea," Korea Journal (1999) 39#3 pp 377
Kim, Han Kyo. Studies on Korea: A Scholar's Guide (1980); 458pp comprehensive guide; ISBN 0-8248-0673-5
Kim, Duol, and Ki-Joo Park. "A Cliometric Revolution in the Economic History of Korea: A Critical Review," Australian Economic History Review (2012) 52#1 pp 85–95,
Kim, Hieyoon. "Living with a Postcolonial Conundrum: Yi Yŏngil and Korean Film Historiography." Journal of Asian Studies 78.3 (2019): 601–620.
Michael, K. I. M. "Cosmopolitanism, Nationalism, and Transnationalism in Korean History." Journal of Contemporary Korean Studies 1#1 (2014): 15–34. online
Xu, Stella. Reconstructing ancient Korean history: the formation of Korean-ness in the shadow of history (Lexington Books, 2016).
Leighanne Yuh. "The Historiography of Korea in the United States". International Journal of Korean History. 2010, vol. 15#2, pp. 127–144 online

Primary sources

Peter H. Lee. Sourcebook of Korean Civilization: Volume 1: From Early Times to the Sixteenth Century. New York: Columbia University Press, 2010. ISBN 978-0-231-51529-0
Peter H. Lee. Sourcebook of Korean Civilization: Volume 2: From the Seventeenth Century to the Modern. New York: Columbia University Press, 2010. ISBN 978-0-231-51530-6

Other books used in this page

M. S. Cha and N. N. Kim. "Korea's first industrial revolution, 1911–1940". Explorations in Economic History. 2012, vol. 49, no. 1, pp. 60–74. doi:10.1016/j.eeh.2011.09.003
Mary E. Connor. The Koreas, A global studies handbook. ABC-CLIO, 2002. p. 307. ISBN 978-1-57607-277-6
Katarzyna J. Cwiertka. Cuisine, Colonialism, and Cold War: Food in Twentieth-Century Korea. Reaktion Books and University of Chicago Press, 2012. p. 237. ISBN 978-1-78023-025-2

Scholarly study of how food reflects Korea's history

Samuel Hawley. The Imjin War. Japan's Sixteenth-Century Invasion of Korea and Attempt to Conquer China. The Royal Asiatic Society, Korea Branch, Seoul, 2005. ISBN 978-89-954424-2-5
H. B. Hulbert. The History of Korea. Routledge, 2014. ISBN 978-1-317-84941-4
Byung-Kook Kim and Ezra F. Vogel, ed. The Park Chung Hee Era: The Transformation of South Korea. Harvard University Press, 2011. p. 744. ISBN 978-0-674-05820-0

Studies of on modernization under Park, 1961–1979.

Korea and the Politics of Imperialism, 1876-1910. 1967
Chong-Sik Lee. The Politics of Korean Nationalism. University of California Press, 1963
Yur-Bok Lee and Wayne Patterson. One Hundred Years of Korean-American Relations, 1882–1982. 1986
Colonial Rule and Social Change in Korea, 1910–1945. U of Washington Press, 2013. ISBN 978-0-295-99216-7
Andre Schmid↗. Korea Between Empires, 1895–1919. New York: Columbia University Press, 2002. ISBN 978-0-231-12538-3
Andre Schmid. Korea Between Empires. Columbia University Press, 2013. ISBN 978-0-231-50630-4
Miriam T. Stark↗. Archaeology Of Asia. Boston: Blackwell Publishing, 2005. ISBN 978-1-4051-0212-4
Miriam T. Stark. Archaeology of Asia. John Wiley & Sons, 2008. ISBN 978-1-4051-5303-4
Stephen Turnbull↗. Samurai Invasion. Japan's Korean War 1592–98. London: Cassell & Co, 2002. ISBN 978-0-304-35948-6
Hugh Dyson Walker. East Asia: A New History. AuthorHouse, 2012. ISBN 978-1-4772-6517-8
Sung-chul Yang. The North and South Korean political systems: A comparative analysis. Seoul: Hollym, 1999. ISBN 978-1-56591-105-5

C/J/K books

Byeon Tae-seop (변태섭). 韓國史通論 (Hanguksa tongnon) (Outline of Korean history), 4th ed. Seoul: Samyeongsa, 1999. ISBN 978-89-445-9101-3
Keizo Yamawaki. Japan and Foreign Laborers: Chinese and Korean Laborers in the late 1890s and early 1920s (近代日本と外国人労働者―1890年代後半と1920年代前半における中国人・朝鮮人労働者問題). Tokyo: Akashi-shoten (明石書店), 1994. ISBN 978-4-7503-0568-4
Setsuko Miyata. Creating Surnames and Changing Given Names (創氏改名). Tokyo: Akashi-shoten (明石書店), 1992. ISBN 978-4-7503-0406-9
Lee Young-hoon↗ (이영훈). Anti-Japan Tribalism↗. Miraesa (미래사), 2019. ISBN 978-89-7087-326-8
Choe Ki-ho (최기호). 日韓併合 : 歴史再検証 : 韓民族を救った「日帝36年」の真実(The Japanese annexation of Korea:Reverification of history:The truth of 36 years lasted "Ilje Gangjeom-gi" that rescued Korean). Shōdensha, 2007. ISBN 978-4-396-31435-4
Alleyne Ireland↗. The New Korea. New York E.P. Dutton & company, 1926
George Trumbull Ladd↗. In Korea with Marquis Ito. New York : C. Scribner's Sons, 1908
O Sonfa↗. Getting over it! : why Korea needs to stop bashing Japan. Tokyo: Tachibana Publishing, 2015

Notes

External links

Wikivoyage: History of Korea↗

the National Institute of Korean History
Korean History online — Korean History Information Center
Timeline of Korean Dynasties
Kyujanggak Archive, PDF copies of Korean classics in their original written classical Chinese
Korean History: Bibliography (Archived on 2011-06-30↗) — Center for Korean Studies, University of Hawaii at Manoa↗.
History of Korea — KBS World
History of Corea, Ancient and Modern; with Description of Manners and Customs, Language and Geography Archived on 2015-12-01↗ by John Ross↗, 1891.

North Korea

North Korea, officially the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK), is a country in East Asia↗. It constitutes the northern half of the Korean Peninsula and borders China↗ and Russia↗ to the north at the Yalu↗ (Amnok) and Tumen↗ rivers, and South Korea to the south at the Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ (DMZ). The country's western border is formed by the Yellow Sea↗, while its eastern border is defined by the Sea of Japan↗. Pyongyang↗ is the capital and largest city.

The Korean Peninsula↗ was first inhabited as early as the Lower Paleolithic↗ period. Its first kingdom↗ was noted in Chinese records in the early 7th century BCE. Following the unification of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ into Silla↗ and Balhae↗ in the late 7th century, Korea was ruled by the Goryeo dynasty↗ (918–1392) and the Joseon dynasty↗ (1392–1897). The succeeding Korean Empire↗ (1897–1910) was annexed in 1910↗ into the Empire of Japan↗. In 1945, after the Japanese surrender↗ at the end of World War II↗, Korea was divided into two zones↗ along the 38th parallel↗, with the north occupied by the Soviet Union↗ and the south occupied by the United States↗.

In 1948, separate governments were formed in Korea: the Soviet-aligned↗ Democratic People's Republic of Korea in the north, and the Western-aligned↗ Republic of Korea in the south. The North Korean invasion of South Korea in 1950 started the Korean War. In 1953, the Korean Armistice Agreement↗ brought about a ceasefire↗ and established a demilitarized zone↗ (DMZ). Kim Il Sung↗, North Korea's first leader, consolidated power and promoted his personal philosophy of Juche↗ as the state ideology↗. Pyongyang's international isolation sharply accelerated from the 1980s onwards as the Cold War↗ came to an end. The fall of the Soviet Union↗ in 1991 then brought about a sharp decline to the North Korean economy. From 1994 to 1998, North Korea suffered a famine↗ with the population continuing to suffer from malnutrition. In 2024, the DPRK formally abandoned efforts to reunify Korea↗.

North Korea is a totalitarian↗ hereditary dictatorship↗ with a comprehensive cult of personality↗ around the Kim family↗. Amnesty International↗ considers the country to have the worst human rights record↗ in the world. Officially, North Korea is a communist state↗, and describes itself as a socialist state↗ which holds democratic elections↗. However, outside observers have described the elections as unfair, uncompetitive, and pre-determined. The Workers' Party of Korea↗ (WPK) is the sole ruling party↗ of North Korea. According to Article 3 of the constitution, Kimilsungism–Kimjongilism↗ is the official ideology of North Korea. The means of production↗ are owned by the state through state-run enterprises↗ and collectivized farms↗. Most services—such as healthcare↗, education↗, housing↗, and food production↗—are subsidized or state-funded.

The country follows Songun↗, a "military first↗" policy which prioritizes the Korean People's Army↗ in state affairs and the allocation of resources. It possesses nuclear weapons↗. Its active-duty army of 1.28 million soldiers is the fourth-largest in the world. In addition to being a member of the United Nations since 1991, North Korea is also a member of the Non-Aligned Movement↗, the G77↗, and the ASEAN Regional Forum↗.

Etymology

See also: Names of Korea↗

The modern spelling of Korea first appeared in 1671 in the travel writings of Hendrick Hamel↗, a sailor of the Dutch East India Company↗.

After the division of the country into North and South Korea, the two sides used different terms to refer to Korea: Korean: 조선 in North Korea, and Korean: 한국 in South Korea. In 1948, North Korea adopted Democratic People's Republic of Korea (Korean: 조선민주주의인민공화국 / Hanja: 朝鮮民主主義人民共和國; ) as its official name. Within North Korea, the country's official name is frequently shortened to just "the Republic" (Korean: 공화국 / Hanja: 共和國), which is a common moniker to refer to North Korea in the country.

In the wider world, because its government controls the northern part of the Korean Peninsula, it is commonly called North Korea to distinguish it from South Korea, which is officially called the Republic of Korea in English. Both governments historically considered themselves to be the legitimate government of the whole of Korea; for this reason, the people of North Korea consider themselves Koreans, not North Koreans, with foreign visitors being discouraged from using the latter term.

History

Main articles: History of Korea and History of North Korea↗

According to Korean mythology↗ in 2333 BC, the Gojoseon↗ Kingdom was established by the god-king Dangun↗. Following the end of the Three Kingdoms of Korea into Silla and Balhae in the late 7th century, Korea was subsequently ruled by the Goryeo dynasty (918–1392) and the Joseon dynasty↗ (1392–1897). In 1897, King Gojong↗ proclaimed the Korean Empire↗, which was annexed↗ by the Empire of Japan↗ in 1910.

Ancient Korea

The Korean Peninsula was inhabited as early as the Lower Paleolithic↗ period.

According to Korea's founding mythology↗, the history of Korea begins with the founding of Joseon (also known as "Gojoseon↗", or "Old Joseon", to differentiate it from the 14th century dynasty) in 2333 BC by the legendary Dangun↗. Gojoseon was noted in Chinese records in the early 7th century. Gojoseon expanded until it controlled the northern Korean Peninsula and parts of Manchuria↗. Gija Joseon↗ was purportedly founded in the 12th century BC, but its existence and role have been controversial in the modern era. In 108 BC, the Han dynasty defeated↗ Wiman Joseon↗ and installed four commanderies↗ in the northern Korean peninsula. Three of the commanderies fell or retreated westward within a few decades, but the Lelang commandery↗ remained a center of cultural and economic exchange with successive Chinese dynasties ruling for four centuries, until it was conquered by Goguryeo in 313.

Beginning around 300 BC, the Japonic↗-speaking Yayoi people↗ from the Korean Peninsula entered the Japanese islands and displaced or intermingled with the original Jōmon↗ inhabitants. The linguistic homeland of Proto-Koreans↗ is located somewhere in southern Siberia↗/Manchuria↗, such as the Liao River↗ area or the Amur↗ River area. Proto-Koreans arrived in the southern part of the Korean Peninsula at around 300 BC, replacing and assimilating Japonic-speakers and likely causing the Yayoi↗ migration.

Three Kingdoms of Korea

During the Proto–Three Kingdoms period↗, the states of Buyeo↗, Okjeo↗, Dongye↗, and Samhan↗ occupied the whole Korean peninsula and southern Manchuria. From them, the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ emerged: Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗.

Goguryeo, the largest and most powerful among them, was a highly militaristic state and competed with various Chinese dynasties during its 700 years of history. Goguryeo experienced a golden age under Gwanggaeto the Great↗ and his son Jangsu↗, who both subdued Baekje and Silla during their respective reigns, achieving a brief unification of the Three Kingdoms and becoming the most dominant power on the Korean Peninsula. In addition to contesting control of the Korean Peninsula, Goguryeo had many military conflicts↗ with various Chinese dynastie↗s, most notably the Goguryeo–Sui War↗, in which Goguryeo defeated a huge force said to number over a million men.

Baekje was a maritime power, sometimes called the "Phoenicia↗ of East Asia". Its maritime ability was instrumental in the dissemination of Buddhism throughout East Asia↗ and spreading continental culture to Japan. Baekje was once a great military power on the Korean Peninsula, especially during the time of Geunchogo↗, but was critically defeated by Gwanggaeto the Great and declined. Silla was the smallest and weakest of the three, but used opportunistic pacts and alliances with the more powerful Korean kingdoms, and eventually Tang China↗, to its advantage.

In 676, the unification of the Three Kingdoms by Silla led to the Northern and Southern States period↗, in which Balhae↗ controlled the northern parts of Goguryeo, and much of the Korean Peninsula was controlled by Later Silla↗. Relationships between Korea and China remained relatively peaceful during this time. Balhae was founded by a Goguryeo general↗ and formed as a successor state to Goguryeo. During its height, Balhae controlled most of Manchuria and parts of the Russian Far East and was called the "Prosperous Country in the East".

Late Silla↗ was a wealthy country, and its metropolitan capital of Gyeongju↗ grew to become the fourth largest city in the world. It experienced a golden age of art and culture, exemplified by monuments such as Hwangnyongsa↗, Seokguram↗, and the Emille Bell↗. It also carried on the maritime legacy and prowess of Baekje, and during the 8th and 9th centuries dominated the seas of East Asia and the trade between China, Korea, and Japan, most notably during the time of Chang Pogo↗. In addition, Silla people made overseas communities in China on the Shandong Peninsula↗ and the mouth of the Yangtze↗ River. However, Silla was later weakened due to internal strife and the revival of successor states Baekje↗ and Goguryeo↗, which culminated into the Later Three Kingdoms↗ period in the late 9th century.

Buddhism flourished during this time. Many Korean Buddhists↗ gained great fame among Chinese Buddhist circles and greatly contributed to Chinese Buddhism↗. Examples of significant Korean Buddhists from this period include Woncheuk↗, Wonhyo↗, Uisang↗, Musang↗, and Kim Gyo-gak↗. Kim was a Silla prince whose influence made Mount Jiuhua↗ one of the Four Sacred Mountains↗ of Chinese Buddhism.

Unified dynasties

In 936, the Later Three Kingdoms were united by Wang Geon↗, who established Goryeo↗ as the successor state of Goguryeo. Balhae had fallen to the Khitan Empire↗ in 926, and a decade later the last crown prince of Balhae↗ fled south to Goryeo, where he was warmly welcomed and included in the ruling family by Wang Geon, thus unifying the two successor nations of Goguryeo. Like Silla, Goryeo was a highly cultural state, and invented the metal movable type printing press↗. After defeating the Khitan Empire, which was the most powerful empire of its time, in the Goryeo–Khitan War↗, Goryeo experienced a golden age that lasted a century, during which the Tripitaka Koreana↗ was completed and significant developments in printing and publishing occurred. This promoted education and the dispersion of knowledge on philosophy, literature, religion, and science. By 1100, there were 12 universities that produced notable scholars.

However, the Mongol invasions↗ in the 13th century greatly weakened the kingdom. Goryeo was never conquered by the Mongols, but exhausted after three decades of fighting, the Korean court sent its crown prince↗ to the Yuan↗ capital to swear allegiance to Kublai Khan↗, who accepted and married one of his daughters to the Korean crown prince. Henceforth, Goryeo continued to rule Korea, though as a tributary ally to the Mongols for the next 86 years. During this period, the two nations became intertwined as all subsequent Korean kings married Mongol princesses, and the last empress↗ of the Yuan dynasty was a Korean princess. In the mid-14th century, Goryeo drove out the Mongols to regain its northern territories, briefly conquered Liaoyang↗, and defeated invasions by the Red Turbans↗. However, in 1392, General Yi Seong-gye↗, who had been ordered to attack China, turned his army around and staged a coup.

Yi Seong-gye declared the new name of Korea as "Joseon" in reference to Gojoseon, and moved the capital to Hanseong (one of the old names of Seoul). The first 200 years of the Joseon dynasty were marked by peace and saw great advancements in science and education, as well as the creation of Hangul by Sejong the Great to promote literacy among the common people. The prevailing ideology of the time was Neo-Confucianism↗, which was epitomized by the seonbi↗ class: nobles who passed up positions of wealth and power to lead lives of study and integrity. Between 1592 and 1598, Japan under Toyotomi Hideyoshi↗ launched invasions of Korea↗, but the advance was halted by Korean forces (most notably the Joseon Navy↗ led by Admiral Yi Sun-sin↗ and his renowned "turtle ship↗") with assistance from righteous army↗ militias formed by Korean civilians, and Ming dynasty↗ Chinese troops. Through a series of successful battles of attrition, the Japanese forces were eventually forced to withdraw, and relations between all parties became normalized. However, the Manchus↗ took advantage of Joseon's war-weakened state and invaded in 1627 and 1637↗ and then went on to conquer↗ the destabilized Ming dynasty. After normalizing relations with the new Qing dynasty↗, Joseon experienced a nearly 200-year period of peace. Kings Yeongjo↗ and Jeongjo↗ particularly led a new renaissance of the Joseon dynasty during the 18th century.

In the 19th century, Joseon began experiencing economic difficulties and widespread uprisings, including the Donghak Peasant Revolution↗. The royal in-law families had gained control of the government, leading to mass corruption and weakening of the state. Additionally, the strict isolationism of the Joseon government that earned it the nickname "the hermit kingdom↗" became increasingly ineffective due to increasing encroachment from powers such as Japan, Russia, and the United States. This was exemplified by the Joseon–United States Treaty of 1882↗, which forced Joseon to open its borders.

Japanese colonization and World War II

Main article: Korea under Japanese rule↗

In the late 19th century, Japan became a significant regional power after winning the First Sino-Japanese War↗ against Qing China and the Russo-Japanese War↗ against the Russian Empire↗. In 1897, King Gojong, the last king of Korea↗, proclaimed Joseon as the Korean Empire↗. However, Japan compelled Korea to become its protectorate↗ in 1905 and formally annexed it↗ in 1910. From 1910 to the end of World War II↗ in 1945, Korea was under Japanese rule↗. What followed was a period of forced assimilation, in which Korean language, culture, and history were suppressed. This led to the March First Movement↗ protests in 1919 and the subsequent foundation of resistance groups in exile, primarily in China. Among the resistance groups was Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea↗.

During the Japanese colonial period, most Koreans were peasants engaged in subsistence farming↗. In the 1930s, Japan developed mines, hydro-electric dams, steel mills, and manufacturing plants in northern Korea and neighboring Manchuria↗. The Korean industrial working class expanded rapidly, and many Koreans went to work in Manchuria. As a result, 65% of Korea's heavy industry was located in the north, but, due to the rugged terrain, only 37% of its agriculture.

Due to its rule by Japan, northern Korea had little exposure to modern, Western ideas. One partial exception was the penetration of religion. Since the arrival of missionaries in the late nineteenth century, the northwest of Korea, and Pyongyang in particular, had been a stronghold of Christianity. As a result, Pyongyang was called the "Jerusalem of the East". A Korean guerrilla movement emerged in the mountainous interior and in Manchuria, harassing the Japanese imperial authorities. One of the most prominent guerrilla leaders was the Communist Kim Il Sung.

Joint US-Soviet occupation and Division of Korea

Main article: Division of Korea↗

After the Japanese surrender↗ at the end of World War II in 1945, the Korean Peninsula was divided↗ into two occupation zones along the 38th parallel↗, with the northern half of the peninsula occupied by the Soviet Union↗ and the southern half by the United States↗. Negotiations on reunification failed. Soviet general Terentii Shtykov↗ recommended the establishment of the Soviet Civil Administration↗ in October 1945, and supported Kim Il Sung as chairman of the Provisional People's Committee of North Korea↗, established in February 1946. In September 1946, South Korean citizens rose up against the Allied Military Government↗. In April 1948, an uprising of the Jeju islanders↗ was violently crushed. The South declared its statehood in May 1948 and two months later the ardent anti-communist Syngman Rhee↗ became its ruler. The Democratic People's Republic of Korea was established in the North on 10 July 1948. p. 121 Shtykov served as the first Soviet ambassador, while Kim Il Sung became premier.

Soviet forces withdrew from the North in 1948, and most American forces withdrew from the South in 1949. Ambassador Shtykov suspected Rhee was planning to invade the North and was sympathetic to Kim's goal of Korean unification under socialism. The two successfully lobbied Soviet leader Joseph Stalin↗ to support a quick war against the South, which culminated in the outbreak of the Korean War.

Korean War

Main article: Korean War

See also: Aftermath of the Korean War↗, Korean Demilitarized Zone↗, and North Korea–South Korea relations↗

The military of North Korea↗ invaded the South on 25 June 1950, and swiftly overran most of the country. The United Nations Command↗ (UNC) was subsequently established following the UN Security Council↗'s recognition of North Korean aggression against South Korea. The motion passed because the Soviet Union↗, a close ally of North Korea and a member of the UN Security Council, was boycotting the UN over its recognition of the Republic of China↗ rather than the People's Republic of China. The UNC, led by the United States, intervened to defend the South, and rapidly advanced into North Korea. As they neared the border with China, Chinese forces↗ intervened on behalf of North Korea, shifting the balance of the war again. Fighting ended on 27 July 1953, with an armistice↗ that approximately restored the original boundaries between North and South Korea, but no peace treaty was signed. Approximately 3 million people died in the Korean War, with a higher proportional civilian death toll than World War II↗ or the Vietnam War↗. In both per capita and absolute terms, North Korea was the country most devastated by the war, which resulted in the death of an estimated 12–15% of the North Korean population (c. 10 million), "a figure close to or surpassing the proportion of Soviet citizens killed in World War II↗", according to Charles K. Armstrong↗. As a result of the war, almost every substantial building in North Korea was destroyed. Some have referred to the conflict as a civil war, with other factors involved.

A heavily guarded demilitarized zone (DMZ) still divides the peninsula, and an anti-communist and anti-North Korea sentiment remains in South Korea. Since the war, the United States has maintained a strong military presence in the South↗ which is depicted by the North Korean government as an imperialist occupation force. It claims that the Korean War was caused by the United States and South Korea.

Leadership of Kim Il Sung

The post-war 1950s and 1960s saw an ideological shift in North Korea, as Kim Il Sung sought to consolidate his power. He was highly critical of Soviet premier Nikita Khrushchev↗ and his de-Stalinization↗ policies and critiqued Khrushchev as revisionist. During the 1956 August faction incident↗, Kim Il Sung purged the rival Soviet↗ and Yan'an factions↗ and successfully resisted efforts by the Soviet Union and China to depose him. Some scholars believe that the 1956 August incident was an example of North Korea demonstrating political independence. However, most scholars consider the final withdrawal of Chinese troops from North Korea in October 1958 to be the latest date when North Korea became effectively independent. In the late 1950s and early 1960s, North Korea sought to distinguish itself internationally by becoming a leader of the Non-Aligned Movement↗ and promoting the ideology of Juche↗. Despite its efforts to break out of the Soviet and Chinese spheres of influence, North Korea remained closely aligned with both countries throughout the Cold War.

Industry was the favored sector in North Korea. Industrial production returned to pre-war levels by 1957. In 1959, relations with Japan had improved somewhat, and North Korea began allowing the repatriation of Japanese citizens in the country. The same year, North Korea revalued the North Korean won↗, which held greater value than its South Korean counterpart. Until the 1960s, economic growth was higher than in South Korea, and North Korean GDP per capita was equal to that of its southern neighbor as late as 1976. However, by the 1980s, the economy had begun to stagnate; it started its long decline in 1987 and almost completely collapsed after the dissolution of the Soviet Union↗ in 1991, when all Soviet aid was suddenly halted.

An internal CIA study acknowledged various achievements of the North Korean government post-war: compassionate care for war orphans and children in general, a radical improvement in the status of women, free housing, free healthcare, and health statistics particularly in life expectancy and infant mortality that were comparable to even the most advanced nations up until the North Korean famine↗. Life expectancy in the North was 72 before the famine which was only marginally lower than in the South. The country once boasted a comparatively developed healthcare system; pre-famine North Korea had a network of nearly 45,000 family practitioners with some 800 hospitals and 1,000 clinics.

The relative peace between the North and South following the armistice was interrupted by border skirmishes, celebrity abductions, and assassination attempts. The North failed in several assassination attempts on South Korean leaders, such as in 1968↗, 1974, and the Rangoon bombing↗ in 1983; tunnels were found under the DMZ and tensions flared over the axe murder incident↗ at Panmunjom↗ in 1976. For almost two decades after the war, the two states did not seek to negotiate with one another. In 1971, secret, high-level contacts began to be conducted culminating in the 1972 July 4 South–North Joint Statement↗ that established principles of working toward peaceful reunification. The talks ultimately failed because in 1973, South Korea declared its preference that the two Koreas should seek separate memberships in international organizations.

Leadership of Kim Jong Il

The Soviet Union was dissolved↗ on 26 December 1991, ending its aid and support to North Korea. In 1992, as Kim Il Sung's health began deteriorating, his son Kim Jong Il slowly began taking over various state tasks. Kim Il Sung died↗ of a heart attack↗ in 1994; Kim Jong Il declared a three-year period of national mourning, afterward officially announcing his position as the new leader. Flooding in the mid-1990s exacerbated the economic crisis, severely damaging crops and infrastructure and leading to widespread famine↗ that the government proved incapable of curtailing, resulting in the deaths of between 240,000 and 420,000 people and leading to the flight of many North Koreans into China, South Korea and neighboring countries. In China, these illegal North Korea child immigrants are called the Kotjebi↗. In 1996, the government accepted UN food aid.

North Korea promised to halt its development of nuclear weapons under the Agreed Framework↗, signed in 1994. South Korea began to engage with the North as part of its Sunshine Policy↗. Kim Jong Il instituted a policy called Songun↗, or "military first". The international environment changed once George W. Bush↗ became U.S. President in 2001, whose administration rejected South Korea's Sunshine Policy and the Agreed Framework. Bush included North Korea in his axis of evil↗ in his 2002 State of the Union Address↗. The U.S. government accordingly treated North Korea as a rogue state↗, while North Korea redoubled its efforts to acquire nuclear weapons. On 9 October 2006, North Korea announced it had conducted its first nuclear weapons test↗. Tensions with South Korea and the United States increased in 2010 with the sinking of the South Korean warship Cheonan↗ and North Korea's bombardment of Yeonpyeongdo↗.

Leadership of Kim Jong Un

On 17 December 2011, Kim Jong Il died↗ from a heart attack. His youngest son Kim Jong Un↗ was announced as his successor. In the face of international condemnation, North Korea continued to develop its nuclear arsenal, possibly including a hydrogen bomb↗ and a missile capable of reaching the United States. Throughout 2017, following Donald Trump↗'s ascension to the US presidency, relations between the United States and North Korea worsened, and there was a period of heightened tension↗ between the two countries. The tensions substantially decreased in 2018, and a détente↗ developed. A series of summits↗ took place between North Korea, South Korea and the United States, though the talks ultimately broke down.

On 30 December 2023, Kim Jong Un marked a significant departure from the longstanding position of mutual claims over the entire Korean Peninsula by both North and South Korea. In 2024, North Korea deployed a contingent of troops to Russia↗ in support of the Russo-Ukrainian war↗.

Geography

Main articles: Geography of North Korea↗ and Geology of North Korea↗

North Korea occupies the northern portion of the Korean Peninsula, lying between latitudes 37°↗ and 43°N↗, and longitudes 124°↗ and 131°E↗. It covers an area of 120540 km². To its west are the Yellow Sea↗ and Korea Bay↗, and to its east lies Japan across the Sea of Japan↗.

Early European visitors to Korea remarked that the country resembled "a sea in a heavy gale" because of the many successive mountain range↗s that crisscross the peninsula. Some 80 percent of North Korea is composed of mountains and uplands, separated by deep and narrow valleys. All of the Korean Peninsula's mountains with elevations of 2000 m or more are located in North Korea. The highest point in North Korea is Paektu Mountain↗, a volcanic mountain with an elevation of 2744 m above sea level. Considered a sacred place by North Koreans, Mount Paektu holds significance in Korean culture and has been incorporated in the elaborate folklore and personality cult around the Kim family. For example, the song, "We Will Go To Mount Paektu" sings in praise of Kim Jong Un and describes a symbolic trek to the mountain. Other prominent ranges are the Hamgyong Range↗ in the extreme northeast and the Rangrim Mountains↗, which are located in the north-central part of North Korea. Mount Kumgang↗ in the Taebaek Range↗, which extends into South Korea, is famous for its scenic beauty.

The coastal plains are wide in the west and discontinuous in the east. A great majority of the population lives in the plains and lowlands. According to a United Nations Environmental Programme↗ report in 2003, forest covers over 70 percent of the country, mostly on steep slopes. North Korea had a 2019 Forest Landscape Integrity Index↗ mean score of 8.02/10, ranking it 28th globally out of 172 countries. The longest river is the Amnok↗ (Yalu) River which flows for 790 km. The country contains three terrestrial ecoregions: Central Korean deciduous forests↗, Changbai Mountains mixed forests↗, and Manchurian mixed forests↗.

Climate

North Korea experiences a humid continental climate↗ within the Köppen climate classification↗ scheme. Winters bring clear weather interspersed with snow storms as a result of northern and northwestern winds that blow from Siberia↗. Summer tends to be by far the hottest, most humid, and rainiest time of year because of the southern and southeastern monsoon↗ winds that carry moist air from the Pacific Ocean↗. Approximately 60 percent of all precipitation occurs from June to September. Spring and autumn are transitional seasons between summer and winter. The daily average high and low temperatures for Pyongyang are −3 °C and −13 °C in January and 29 °C and 20 °C in August.

Governance and politics

Main article: Politics of North Korea↗

North Korea is a highly centralized communist state↗ that self-identifies as a socialist state↗. North Korea is unique among communist states due to the political dominance of the Kim family↗ or dynasty. The three supreme leaders↗ of North Korea have all been members of the Kim family, and other members of the Kim family are prominent in North Korean political life as well; because of this North Korea's political system has been characterized as hereditary or dynastic. Kim Jong Un, the current supreme leader, heads all major governing structures: he is the leader of the Workers' Party of Korea↗, the head of state↗, and the commander-in-chief↗ of the Korean People's Army↗.

Workers' Party of Korea

The Workers' Party of Korea↗ (WPK) is the founding and sole ruling party of North Korea. While two other parties – the Korean Social Democratic Party↗ and the Chondoist Chongu Party↗ – exist, they are subordinate to the WPK. The leading role↗ of the WPK over state and society is enshrined in the constitution↗ by stating that "the Democratic People's Republic of Korea shall conduct all activities under the leadership of the Workers' Party of Korea." All state organs of North Korea operate under the leadership of the WPK; because of the party's organizational principle of democratic centralism↗, all party members in state organs are required to implement the decisions of the Central Committee of the WPK↗. All state organs consist of a majority of party members as well. The party also establishes party groups within state organs, which the WPK Central Committee supervises through its Organization and Guidance Department↗ and other departments.

The highest organ of the WPK is the party congress↗, which meets at least every fifth year. It elects the General Secretary↗ (the party leader) and the members and candidates of the WPK Central Committee. At its first session after a party congress, the WPK Central Committee elects its central leading organs: the Presidium↗, the Politburo↗, the Secretariat↗, the Central Military Commission↗ (CMC) and the Central Auditing Commission↗ (CAC). The general secretary leads the work of the Presidium, Politburo and the Secretariat, and concurrently serves as chairman of the CMC. These organs are delegated specific powers of the Central Committee when the latter is not in session; the Presidium is the party's highest decision-making organ when the Politburo, Central Committee, the Conference of Representatives and the Congress are not in session.

The unified powers of the Supreme People's Assembly

The Supreme People's Assembly↗ (SPA) is North Korea's supreme state organ of power↗, and holds, formally speaking, the state's unified power↗. It is officially considered the embodiment of popular sovereignty↗ since it is elected through highly controlled elections↗. As the state's highest organ, all other state organs are accountable to it per democratic centralism since, according to the constitution, "All State organs in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea are formed and function on the principle of democratic centralism." As a result, the SPA establishes all other state organs that make up North Korea's unified state apparatus↗ per the division of labour of state organs↗. The constitution of North Korea↗, which is a communist state constitution↗, has created the following hierarchy of state organs: the SPA as the highest, followed by the president of the State Affairs Commission↗, the State Affairs Commission↗ (SAC), the Standing Committee of the Supreme People's Assembly↗, the Cabinet of North Korea↗, local people's assemblies and people's committees, the Central Public Prosecutors Office, and the Supreme Court↗. All these organs are, in theory, accountable to the SPA: This is a formality since, in practice, the other state organs, especially the SAC and the SAC president, work highly independently from the SPA.

Formally speaking, the second-highest state organ in North Korea is the SAC president, which in practice is the most powerful. The officeholder is elected by a session of the SPA, and is by right of office the supreme leader↗ and the commander-in-chief of North Korea↗. Under the constitution, the SAC president is authorised to provide overall guidance for state affairs and to oversee the SAC's work. The officeholder may appoint and dismiss any state official, ratify or abrogate major treaties, issue special pardons, and declare a state of emergency↗. In wartime, the president organises and leads a National Defence Committee. A 2019 constitutional amendment conferred authority to promulgate laws and ordinances of the SPA, as well as major decrees and decisions of the SAC, and to appoint or recall diplomatic representatives resident abroad. The president also holds the power to issue orders binding on the state as a whole. Kim Jong Un is the incumbent SAC president, having held this title since 2016. Upon his re-election in 2019 at the 1st Session of the 14th Supreme People's Assembly↗, Kim Jong Un was elected as "the supreme representative of all the Korean people and supreme leader of the country". Next in line is the SAC itself. The SAC is a collective decision-making organ headed by the SAC president. It is designated as the “supreme policy-oriented leadership organ of State power". It is responsible for executing the decisions of the SAC president and for discussing and adopting state policies more generally.

The fourth-ranking state organ is the permanent organ↗ of the SPA, the Standing Committee. In between convocations of the SPA, most of its powers are transferred to the Standing Committee. In between two SPA sessions, the Standing Committee periodically adopts new bills, which gain force once approved by the SPA, which they always are. There exists a division of labour between the two organs: the SPA may adopt or amend the constitution with the support of more than two-thirds of its representatives, whereas the Standing Committee is empowered to interpret the constitution, laws, and regulations. Constitutional enforcement is the responsibility of the Standing Committee, and its empowered to take appropriate measures, including rescinding decisions, directives, and regulations of state organs that conflict with the constitution or with acts of the SPA, the Standing Committee itself, the SAC, and acts issued by the SAC president. Jo Yong-won↗ has headed the Standing Committee as chairman↗ since 2026, and is the second-ranked official in North Korea.

North Korea's supreme executive and administrative organ of state power↗ is the Cabinet of North Korea, and is the fifth-ranked organ. The cabinet is constitutionally designated as the government of North Korea, and is empowered to administer the national economy and execute the decisions of the SPA, the Standing Committee, the SAC and the SAC president. The head of the cabinet is the premier↗, who is elected by the SPA. Since 29 December 2024, Pak Thae-song↗ has headed the cabinet, and is the third-ranking official in North Korea. The premier's powers extends over two vice premiers, 30 ministers↗, two cabinet commission chairmen, the cabinet chief secretary, the president of the Central Bank↗, the director of the Central Bureau of Statistics↗ and the president of the Academy of Sciences↗.

The Cabinet is, through the Ministry of Social Security↗ and the Ministry of State Security↗, responsible for law enforcement in North Korea↗. The social security ministry is one of the most powerful state institutions in North Korea and oversees the national police force, investigates criminal cases and manages non-political correctional facilities. It handles other aspects of domestic security like civil registration, traffic control, fire departments and railroad security. The state security ministry was separated from the social security ministry in 1973 to conduct domestic and foreign intelligence, counterintelligence and manage the political prison system. This security apparatus is extensive, exerting strict control over residence, travel, employment, clothing, food, family life and employ mass surveillance↗.

The Supreme Court↗ is the state's supreme judicial organ↗, and its president is elected by the SPA. Judicial procedures are handled by the Supreme Court, which also acts as the highest court of appeal↗. As with other communist states, the court is viewed as a political organ responsible for working within the bounds set by the SPA and the WPK. Therefore, courts carry out legal procedures related to not only criminal and civil matters, but also political cases as well. The legal system↗ created by the SPA, and overseen by the Supreme Court, is a civil law↗ system based on the Prussian model↗ and influenced by Japanese traditions and communist legal theory.

Political ideology

Further information: Ideology of the Workers' Party of Korea↗ and Juche↗Kimilsungism–Kimjongilism is the official ideology of North Korea and the WPK, and is the cornerstone of party works and government operations. Juche, part of the larger Kimilsungism–Kimjongilism along with Songun↗ under Kim Jong Un, is viewed by the official North Korean line as an embodiment of Kim Il Sung's wisdom, an expression of his leadership, and an idea which provides "a complete answer to any question that arises in the struggle for national liberation". Juche was pronounced in 1955 in a speech called On Eliminating Dogmatism and Formalism and Establishing Juche in Ideological Work↗ in order to emphasize a Korea-centered revolution. Its core tenets are economic self-sufficiency↗, military self-reliance and an independent foreign policy. The roots of Juche were made up of a complex mixture of factors, including the popularity of Kim Il Sung, the conflict with pro-Soviet and pro-Chinese dissenters, and Korea's centuries-long struggle for independence. Juche was introduced into the constitution in 1972.

Juche was initially promoted as a "creative application" of Marxism–Leninism↗, but in the mid-1970s, it was described by state propaganda in North Korea↗ as "the only scientific thought... and most effective revolutionary theoretical structure that leads to the future of communist society". Juche eventually replaced Marxism–Leninism entirely by the 1980s, and in 1992 references to the latter were omitted from the constitution. The 2009 constitution dropped references to communism and elevated the Songun military first policy while explicitly confirming the position of Kim Jong Il. However, the constitution retains references to socialism. The WPK reasserted its commitment to communism in 2021. Juches concepts of self-reliance have evolved with time and circumstances, but still provide the groundwork for the spartan austerity, sacrifice, and discipline demanded by the party.

Kim family

Main article: Kim family (North Korea)↗

Since the founding of the nation, North Korea's supreme leadership has stayed within the Kim family, which in North Korea is referred to as the Mount Paektu Bloodline, with an extensive cult of personality↗ surrounding them. It is a three-generation lineage descending from the country's first leader, Kim Il Sung, who developed a cult of personality closely tied to the state philosophy of Juche, which was later passed on to his successors: his son Kim Jong Il in 1994 and grandson Kim Jong Un in 2011. The cult of personality surrounding the Kim family has been crucial for legitimizing the family's hereditary succession. The control the North Korean government exercises over many aspects of the nation's culture is used to perpetuate the cult of personality. North Korea is governed by the Ten Principles for the Establishment of a Monolithic Ideological System↗, which establishes standards for governance and a guide for the behaviours of North Koreans. The principles mandate absolute obedience to the Kim family.

Kim Il Sung and Kim Jong Il are officially revered as the "eternal leaders of Korea↗". Several landmarks in North Korea are named for Kim Il Sung↗, including Kim Il Sung University↗, Kim Il Sung Stadium↗, and Kim Il Sung Square↗, while his birthday on 15 April is a public holiday called the Day of the Sun↗. Defectors have been quoted as saying that North Korean schools deify both father and son. Kim Jong Il's personality cult was inherited from his father. Kim Jong Il was often the center of attention throughout ordinary life. His birthday, called the Day of the Shining Star↗, is one of the most important public holidays in the country↗. Kim Jong Il's personality cult, although significant, was not as extensive as his father's. One point of view is that Kim Jong Il's cult of personality was solely out of respect for Kim Il Sung or out of fear of punishment for failure to pay homage, while North Korean government sources consider it genuine hero worship.

Administrative divisions

Main article: Administrative divisions of North Korea↗

See also: Provinces of North Korea↗, Special cities of North Korea↗, and Provinces of Korea↗

Foreign relations

Main article: Foreign relations of North Korea↗

North Korea historically claimed to be the legitimate government of the entire Korean Peninsula↗ and adjacent islands, a claim which was abandoned in 2024. North Korea joined the United Nations↗ in 1991 together with South Korea. North Korea is also a member of the Non-Aligned Movement↗, G77↗ and the ASEAN Regional Forum↗. As of 2015, North Korea had diplomatic relations with 166 countries and embassies in 47 countries.

As a result of its isolation, North Korea is sometimes known as the "hermit kingdom↗", a term that originally referred to the isolationism in the latter part of the Joseon period. Initially, North Korea had diplomatic ties only with other communist countries, and even today, most of the foreign embassies accredited to North Korea are located in Beijing↗ rather than in Pyongyang↗. In the 1960s and 1970s, it pursued an independent foreign policy, established relations with many developing countries, and joined the Non-Aligned Movement. In the late 1980s and the 1990s its foreign policy was thrown into turmoil with the collapse of the Soviet Bloc↗. Suffering an economic crisis, it closed a number of its embassies. At the same time, North Korea sought to build relations with developed free market countries.

North Korea enjoys a close relationship with China↗ which is often called North Korea's closest ally, and the two countries maintain a defense agreement↗. However, relations have sometimes been strained because of China's concerns about North Korea's nuclear program. North Korea has a close relationship with Russia↗ and has voiced support for the 2022 Russian invasion of Ukraine↗, and the two countries signed a defense agreement↗ in 2024. North Korea continues to have strong ties with several Southeast Asian countries such as Vietnam↗, Laos↗, Cambodia↗, and Indonesia↗. Relations with Malaysia↗ were strained in 2017 by the assassination of Kim Jong-nam↗. The kidnapping of at least 13 Japanese citizens↗ by North Korean agents in the 1970s and the 1980s has had a detrimental effect on North Korea's relationship with Japan.

South Korea

Main articles: North Korea–South Korea relations↗ and Korean reunification↗

The Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ with South Korea remains the most heavily fortified border in the world. Inter-Korean relations are at the core of North Korean diplomacy and have seen numerous shifts in the last few decades. In 1972, North and South Korea agreed in principle to achieve reunification↗ through peaceful means and without foreign interference. In 1980, Kim Il Sung proposed a federation between North and South Korea in which the respective political systems would initially remain. However, relations remained cool well until the early 1990s, with a brief period in the early 1980s when North Korea offered to provide flood relief to its southern neighbor. Although the offer was initially welcomed, talks over how to deliver the relief goods broke down and none of the promised aid ever crossed the border. The two countries also organized a reunion of 92 separated families.

The Sunshine Policy↗ instituted by South Korean president Kim Dae-jung↗ in 1998 was a watershed in inter-Korean relations. The culmination of the Sunshine Policy was the 2000 inter-Korean summit↗, when Kim Dae-jung visited Kim Jong Il in Pyongyang. Both North and South Korea signed the June 15th North–South Joint Declaration↗, in which both sides promised to seek peaceful reunification. In 2007, South Korean president Roh Moo-hyun↗ and Kim Jong Il signed an eight-point peace agreement. However, relations worsened when South Korean president Lee Myung-bak↗ adopted a more hard-line approach and suspended aid deliveries pending the de-nuclearization of the North. In 2009, North Korea responded by ending all of its previous agreements with the South. The next few years witnessed a string of hostilities, including the alleged North Korean involvement in the sinking of South Korean warship Cheonan↗, mutual ending of diplomatic talks, and North Korean artillery attack on Yeonpyeongdo↗.

In 2017, Moon Jae-in was elected president of South Korea with a promise to return to the Sunshine Policy. In 2018, a détente developed at the Winter Olympics held in South Korea. In April, South Korean president Moon Jae-in and Kim Jong Un met at the DMZ, and, in the Panmunjom Declaration↗, pledged to work for peace and nuclear disarmament. Relations deteriorated again under the Presidency of Yoon Suk Yeol↗. In 2024, North Korea officially announced through its leader Kim Jong Un that it would no longer seek reunification with South Korea, identifying the country as a "hostile state".

Military

Main article: Korean People's Army↗

See also: North Korea and weapons of mass destruction↗ and Songun↗

The North Korean armed forces, or the Korean People's Army↗ (KPA), is estimated to comprise 1,280,000 active and 6,300,000 reserve and paramilitary troops, making it one of the largest military institutions in the world↗. With an active duty army consisting of 4.9% of its population, North Korea maintains the fourth largest active military force in the world behind China, India and the United States. About 20 percent of men aged 17–54 serve in the regular armed forces, and approximately one in every 25 citizens is an enlisted soldier.

The KPA is divided into five branches: Ground Force↗, Navy↗, Air Force↗, Special Operations Force↗, and Strategic Force↗. Command of the KPA lies in both the Central Military Commission of the Workers' Party of Korea↗ and the State Affairs Commission, which controls the Ministry of Defence↗. Of all the KPA's branches, the Ground Force is the largest, comprising approximately one million personnel, while the Navy operates the largest submarine fleet in the world. The KPA's Special Operation Force is also the world's largest special forces unit.

North Korea is a nuclear-armed state↗, though the nature and strength of the country's arsenal is uncertain. As of June 2024, North Korea was estimated to possess 50 nuclear warheads↗. Delivery capabilities are provided by the Rocket Force, which has ballistic missile↗s with a range of up to 15000 km. As a result of its nuclear and missile tests, North Korea has been sanctioned under multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions↗. According to a 2004 South Korean assessment, North Korea also possesses a stockpile of chemical weapon↗s, as well as the ability to cultivate and produce biological weapons↗.

The sale of weapons to North Korea by other states is prohibited by UN sanctions, and the KPA's conventional capabilities are limited by a number of factors including obsolete equipment, insufficient fuel supplies and a shortage of digital command and control↗ assets. To compensate for these deficiencies, the KPA has deployed a wide range of asymmetric warfare↗ technologies including anti-personnel blinding lasers, GPS↗ jammers, midget submarine↗s and human torpedo↗es, stealth↗ paint, and cyberwarfare↗ units. In 2015, North Korea was reported to employ 6,000 sophisticated computer security personnel in a cyberwarfare unit operating out of China.

Much of the equipment in use by the KPA is engineered and manufactured by the domestic defense industry↗. Weapons are manufactured in roughly 1,800 underground defense industry plants scattered throughout the country, most of them located in Chagang Province↗. The defense industry is capable of producing a full range of weapons, and may even have limited jet aircraft manufacturing capacity. According to North Korean state media, military expenditure amounted to 15.8 percent of the state budget in 2010. The U.S. State Department has estimated that North Korea's military spending averaged 23% of its GDP from 2004 to 2014, the highest level in the world.

Human rights

Main article: Human rights in North Korea↗

See also: Prisons in North Korea↗, Kwalliso↗, and LGBTQ rights in North Korea↗

The state of human rights↗ in North Korea has been widely condemned. A 2014 UN inquiry↗ into the DPRK's human rights record found evidence for "systematic, widespread and gross human rights violations" and stated that "the gravity, scale and nature of these violations reveal a state that does not have any parallel in the contemporary world", with Amnesty International↗ and Human Rights Watch↗ holding similar views. The UN inquiry has accused North Korea of crimes against humanity↗. North Koreans have been referred to as "some of the world's most brutalized people" by Human Rights Watch, because of the severe restrictions placed on their political↗ and economic freedom↗s. There are restrictions on the freedom of association, expression and movement; arbitrary detention, torture and other ill-treatment result in death and execution. Citizens in North Korea are generally not permitted to leave the country at will and its government denies access to UN human rights observers.

The Ministry of State Security extrajudicially apprehends and imprisons those accused of political crimes without due process. People perceived as hostile to the government, such as Christians or critics of the leadership, are deported to re-education camps or political labor camps (kwalliso)↗ without trial, often with their whole family and mostly without any chance of being released. Forced labor is part of an established system of political repression↗. Based on satellite images and defector testimonies, an estimated 200,000 prisoners are held in six large prison camps, where they are made to work to right their wrongdoings. Supporters of the government who deviate from the government line are subject to reeducation↗ in sections of labor camp↗s set aside for that purpose. Those who are deemed politically rehabilitated↗ may reassume responsible government positions on their release. The International Coalition to Stop Crimes Against Humanity in North Korea↗ (ICNK) estimates that over 10,000 people die in North Korean prison camps every year.

The North Korean population is strictly managed by the state and all aspects of daily life are subordinated to party and state planning. According to US government reports, employment is managed by the party on the basis of political reliability, and travel is tightly controlled by the Ministry of People's Security. The US State Department says that North Koreans do not have a choice in the jobs they work and are not free to change jobs at will. With 1,100,000 people in modern slavery↗ (via forced labor), North Korea is ranked highest in the world in terms of the percentage of the population that is enslaved, at 10.4 percent according to the Walk Free↗'s 2018 Global Slavery Index↗. North Korea is the only country in the world that has not explicitly criminalized some form of modern slavery. A United Nations report listed slavery among the crimes against humanity occurring in North Korea. According to the US State Department, the North Korean government does not fully comply with the minimum standards for the elimination of human trafficking↗ and is not making significant efforts to do so. North Korea has trafficked thousands of its own citizens allegedly as forced laborers to other countries, where most of the laborers' earnings are pocketed by Pyongyang.

The North Korean government rejects the human rights abuse claims, calling them a smear campaign and a human rights racket made to topple the government. In a 2014 report to the UN, North Korea dismissed accusations of atrocities as wild rumors. The government, however, admitted some human rights issues related to living conditions and stated that it is working to improve them.

Economy

Main article: Economy of North Korea↗

North Korea has maintained one of the most closed and centralized economies in the world since the 1940s. For several decades, it followed the Soviet pattern of five-year plans with the ultimate goal of achieving self-sufficiency. Extensive Soviet and Chinese support allowed North Korea to rapidly recover from the Korean War and register very high growth rates. Systematic inefficiency began to arise around 1960, when the economy shifted from the extensive↗ to the intensive development↗ stage. The shortage of skilled labor, energy, arable land and transportation significantly impeded long-term growth and resulted in consistent failure to meet planning objectives. The major slowdown of the economy contrasted with South Korea, which surpassed the North in terms of absolute GDP↗ and per capita income by the 1980s. North Korea declared the last seven-year plan unsuccessful in December 1993 and thereafter stopped announcing plans.

The loss of Eastern Bloc↗ trading partners and a series of natural disasters throughout the 1990s caused severe hardships, including widespread famine↗. By 2000, the situation improved owing to a massive international food assistance effort, but the economy continues to suffer from food shortages, dilapidated infrastructure and a critically low energy supply. In an attempt to recover from the collapse, the government began structural reforms in 1998 that formally legalized private ownership↗ of assets and decentralized control over production. A second round of reforms in 2002 led to an expansion of market activities, partial monetization↗, flexible prices and salaries, and the introduction of incentives and accountability techniques. Despite these changes, North Korea remains a command economy↗ where the state owns almost all means of production and development priorities are defined by the government.

North Korea has the structural profile of a relatively industrialized country where nearly half of the gross domestic product↗ is generated by industry↗ and human development↗ is at medium levels. Purchasing power parity↗ (PPP) GDP is estimated at $40 billion, with a very low per capita value of $1,800. In 2024, gross national income↗ per capita was $1,261, compared to $36,760 in South Korea. The North Korean won↗ is the national currency, issued by the Central Bank of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea↗. As of 2023, China is the biggest trading partner of North Korea, accounting for more than 74% of exports and 97% of imports.

The economy is heavily nationalized. Food and housing are extensively subsidized by the state; education and healthcare are free; and the payment of taxes was officially abolished in 1974. A variety of goods are available in department stores and supermarkets in Pyongyang, though most of the population relies on small-scale jangmadang↗ markets. In 2009, the government attempted to stem the expanding free market by banning jangmadang and the use of foreign currency, heavily devaluing the won and restricting the convertibility of savings in the old currency, but the resulting inflation↗ spike and rare public protests caused a reversal of these policies. Private trade is dominated by women because most men are required to be present at their workplace, even though many state-owned enterprises are non-operational.

Industry and services employ 65% of North Korea's 17.6 million labor force. Major industries include machine building, military equipment, chemicals, mining, metallurgy, textiles, food processing and tourism↗. Iron ore↗ and coal↗ production are among the few sectors where North Korea performs significantly better than its southern neighbor—it produces about 10 times more of each resource. Using ex-Romanian drilling rigs, several oil exploration companies have confirmed significant oil reserves in the North Korean shelf of the Sea of Japan, and in areas south of Pyongyang. The agricultural sector was shattered by the natural disasters of the 1990s. Its 3,500 cooperatives↗ and state farms were moderately successful until the mid-1990s but now experience chronic fertilizer↗ and equipment shortages. Rice, corn, soybeans and potatoes↗ are some of the primary crops. A significant contribution to the food supply comes from commercial fishing and aquaculture↗. Smaller specialized farms, managed by the state, also produce high-value crops, including ginseng↗, honey↗, matsutake↗ and herbs for traditional Korean↗ and Chinese medicine↗. Tourism has been a growing sector for the past decade, with North Korea aiming to increase the number of foreign visitors through projects like the Masikryong Ski Resort↗.

Transportation

Main article: Transport in North Korea↗

Transport infrastructure in North Korea includes railways, highways, water and air routes, but rail transport is by far the most widespread. North Korea has some 5200 km of railways mostly in standard gauge↗ which carry 80% of annual passenger traffic and 86% of freight, but electricity shortages undermine their efficiency. Construction of a high-speed rail↗way connecting Kaesong, Pyongyang and Sinuiju↗ with speeds exceeding 200 km/h was approved in 2013. North Korea connects with the Trans-Siberian Railway↗ through Rajin↗.

Road transport is very limited—only 724 km of the 25554 km road network are paved, and maintenance on most roads is poor. Only 2% of the freight capacity is supported by river and sea transport, and air traffic is negligible. All port facilities are ice-free and host a merchant fleet of 158 vessels. 81 airports and 8 helipads are operational and the largest serve the state-run airline, Air Koryo↗. Cars are relatively rare, though private car ownership has increased in the 2020s. Bicycles are common. There is only one international airport↗—Pyongyang International Airport↗—serviced by Russia and China (see List of public airports in North Korea↗)

Energy

Main article: Energy in North Korea↗

North Korea's energy infrastructure is obsolete and in disrepair. Power shortages are chronic and would not be alleviated even by electricity imports because the poorly maintained grid causes significant losses during transmission. Coal↗ accounts for 70% of primary energy production, followed by hydroelectric power↗ with 17%. The government under Kim Jong Un has increased emphasis on renewable energy projects like wind farms, solar parks, solar heating and biomass↗. North Korea's long-term objective is to curb fossil fuel usage and reach an output of 5 million kilowatt↗s from renewable sources by 2044, up from its current total of 430,000 kilowatts from all sources. Wind power is projected to satisfy 15% of the country's total energy demand under this strategy. North Korea also strives to develop its own civilian nuclear program. These efforts are under much international dispute due to their military applications and concerns about safety.

Science and technology

Further information: Korean Committee of Space Technology↗, Telecommunications in North Korea↗, and National Aerospace Technology Administration↗

R&D efforts are concentrated at the State Academy of Sciences, which runs 40 research institutes, 200 smaller research centers, a scientific equipment factory and six publishing houses. The government considers science and technology to be directly linked to economic development. A five-year scientific plan emphasizing IT, biotechnology, nanotechnology, marine technology, and laser and plasma research was carried out in the early 2000s.

Significant resources have been allocated to the national space program, which is managed by the National Aerospace Technology Administration↗ (formerly managed by the Korean Committee of Space Technology↗ until April 2013). Domestically produced launch vehicles↗ and the Kwangmyŏngsŏng satellite class↗ are launched from two spaceport↗s, the Tonghae Satellite Launching Ground↗ and the Sohae Satellite Launching Station↗. After four failed attempts, North Korea became the tenth spacefaring nation↗ with the launch of Kwangmyŏngsŏng-3 Unit 2↗ in December 2012, which successfully reached orbit but was believed to be crippled and non-operational. It joined the Outer Space Treaty↗ in 2009 and has stated its intentions to undertake crewed↗ and Moon missions↗. The government insisted the space program is for peaceful purposes, but the United States, Japan, South Korea and other countries maintained that it serves to advance North Korea's ballistic missile program. On 7 February 2016, a statement broadcast on Korean Central Television said that a near Earth observation satellite, Kwangmyongsong-4↗, had successfully been put into orbit.

Usage of communication technology is controlled by the Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications↗. An adequate nationwide fiber-optic↗ telephone system↗ with 1.18 million fixed lines and expanding mobile coverage is in place. Most phones are installed for senior government officials and installation requires written explanation why the user needs a telephone and how it will be paid for. Cellular coverage is available with a 4G↗ network operated by Koryolink↗ and Kangsong NET↗. The number of subscribers has increased from 3,000 in 2002 to almost two million in 2013. International calls through either fixed or cellular service are restricted, and mobile Internet↗ is not available. Internet access itself is limited to a handful of elite users and scientists. Instead, North Korea has a walled garden↗ intranet↗ system called Kwangmyong↗, which is maintained and monitored by the Korea Computer Center↗. Its content is limited to state media, chat services, message boards, an e-mail service and an estimated 1,000–5,500 websites. Computers employ the Red Star OS↗, an operating system derived from Linux↗, with a user shell↗ visually similar to that of macOS↗.

Demographics

Main article: Demographics of North Korea↗

See also: Koreans↗ and List of cities in North Korea↗

With the exception of a small Chinese community↗ and a few ethnic Japanese↗, North Korea's 26,100,000 people are ethnically homogeneous. Demographic experts in the 20th century estimated that the population would grow to 25.5 million by 2000 and 28 million by 2010, but this increase never occurred due to the North Korean famine↗. The famine, which began in 1995 and lasted for three years, resulted in the deaths of an estimated 240,000 to 420,000 North Koreans.

International donors led by the United States initiated shipments of food through the World Food Programme↗ in 1997 to combat the famine. The situation gradually improved: the number of malnourished children declined from 60% in 1998 to 28% in 2013. Domestic food production almost recovered to the recommended annual level of 5.37 million tons of cereal equivalent in 2013, but the World Food Programme reported a continuing lack of dietary diversity and access to fats and proteins. By the mid-2010s national levels of severe wasting, an indication of famine-like conditions, were lower than in other low-income countries and about on par with developing nations in the Pacific and East Asia. Children's health and nutrition is significantly better on a number of indicators than in many other Asian countries.

The famine had a significant impact on the population growth rate, which declined to 0.9% annually in 2002. It was 0.4% in 2024. Late marriages after military service, limited housing space and long hours of work or political studies further exhaust the population and reduce growth. The national birth rate is 13.2 births per year per 1,000 population. Two-thirds of households consist of extended families↗ mostly living in two-room units. Marriage↗ is virtually universal and divorce↗ is extremely rare.

Language

Main articles: Korean language↗ and Korean dialects↗

Further information: North–South differences in the Korean language↗

North Korea shares the Korean language↗ with South Korea, although some dialectal differences↗ exist within both Koreas. North Koreans refer to their Pyongan dialect↗ as munhwaŏ↗ ("cultured language") as opposed to the dialects of South Korea, especially the Seoul dialect↗ or p'yojun'ŏ ("standard language"), which are viewed as decadent because of its use of loanwords from Chinese↗ and European languages↗ (particularly English↗). Words of Chinese, Manchu or Western origin have been eliminated from munhwa along with the usage of Chinese hanja↗ characters. Written language uses only the Chosŏn'gŭl↗ (Hangul) phonetic alphabet, developed under Sejong the Great (1418–1450).

Religion

Main article: Religion in North Korea↗

North Korea is officially an atheist state↗. Its constitution guarantees freedom of religion↗ under Article 68, but this principle is limited by the requirement that religion may not be used as a pretext to harm the state, introduce foreign forces, or harm the existing social order. Religious practice is therefore restricted, despite nominal constitutional protections. Proselytizing is also prohibited due to concerns about foreign influence. The number of Christian churchgoers nonetheless more than doubled between the 1980s and the early 2000s due to the recruitment of Christians who previously worshipped privately or in small house churches. The Open Doors↗ mission, a Protestant group based in the United States and founded during the Cold War era, claims the most severe persecution of Christians↗ in the world occurs in North Korea.

There are no known official statistics of religions in North Korea. According to a 2020 study published by the Centre for the Study of World Christianity↗, 73% of the population are irreligious↗ (58% agnostic↗, 15% atheist↗), 13% practice Chondoism↗, 12% practice Korean shamanism↗, 1.5% are Buddhist↗, and less than 0.5% practice another religion such as Christianity↗, Islam↗, or Chinese folk religion↗. Amnesty International has expressed concerns about religious persecution in North Korea. Pro-North groups such as the Paektu Solidarity Alliance deny these claims, saying that multiple religious facilities exist across the nation. Some religious places of worship are located in foreign embassies in the capital city of Pyongyang. Five Christian churches built with state funds stand in Pyongyang: three Protestant, one Roman Catholic, and one Russian Orthodox. Critics claim these are showcases for foreigners.

Buddhism and Confucianism↗ still influence spirituality. Chondoism ("Heavenly Way") is an indigenous syncretic belief↗ combining elements of Korean shamanism, Buddhism, Taoism↗ and Catholicism↗ that is officially represented by the WPK-controlled Chondoist Chongu Party↗. Chondoism is recognized and favored by the government, being seen as an indigenous form of "revolutionary religion".

Education

Main article: Education in North Korea↗

The 2008 census↗ listed the entire population as literate. An 11-year free, compulsory cycle of primary and secondary education is provided in more than 27,000 nursery school↗s, 14,000 kindergarten↗s, 4,800 four-year primary and 4,700 six-year secondary schools. 77% of males and 79% of females aged 30–34 have finished secondary school. An additional 300 universities and colleges offer higher education↗.

Most graduates from the compulsory program do not attend university but begin their obligatory military service or proceed to work in farms or factories instead. The main deficiencies of higher education are the heavy presence of ideological subjects, which comprise 50% of courses in social studies and 20% in sciences, and the imbalances in curriculum. The study of natural sciences is greatly emphasized while social sciences are neglected. Heuristics↗ is actively applied to develop the independence and creativity of students throughout the system. The study of Russian↗ and English↗ was made compulsory in upper middle schools in 1978.

Health

Main article: Health in North Korea↗

North Korea has a life expectancy of 72.3 years in 2019, according to HDR 2020. While North Korea is classified as a low-income country, the structure of North Korea's causes of death (2013) is unlike that of other low-income countries. Instead, it is closer to worldwide averages, with non-communicable diseases—such as cardiovascular disease and cancers—accounting for 84 percent of the total deaths in 2016. According to the World Bank report of 2016 (based on WHO↗'s estimate), only 9.5% of the total deaths recorded in North Korea are attributed to communicable diseases and maternal, prenatal and nutrition conditions, a figure which is slightly lower than that of South Korea (10.1%) and one fifth of other low-income countries (50.1%) but higher than that of high income countries (6.7%). Only one out of ten leading causes of overall deaths in North Korea is attributed to communicable diseases (lower respiratory infection↗), a disease which is reported to have declined by six percent since 2007.

In 2013, cardiovascular disease↗ as a single disease group was reported as the largest cause of death in North Korea. The three major causes of death in North Korea are stroke↗, COPD↗ and ischaemic heart disease↗. Non-communicable diseases risk factors in North Korea include high rates of urbanization, an aging society, and high rates of smoking↗ and alcohol↗ consumption amongst men. Maternal mortality is lower than other low-income countries, but significantly higher than South Korea and other high income countries, at 89 per 100,000 live births. In 2008 child mortality was estimated to be 45 per 1,000, which is much better than other economically comparable countries. Chad↗ for example had a child mortality rate of 120 per 1,000, despite the fact that Chad was most likely wealthier than North Korea at the time. According to a 2003 report by the United States Department of State↗, almost 100% of the population has access to water and sanitation. Further, 80% of the population had access to improved sanitation↗ facilities in 2015.

A free universal insurance system is in place. Quality of medical care varies significantly by region and is often low, with severe shortages of equipment, drugs and anesthetics. According to WHO, expenditure on health per capita is one of the lowest in the world. Preventive medicine↗ is emphasized through physical exercise and sports, nationwide monthly checkups and routine spraying of public places against disease. Every individual has a lifetime health card which contains a full medical record. Healthcare Access and Quality Index, as calculated by IHME↗, was reported to stand at 62.3, much lower than that of South Korea. North Korea has the highest number of doctors per capita amongst low-income countries, with 3.7 physicians per 1,000 people, a figure which is also significantly higher than that of South Korea, according to WHO↗'s data. Conflicting reports between Amnesty and WHO have emerged, where the Amnesty report claimed that North Korea had an inadequate health care system, while the Director of the World Health Organization claimed that North Korea's healthcare system was considered the envy of the developing world and had "no lack of doctors and nurses".

Songbun

Main article: Songbun↗

According to U.S. reports and refugee testimonies, all North Koreans are sorted into groups according to their Songbun↗, an ascribed status↗ system based on a citizen's assessed loyalty to the government. Based on their own behavior and the political, social, and economic background of their family for three generations as well as behavior by relatives within that range, Songbun is allegedly used to determine whether an individual is trusted with responsibility or given certain opportunities. Songbun reportedly affects access to educational and employment opportunities and particularly whether a person is eligible to join North Korea's ruling party.

There are 3 main classifications and about 50 sub-classifications. According to Kim Il Sung, speaking in 1958, the loyal "core class" constituted 25% of the North Korean population, the "wavering class" 55%, and the "hostile class" 20%. The highest status is accorded to individuals descended from those who participated with Kim Il Sung in the resistance against Japanese occupation before and during World War II and to those who were factory workers, laborers, or peasants in 1950. While some analysts believe private commerce recently changed the Songbun system to some extent, most North Korean refugees say it remains a commanding presence in everyday life. The North Korean government claims all citizens are equal and denies any discrimination on the basis of family background.

Culture

Main article: Culture of North Korea↗

See also: Culture of Korea↗

Despite a historically strong Chinese influence, Korean culture has shaped its own unique identity. It came under attack during the Japanese rule↗ from 1910 to 1945, when Japan enforced a cultural assimilation↗ policy. Koreans were forced to learn and speak Japanese, adopt the Japanese family name system and Shinto↗ religion, and were forbidden to write or speak the Korean language in schools, businesses, or public places.

After the peninsula was divided in 1945, two distinct cultures formed out of the common Korean heritage. North Koreans have little exposure to foreign influence. The revolutionary struggle and the brilliance of the leadership are some of the main themes in art. "Reactionary" elements from traditional culture have been discarded and cultural forms with a "folk" spirit have been reintroduced.

Korean heritage is protected and maintained by the state. Over 190 historical sites and objects of national significance are cataloged as National Treasures of North Korea↗, while some 1,800 less valuable artifacts are included in a list of Cultural Assets↗. The Historic Monuments and Sites in Kaesong↗ and the Complex of Koguryo Tombs↗ are UNESCO↗ World Heritage Site↗s. The Goguryeo tombs↗ are registered on UNESCO's list of World Heritage Sites. These remains were registered as the first World Heritage property of North Korea in the UNESCO World Heritage Committee↗ (WHC) in July 2004. There are 63 burial mounds on the site, with clear murals preserved. The burial customs of the Goguryeo culture have influenced Asian civilizations beyond Korea, including Japan.

Art

See also: Korean art↗ and Korean architecture↗

Visual arts are generally produced in the aesthetic of socialist realism↗. North Korean painting combines the influence of Soviet and Japanese visual expression to instill a sentimental loyalty to the system. All artists in North Korea are required to join the Artists' Union, and the best among them can receive an official license to portray the leaders. Portraits and sculptures depicting Kim Il Sung, Kim Jong Il and Kim Jong Un are classed as "Number One works".

Most aspects of art have been dominated by Mansudae Art Studio↗ since its establishment in 1959. It employs around 1,000 artists in what is likely the biggest art factory in the world where paintings, mural↗s, poster↗s and monuments are designed and produced. The studio has commercialized its activity and sells its works to collectors in a variety of countries including China, where it is in high demand. Mansudae Overseas Projects↗ is a subdivision of Mansudae Art Studio that carries out construction of large-scale monuments for international customers.

Literature

Main article: North Korean literature↗

All publishing houses are owned by the government or the WPK because they are considered an important tool for agitprop↗. The Workers' Party of Korea Publishing House↗ is the most authoritative among them and publishes all works of Kim Il Sung↗, ideological education materials and party policy documents. The availability of foreign literature is limited, examples being North Korean editions of Indian, German, Chinese and Russian fairy tales, Tales from Shakespeare↗ and some works of Bertolt Brecht↗ and Erich Kästner↗.

Kim Il Sung's personal works are considered "classical masterpieces" while the ones created under his instruction are labeled "models of Juche literature". These include The Fate of a Self-Defense Corps Man, The Song of Korea and Immortal History, a series of historical novels depicting the suffering of Koreans under Japanese occupation. More than four million literary works were published between the 1980s and the early 2000s, but almost all of them belong to a narrow variety of political genres like "army-first revolutionary literature".

Science fiction↗ is considered a secondary genre because it somewhat departs from the traditional standards of detailed descriptions and metaphors of the leader. The exotic settings of the stories give authors more freedom to depict cyberwarfare↗, violence↗, sexual abuse↗, and crime↗, which are absent in other genres. Sci-fi works glorify technology and promote the Juche concept of anthropocentric existence↗ through depictions of robotics↗, space exploration↗, and immortality↗.

Music

Main article: Music of North Korea↗

The government emphasized optimistic folk-based tunes and revolutionary music throughout most of the 20th century. Ideological messages are conveyed through massive orchestral pieces like the "Five Great Revolutionary Operas↗" based on traditional Korean ch'angguk↗. Revolutionary operas differ from their Western counterparts by adding traditional instruments to the orchestra and avoiding recitative↗ segments. Sea of Blood↗ is the most widely performed of the Five Great Operas: since its premiere in 1971, it has been played over 1,500 times, and its 2010 tour in China was a major success. Western classical music↗ by Brahms↗, Tchaikovsky↗, Stravinsky↗ and other composers is performed both by the State Symphony Orchestra↗ and student orchestras.

Pop music↗ appeared in the 1980s with the Pochonbo Electronic Ensemble↗ and Wangjaesan Light Music Band↗. Improved relations with South Korea following the 2000 inter-Korean summit↗ caused a decline in direct ideological messages in pop songs, but themes like comradeship, nostalgia and the construction of a powerful country remained. In 2014, the all-girl↗ Moranbong Band↗ was described as the most popular group in the country. North Koreans also listen to K-pop↗ which spreads through illegal markets.

Media

Main article: Media of North Korea↗

North Korean media are under some of the strictest government control in the world. The censorship in North Korea↗ encompasses all the information produced by the media. Monitored heavily by government officials, the media is strictly used to reinforce ideals approved by the government. There is no freedom of press in North Korea as all the media is controlled and filtered through governmental censors. In 2025, North Korea ranked 179th out of 180 countries in Reporters Without Borders↗' annual World Press Freedom Index↗. According to Freedom House↗, all media outlets serve as government mouthpieces, all journalists are party members and listening to foreign broadcasts carries the threat of the death penalty. Cultural products from enemy states such as South Korea are outlawed↗ by the North Korean government, with a maximum penalty of death.

Government policies towards film↗ are no different from those applied to other arts—motion pictures serve to fulfill the targets of "social education". Some of the most influential films are based on historic events (An Jung-geun shoots Itō Hirobumi) or folk tales (Hong Gildong↗). Most movies have predictable propaganda story lines which make cinema an unpopular entertainment; viewers only see films that feature their favorite actors. Most foreign productions are only available at private showings to high-ranking Party members. Access to foreign media products is available through smuggled DVD↗s and television or radio broadcasts in border areas. Some foreign films have been smuggled across the borders of North Korea, allowing for access to the North Korean citizens.

The main news provider is the Korean Central News Agency↗. All 12 major newspapers↗ and 20 periodicals, including Rodong Sinmun↗, the official newspaper of the Party Central Committee, are published in the capital. There are three state-owned TV stations. Two of them broadcast only on weekends and Korean Central Television↗ is on air every day in the evenings. The Associated Press↗ opened the first Western all-format, full-time bureau in Pyongyang in 2012.

Media coverage of North Korea↗ has often been inadequate as a result of the country's isolation. Stories like Kim Jong Un executing his ex-girlfriend or feeding his uncle to a pack of hungry dogs have been circulated by foreign media as truth despite the lack of a credible source. Many of the claims originate from the South Korean right-wing↗ newspaper The Chosun Ilbo↗. Max Fisher of The Washington Post↗ has written that "almost any story [on North Korea] is treated as broadly credible, no matter how outlandish or thinly sourced". Occasional deliberate disinformation on the part of North Korean establishments further complicates the issue.

Cuisine

Main articles: Korean cuisine↗ and North Korean cuisine↗

Korean cuisine has evolved through centuries of social and political change. Originating from ancient agricultural and nomadic traditions↗ in southern Manchuria↗ and the Korean Peninsula, it has gone through a complex interaction of the natural environment and different cultural trends. Rice↗ dishes and kimchi↗ are staple Korean food. In a traditional meal, they accompany both side dishes (panch'an↗) and main courses like chuk↗, pulgogi↗ or noodles↗. Soju↗ liquor is the best-known traditional Korean spirit.

North Korea's most famous restaurant, Okryu-gwan↗, located in Pyongyang, is known for its raengmyŏn↗ cold noodles. Other dishes served there include gray mullet↗ soup with boiled rice, beef rib soup↗, green bean pancake, shinsŏllo↗ and dishes made from terrapin↗. Okryu-gwan sends research teams into the countryside to collect data on Korean cuisine↗ and introduce new recipes. Some Asian cities host branches of the Pyongyang restaurant chain↗ where waitresses perform music and dance.

Sports

Main article: Sport in North Korea↗

Most schools have daily practice in association football↗, basketball↗, table tennis↗, gymnastics↗, boxing↗ and others. The DPR Korea League↗ is popular inside the country and its games are often televised. The national football team, Chollima↗, competed in the FIFA World Cup↗ in 2010↗, when it lost all three matches against Brazil↗, Portugal↗ and Ivory Coast↗. Its 1966 appearance↗ was much more successful, seeing a surprise 1–0 victory over Italy↗ and a quarter final loss to Portugal by 3–5. A national team↗ represents the nation in international basketball competitions as well. In December 2013, former American basketball professional Dennis Rodman↗ visited North Korea to help train the national team after he developed a friendship with Kim Jong Un.

North Korea's first appearance↗ in the Olympics↗ came in 1964↗. The 1972 Olympics↗ saw its summer games debut and five medals, including one gold. With the exception of the boycotted Los Angeles↗ and Seoul Olympics↗, North Korean athletes have won medals in all summer games since then. Weightlifter↗ Kim Un-guk↗ broke the world record↗ of the Men's 62 kg↗ category at the 2012 Summer Olympics↗ in London↗. Successful Olympians receive luxury apartments from the state in recognition for their achievements.

The Arirang Mass Games↗ has been recognized by the Guinness World Records↗ as the biggest choreographic event in the world. Some 100,000 athletes perform rhythmic gymnastics↗ and dances while another 40,000 participants create a vast animated screen in the background. The event is an artistic representation of the country's history and pays homage to Kim Il Sung and Kim Jong Il. Rungrado 1st of May Stadium↗, the second largest stadium in the world↗ with its capacity of 114,000, hosts the Festival. The Pyongyang Marathon↗ is another notable sports event. It is an IAAF Bronze Label Race↗ where amateur runners from around the world can participate.

See also

Outline of North Korea↗
Bibliography of North Korea↗
China–North Korea border↗
North Korea–South Korea border↗

Notes

References

Citations

General and cited sources

"Country Profile: North Korea"↗. Library of Congress – Federal Research Division. July 2007
Felix Abt. A Capitalist in North Korea: My Seven Years in the Hermit Kingdom. Tuttle Publishing, 2014. ISBN 9780804844390
David Alton and Rob Chidley. Building Bridges: Is There Hope for North Korea?. Oxford: Lion Books, 2013. ISBN 978-0-7459-5598-8
Charles K. Armstrong. "The Destruction and Reconstruction of North Korea, 1950–1960". The Asia-Pacific Journal. 20 December 2010, vol. 8, no. 51
Armstrong, Charles K. "North Korea in 2016." Asian Survey 57.1 (2017): 119–27. abstract Archived on 21 July 2019↗
Roland Boer. Red theology : on the Christian Communist tradition. Boston: Haymarket Books↗, 2019. ISBN 978-90-04-38132-2. OCLC 1078879745
Legal Reform in the Contemporary Socialist World. Oxford University Press↗, 2024. ISBN 9780192671585
Adrian Buzo. The Guerilla Dynasty: Politics and Leadership in North Korea. I.B. Tauris↗, 1999. ISBN 978-1860644146
Paul French. North Korea: The Paranoid Peninsula: A Modern History. London: Zed Books, 2007. Second ed. ISBN 978-1-84277-905-7
Patricia Goedde. "Beyond Sham: The North Korean Constitution". Asian Perspective↗. 2020, vol. 44, no. 1, pp. 1–29. doi:10.1353/apr.2020.0002
Hayes, Peter, and Roger Cavazos. "North Korea in 2015." Asian Survey 56.1 (2016): 68–77. abstract Archived on 21 July 2019↗
Hayes, Peter, and Roger Cavazos. "North Korea in 2014." Asian Survey 55.1 (2015): 119–31. abstract Archived on 21 July 2019↗; also full text online Archived on 4 April 2023↗
Van Jackson. Rival Reputations: Coercion and Credibility in US–North Korea Relations. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2016. ISBN 978-1-107-13331-0, covers 1960s to 2010.
Jackson, Van. "Deterring a Nuclear-Armed Adversary in a Contested Regional Order: The 'Trilemma' of US–North Korea Relations." Asia Policy 23.1 (2017): 97–103. online Archived on 23 December 2017↗
Sheila Miyoshi Jager↗. Brothers at War – The Unending Conflict in Korea. London: Profile Books, 2013. ISBN 978-1-84668-067-0
Nam-Sik Kim. "North Korea's Power Structure and Foreign Relations: an Analysis of the Sixth Congress of the KWP". The Journal of East Asian Affairs. Spring–Summer 1982, vol. 2, no. 1, pp. 125–151. JSTOR 23253510
Lee, Hong Yung. "North Korea in 2013: Economy, Executions, and Nuclear Brinksmanship." Asian Survey 54.1 (2014): 89–100. Online Archived on 8 August 2019↗.
"A historical approach to the leadership of the Organisation and Guidance Department of the Workers' Party of Korea". Acta Asiatica Varsoviensia↗. 2019, vol. 32, pp. 99–116. doi:10.1163/157303577X00110
Michael Kirby, Marzuki Darusman, and Sonja Biserko. "Report of the Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea"↗. United Nations Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights. 17 February 2014
Bradley K. Martin. Under the Loving Care of the Fatherly Leader: North Korea and the Kim Dynasty. New York: Thomas Dunne Books, 2004. ISBN 978-0-312-32322-6
"North Korea's Seventh Party Congress: Significance and Responses from the Major Stakeholders"↗. Indian Council of World Affairs↗. 2016. p. 1–14
Brian Reynolds Myers↗. The Cleanest Race: How North Koreans See Themselves and Why It Matters. Melville House, 2011. ISBN 978-1933633916
Understanding North Korea 2014. Research and Development Division, National Institute for Unification Education, Ministry of Unification↗, 2014
"North Korea – A Country Study"↗. Library of Congress Country Studies↗. 2009
Sonia Ryang. The North Korean Homeland of Koreans in Japan. Koreans in Japan: Critical Voices from the Margin. London: Routledge, 2013. p. 32–54. ISBN 978-1-136-35305-5
Yonhap News Agency, ed. North Korea Handbook. Yonhap T'ongsin, 2003. ISBN 978-0-7656-1004-1

External links

Government websites

KCNA (Archived on 4 March 2016↗) – website of the Korean Central News Agency↗
Naenara (Archived on 18 August 2021↗) – the official North Korean governmental portal Naenara↗
DPRK Foreign Ministry (Archived on 24 April 2019↗) – official North Korean foreign ministry website
The Pyongyang Times – official foreign language newspaper of the DPRK (archived)

General websites

Britannica: Encyclopaedia Britannica↗
Official website of the DPR of Korea Archived on 26 October 2008↗ – Administered by the Korean Friendship Association
38North Archived on 15 November 2011↗
North Korea profile Archived on 8 March 2021↗ at BBC News↗
North Korea – link collection (University of Colorado at Boulder↗ Libraries GovPubs)
NKnews Archived on 20 October 2017↗ – a news agency covering North Korean topics.
Friend.com.kp Archived on 2010-07-31↗ – website of the Committee for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries↗
Korea Education Fund Archived on 17 May 2013↗
Rodong Sinmun – the newspaper of the Central Committee of the Workers' Party of Korea Rodong Sinmun↗
Uriminzokkiri Archived on 7 March 2016↗
DPRK Portal Archived on 5 October 2022↗
United Nations Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights Archived on 17 February 2014↗ – Report of the Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea↗

40°N 127°E

Korea

Korea is a peninsula↗r region in East Asia↗ consisting of the Korean Peninsula, Jeju Island↗, and smaller islands. Since the end of World War II in Asia↗ in 1945, it has been politically divided↗ at or near the 38th parallel↗ between North Korea↗ (Democratic People's Republic of Korea; DPRK) and South Korea↗ (Republic of Korea; ROK). Both countries proclaimed independence in 1948, and the two countries fought the Korean War↗ from 1950 to 1953. The region is bordered by China↗ to the north and Russia↗ to the northeast, across the Amnok↗ (Yalu) and Duman↗ (Tumen) rivers, and is separated from Japan↗ to the southeast by the Korea Strait↗.

Known human habitation of the Korean peninsula dates to 40,000 BC. The kingdom of Gojoseon↗, which according to tradition was founded in 2333 BC, fell to the Han dynasty↗ in 108 BC. It was followed by the Three Kingdoms↗ period, in which Korea was divided into Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗. In 668 AD, Silla conquered Baekje and Goguryeo with the aid of the Tang dynasty↗, forming Unified Silla↗; Balhae↗ succeeded Goguryeo in the north. In the late 9th century, Unified Silla collapsed into three states, beginning the Later Three Kingdoms↗ period. In 918, Goguryeo was resurrected as Goryeo↗, which achieved what has been called a "true national unification" by Korean historians, as it unified both the Later Three Kingdoms and the ruling class of Balhae after its fall. Goryeo, whose name developed into the modern exonym↗ "Korea", became a vassal state↗ of the Mongol Empire↗ during the 13th century. Goryeo overthrew Mongol rule before falling to a coup led by General Yi Seong-gye↗, who established the Joseon↗ dynasty in 1392. The first 200 years of Joseon were marked by peace; the Hangul, the Korean alphabet↗ was created and Confucianism↗ became influential. This ended with Japanese↗ and Qing invasions↗, which brought devastation to Joseon and led to Korean isolationism. After the invasions, an isolated Joseon experienced another nearly 200-year period of peace and prosperity, along with cultural and technological development. In the final years of the 19th century, Japan forced Joseon to open up↗ and Joseon experienced turmoil such as the Kapsin Coup↗, Donghak Peasant Revolution↗, and the assassination of Empress Myeongseong↗. In 1895, Japan defeated China↗ in the First Sino-Japanese War↗ and China lost suzerainty over Korea and Korea was placed under further Japanese influence. In 1897, the centuries old Joseon was replaced by the Korean Empire↗ with the Joseon's last king, Gojong↗, becoming the Emperor of the Korean Empire. Japan's further victory in the 1904–1905 Russo-Japanese War↗, expelled Russian influence in Korea and Manchuria. In 1905, the Korean Empire became a protectorate of the Empire of Japan↗. In 1910, the Empire of Japan↗ officially annexed the Korean peninsula↗.

Korea under Japanese rule↗ was marked by industrialization and modernization, economic exploitation, and brutal suppression of the Korean independence movement↗, as reflected in the 1919 March First Movement↗. The Japanese suppressed Korean culture, and during World War II forcefully mobilized millions of Koreans to support its war effort. In 1945, Japan surrendered to the Allies↗, and the Soviet Union↗ and United States↗ agreed to divide Korea into two military occupation zones divided by the 38th parallel, with the Soviet zone in the north and American zone in the south. The division was meant to be temporary, with plans for Korea to be reunited under a single government. In 1948, the DPRK and ROK were established with the backing of each power, and ongoing tensions led to the outbreak of the Korean War in 1950, which came to involve U.S.-led United Nations↗ and communist Chinese↗ forces. The war ended in stalemate in 1953, but without a peace treaty. A demilitarized zone↗ was created between the countries, approximating the original partition.

This status contributes to the high tensions that divide the peninsula, and South Korea claims to be the sole legitimate government of Korea. South Korea is a regional power↗ and a developed country↗, with its economy↗ ranked as the world's fourteenth-largest by GDP (PPP)↗. Its armed forces↗ are one of the world's strongest militaries, with the world's second-largest standing army by military and paramilitary personnel↗. South Korea has been renowned for its globally influential pop culture, particularly in music (K-pop↗) and cinema↗, a phenomenon referred to as the Korean Wave↗. North Korea follows Songun↗, a "military first↗" policy which prioritizes the Korean People's Army↗ in state affairs and resources. It possesses nuclear weapons↗, and is the country with the highest number of military personnel↗, with a total of 7.8 million active↗, reserve↗, and paramilitary↗ personnel, or approximately 30% of its population. Its active duty army of 1.3 million soldiers is the fourth-largest in the world, consisting of 4.9% of its population. North Korea is widely considered to have the worst human rights record↗ in the world.

Etymology

Main article: Names of Korea↗ See also: Korean romanization↗

"Korea" is the modern spelling of "Corea", a name attested in English as early as 1614. "Corea" is derived from the name of the ancient kingdom of Goryeo↗. Korea was transliterated↗ as Cauli in The Travels of Marco Polo↗, of the Chinese↗ 高麗 (MC↗: Kawlej, mod.↗ Gāolì). This was the Hanja↗ for the Korean kingdom of Goryeo↗ (Korean: 고려 / Hanja: 高麗), which ruled most of the Korean peninsula during the 12th century. Korea's introduction to the West resulted from trade and contact with merchants from Arabic lands, with some records dating back as far as the 9th century. Goryeo's name was a continuation of Goguryeo↗ (Koguryŏ) the northernmost of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, which was officially known as Goryeo beginning in the 5th century. The original name was a combination of the adjectives "high" and "lofty" with the name of a local Yemaek↗ tribe, whose original name is thought to have been either "Guru" (溝樓, lit. Walled City, inferred from some toponyms in Chinese historical documents) or "Gauri" (가우리, lit. Center). With expanding British and American trade following the opening of Korea↗ in the late 19th century, the spelling "Korea" appeared and gradually grew in popularity. The name Korea is now commonly used in English contexts by both North and South Korea.

In South Korea, Korea as a whole is referred to as Hanguk/Han'guk (Korean: 한국, [haːnɡuk]). The name references Samhan↗, referring to the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, not the ancient confederacies in the southern Korean Peninsula. Although written in Hanja as 韓, 幹, or 刊, this Han has no relation to the Chinese place names or peoples who used those characters but was a phonetic transcription↗ (OC↗: *↗Gar, MC↗: Han or Gan) of a native Korean word that seems to have had the meaning "big" or "great", particularly in reference to leaders. It has been tentatively linked with the title khan↗ used by the nomads of Manchuria↗ and Central Asia↗.

In North Korea, Korea as a whole is referred to as Chosŏn/Joseon, (Korean: 조선, [tɕosʰʌn]) which is also the basis of the word for Korea as a whole in Japan↗ (朝鮮 (Chōsen)), China↗ (朝鮮 (Cháoxiǎn)), and Vietnam↗ (Triều Tiên). "Great Joseon↗" was the name of the kingdom ruled by the Joseon dynasty↗ from 1392 until their declaration of the short-lived Great Korean Empire↗ in 1897. King Taejo↗ had named them for the earlier Gojoseon↗ (고조선), who ruled northern Korea from its legendary prehistory↗ until their conquest in 108 BCE by China's Han Empire↗. The Go- in Gojoseon is the Hanja word 古 and simply means "ancient" or "old"; it is a modern usage to distinguish the ancient Joseon from the later dynasty. It is unclear whether Joseon was a transcription↗ of a native Korean name (OC↗ *↗T[r]awser, MC↗ Trjewsjen) or a partial translation into Chinese of the Korean capital Asadal↗ (아사달), whose meaning has been reconstructed as "Morning Land" or "Mountain".

History

Main article: History of Korea↗ For a timeline, see: Timeline of Korean history↗

Prehistory

Main article: Prehistoric Korea↗ The Korean Academy claimed ancient hominid fossils originating from about 100,000 BCE in the lava at a stone city site in Korea. Fluorescent and high-magnetic analyses indicate the volcanic fossils may be from as early as 300,000 BCE. The best preserved Korean pottery goes back to the Paleolithic↗ times around 10,000 BCE and the Neolithic↗ period begins around 6000 BCE.

Beginning around 300 BC, the Japonic↗-speaking Yayoi people↗ from the Korean Peninsula entered the Japanese islands and displaced or intermingled with the original Jōmon↗ inhabitants. The linguistic homeland of Proto-Koreans↗ is located somewhere in Southern Siberia / Manchuria, such as the Liao river↗ area or the Amur region. Proto-Koreans arrived in the southern part of the Korean Peninsula at around 300 BC, replacing and assimilating Japonic-speakers and likely causing the Yayoi↗ migration.

Gojoseon

Main article: Gojoseon↗ According to Korean legend, Dangun↗, a descendant of Heaven↗, established Gojoseon↗ in 2333 BCE. In 108 BCE, the Han dynasty↗ defeated Gojoseon and installed four commanderies↗ in the northern Korean peninsula. Three of the commanderies fell or retreated westward within a few decades, but the Lelang Commandery↗ remained as a center of cultural and economic exchange with successive Chinese dynasties for four centuries. By 313, Goguryeo↗ annexed all of the Chinese commanderies.

Proto–Three Kingdoms

Main article: Proto–Three Kingdoms of Korea↗

The Proto–Three Kingdoms period, sometimes called the Multiple States Period, is the earlier part of what is commonly called the Three Kingdoms Period↗, following the fall of Gojoseon↗ but before Goguryeo↗, Baekje↗, and Silla↗ fully developed into kingdoms.

This time period saw numerous states spring up from the former territories of Gojoseon, which encompassed northern Korea and southern Manchuria↗. With the fall of Gojoseon, southern Korea entered the Samhan↗ period.

Located in the southern part of Korea, Samhan referred to the three confederacies of Mahan↗, Jinhan↗, and Byeonhan↗. Mahan was the largest and consisted of 54 states. Byeonhan↗ and Jinhan↗ both consisted of twelve states, bringing a total of 78 states within the Samhan↗. These three confederacies eventually developed into Baekje↗, Silla↗, and Gaya↗.

Three Kingdoms

Main articles: Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, Baekje↗, Goguryeo↗, and Silla↗

The Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ consisted of Goguryeo↗, Silla↗, and Baekje↗. Silla and Baekje controlled the southern half of the Korean Peninsula↗, maintaining the former Samhan↗ territories, while Goguryeo controlled the northern half of the Korean Peninsula, Manchuria and the Liaodong Peninsula↗, uniting Buyeo↗, Okjeo↗, Dongye↗ and other states in the former Gojoseon↗ territories.

Goguryeo↗ was a highly militaristic state, and a large empire in East Asia, reaching its zenith in the 5th century when its territories expanded to encompass most of Manchuria to the north, parts of Inner Mongolia↗ to the west, parts of Russia to the east, and the Seoul region to the south. Goguryeo experienced a golden age under Gwanggaeto the Great↗ and his son Jangsu↗, who both subdued Baekje and Silla during their times, achieving a brief unification of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗ and becoming the most dominant power on the Korean Peninsula. In addition to contesting for control of the Korean Peninsula, Goguryeo had many military conflicts↗ with various Chinese dynasties, most notably the Goguryeo–Sui War↗, in which Goguryeo defeated a huge force said to number over a million men. In 642, the powerful general Yŏn Kaesomun↗ led a coup and gained complete control over Goguryeo. In response, Emperor Tang Taizong↗ of China led a campaign against Goguryeo↗, in which the Gorguryeo forces were decimated by the Tang at the Battle of Mount Jupil↗. Taizong was later defeated at the Battle of Ansi↗ and withdrew his forces from Goguryeo. After the death of Tang Taizong, his son Emperor Tang Gaozong↗ allied with the Korean kingdom of Silla and invaded Goguryeo again, but were forced to withdraw in 662. However, Yŏn Kaesomun died of a natural cause in 666 and Goguryeo was thrown into chaos and weakened by a succession struggle among his sons and younger brother, with his eldest son defecting to Tang↗ and his younger brother defecting to Silla. The Tang-Silla alliance conquered Goguryeo in 668. After the collapse of Goguryeo, Tang and Silla ended their alliance and fought over control of the Korean Peninsula. Silla succeeded in gaining control over most of the Korean Peninsula, while Tang gained control over Goguryeo's northern territories. However, 30 years after the fall of Goguryeo, a Goguryeo general by the name of Dae Joyeong↗ founded the Korean-Mohe state of Balhae↗ and successfully expelled the Tang presence from much of the former Goguryeo territories.

The southwestern Korean kingdom of Baekje↗ was founded around modern-day Seoul↗ by a Goguryeo prince↗, a son of the founder of Goguryeo↗. Baekje absorbed all of the Mahan↗ states and subjugated most of the western Korean peninsula (including the modern provinces of Gyeonggi↗, Chungcheong↗, and Jeolla↗, as well as parts of Hwanghae↗ and Gangwon↗) to a centralised government; during the expansion of its territory, Baekje acquired Chinese culture and technology through maritime contacts with the Southern Dynasties↗. Baekje was a great maritime power; its nautical skill, which made it the Phoenicia↗ of East Asia, was instrumental in the dissemination of Buddhism throughout East Asia and continental culture to Japan. Historic evidence suggests that Japanese culture, art, and language were influenced by the kingdom of Baekje and Korea itself; Baekje also played an important role in transmitting advanced Chinese culture to the Japanese archipelago. Baekje was once a great military power on the Korean Peninsula, most notably in the 4th century during the rule of Geunchogo↗ when its influence extended across the sea to Liaoxi↗ and Shandong↗ in China, taking advantage of the weakened state of Former Qin↗, and Kyushu↗ in the Japanese archipelago; however, Baekje was critically defeated by Gwanggaeto the Great and declined.

Although later records claim that Silla↗ was the oldest of the Three Kingdoms of Korea↗, it is now believed to have been the last kingdom to develop. By the 2nd century, Silla existed as a large state in the southeast, occupying and influencing its neighbouring city-states. In 562, Silla annexed the Gaya confederacy↗, which was located between Baekje and Silla. The Three Kingdoms of Korea often warred with each other and Silla was often dominated by Baekje and Goguryeo. Silla was the smallest and weakest of the three, but it used cunning diplomatic means to make opportunistic pacts and alliances with the more powerful Korean kingdoms, and eventually Tang China, to its great advantage. In 660, King Muyeol↗ ordered his armies to attack Baekje↗. General Kim Yu-shin↗, aided by Tang↗ forces, conquered Baekje after defeating General Gyebaek↗ at the Battle of Hwangsanbeol↗. In 661, Silla and Tang attacked Goguryeo but were repelled. King Munmu↗, son of Muyeol and nephew of General Kim Yu-shin, launched another campaign in 667 and Goguryeo fell in the following year.

North–South States Period

Main articles: North–South States Period↗, Later Silla↗, and Balhae↗ Beginning in the 6th century, Silla↗'s power gradually extended across the Korean Peninsula. Silla first annexed the adjacent Gaya confederacy↗ in 562. By the 640s, Silla formed an alliance with the Tang dynasty↗ of China to conquer Baekje↗ and later Goguryeo↗. After conquering Baekje and Goguryeo, Silla repulsed Tang China from the Korean peninsula in 676. Even though Silla unified most of the Korean Peninsula, most of the Goguryeo territories to the north of the Korean Peninsula were ruled by Balhae↗. Former Goguryeo general or chief of Sumo Mohe Dae Jo-yeong↗ led a group of Goguryeo and Mohe↗ refugees to the Jilin↗ and founded the kingdom of Balhae↗, 30 years after the collapse of Goguryeo, as the successor to Goguryeo. At its height, Balhae's territories extended from southern Manchuria↗ down to the northern Korean peninsula. Balhae was called the "Prosperous Country in the East".

Later Silla↗ carried on the maritime prowess of Baekje↗, which acted like the Phoenicia↗ of medieval East Asia↗, and during the 8th and 9th centuries dominated the seas of East Asia and the trade between China, Korea and Japan, most notably during the time of Chang Pogo↗; in addition, Silla people made overseas communities in China on the Shandong Peninsula↗ and the mouth of the Yangtze River↗. Later Silla was a prosperous and wealthy country, and its metropolitan capital of Gyeongju↗ was the fourth largest city in the world. Later Silla experienced a golden age of art and culture, as evidenced by the Hwangnyongsa↗, Seokguram↗, and Emille Bell↗. Buddhism flourished during this time, and many Korean Buddhists gained great fame among Chinese Buddhists and contributed to Chinese Buddhism, including: Woncheuk↗, Wonhyo↗, Uisang↗, Musang↗, and Kim Gyo-gak↗, a Silla prince whose influence made Mount Jiuhua↗ one of the Four Sacred Mountains↗ of Chinese Buddhism.

Later Silla fell apart in the late 9th century, giving way to the tumultuous Later Three Kingdoms period↗ (892–935), and Balhae was destroyed by the Khitan↗s in 926. Goryeo↗ unified the Later Three Kingdoms and received the last crown prince↗ and much of the ruling class of Balhae, thus bringing about a unification of the two successor nations of Goguryeo↗.

Goryeo dynasty

Main article: Goryeo↗ Goryeo↗ was founded in 918 and replaced Silla as the ruling dynasty of Korea. Goryeo's land was at first what is now South Korea and about 1/3 of North Korea, but later on managed to recover most of the Korean peninsula. Momentarily, Goryeo advanced to parts of Jiandao↗ while conquering the Jurchens↗, but returned the territories due to the harsh climate and difficulties in defending them. The name "Goryeo" (高麗) is a short form of "Goguryeo↗" (高句麗) and was first used during the time of King Jangsu↗. Goryeo regarded itself as the successor of Goguryeo, hence its name and efforts to recover the former territories of Goguryeo. Wang Geon↗, the founder of Goryeo, was of Goguryeo descent and traced his ancestry to a noble Goguryeo clan. He made Kaesong↗, his hometown, the capital.

During this period, laws were codified and a civil service system was introduced. Buddhism↗ flourished and spread throughout the peninsula. The development of celadon↗ industries flourished in the 12th and 13th centuries. The publication of the Tripitaka Koreana↗ onto more than 80,000 wooden blocks and the invention of the world's first metal movable type↗ in the 13th century attest to Goryeo's cultural achievements.

Goryeo had to defend frequently against attacks by nomadic empires, especially the Khitans↗ and the Mongols↗. Goryeo had a hostile relationship with the Khitans, because the Khitan Empire↗ had destroyed Balhae↗, also a successor state of Goguryeo. In 993, the Khitans, who had established the Liao dynasty↗ in 907, invaded Goryeo↗, demanding that it make amity with them. Goryeo sent the diplomat Sŏ Hŭi↗ to negotiate, who successfully persuaded the Khitans to let Goryeo expand to the banks of the Amnok (Yalu) River↗, citing that in the past the land belonged to Goguryeo, the predecessor of Goryeo. During the Goryeo–Khitan War↗, the Khitan Empire invaded Korea twice more in 1009↗ and 1018↗, but was defeated.

After defeating the Khitan Empire, which was the most powerful empire of its time, Goryeo experienced a golden age that lasted a century, during which the Tripitaka Koreana↗ was completed, and there were great developments in printing and publishing, promoting learning and dispersing knowledge on philosophy, literature, religion, and science; by 1100, there were 12 universities that produced famous scholars and scientists.

Goryeo was invaded by the Mongols↗ in seven major campaigns from the 1230s until the 1270s, but was never conquered. Exhausted after decades of fighting, Goryeo sent its crown prince↗ to the Yuan↗ capital to swear allegiance to the Mongols; Kublai Khan↗ accepted, and married one of his daughters to the Korean crown prince, and the dynastic line of Goryeo continued to survive under the overlordship↗ of the Mongol Yuan dynasty as a semi-autonomous vassal state and compulsory ally. The two nations became intertwined for 80 years as all subsequent Korean kings married Mongol princesses, and the last empress↗ of the Yuan dynasty was a Korean princess.

In the 1350s, King Gongmin↗ was free at last to reform the Goryeo government when the Yuan dynasty began to crumble. Gongmin had various problems that needed to be dealt with, which included the removal of pro-Mongol aristocrats and military officials, the question of land holding, and quelling the growing animosity between the Buddhists and Confucian↗ scholars. During this tumultuous period, Goryeo momentarily conquered Liaoyang↗ in 1356, repulsed two large invasions by the Red Turbans↗ in 1359 and 1360, and defeated the final attempt by the Yuan to dominate Goryeo when General Ch'oe Yŏng↗ defeated a Mongol tumen↗ in 1364. During the 1380s, Goryeo turned its attention to the Wokou↗ threat and used naval artillery↗ created by Ch'oe Mu-sŏn↗ to annihilate hundreds of pirate ships.

Joseon dynasty

Main article: Joseon↗

In 1392, the general Yi Seong-gye↗ overthrew the Goryeo↗ dynasty after he staged a coup and defeated General Ch'oe Yŏng↗. Yi Seong-gye named his new dynasty Joseon↗ and moved the capital from Kaesong↗ to Hanseong↗ (formerly Hanyang; modern-day Seoul↗) and built the Gyeongbokgung↗ palace. In 1394, he adopted Confucianism↗ as the country's official ideology, resulting in much loss of power and wealth by the Buddhists↗. The prevailing philosophy of the Joseon dynasty was Neo-Confucianism↗, which was epitomized by the seonbi↗ class, scholars who passed up positions of wealth and power to lead lives of study and integrity.

Joseon was a nominal tributary state of China↗ but exercised full sovereignty, and maintained the highest position among China's tributary states, which also included countries such as the Ryukyu Kingdom↗, Vietnam, Burma, Brunei, Laos, Thailand, and the Philippines, among others. In addition, Joseon received tribute from Jurchens and Japanese until the 17th century, and had a small enclave in the Ryukyu Kingdom that engaged in trade with Siam and Java.

During the 15th and 16th centuries, Joseon enjoyed many benevolent rulers who promoted education and science. Most notable among them was Sejong the Great↗ (r. 1418–50), who personally created and promulgated Hangul↗, the Korean alphabet. This golden age saw great cultural and scientific advancements, including in printing, meteorological observation↗, astronomy, calendar science, ceramics↗, military technology, geography, cartography, medicine, and agricultural technology, some of which were unrivaled elsewhere. Joseon implemented a class system that consisted of yangban↗ the noble class, jungin the middle class, yangin the common class, and cheonin the lowest class, which included occupations such as butchers, tanners, shamans, entertainers, and nobi↗, the equivalent of slaves, bondservants, or serfs↗.

In 1592 and again in 1597, the Japanese invaded Korea↗; the Korean military at the time was unprepared and untrained, due to two centuries of peace on the Korean Peninsula↗. Toyotomi Hideyoshi↗ intended to conquer China and India through the Korean Peninsula, but was defeated by strong resistance from the Righteous Army↗, the naval superiority of Admiral Yi Sun-sin↗ and his turtle ship↗s, and assistance from Wanli Emperor↗ of Ming China↗. However, Joseon experienced great destruction, including a tremendous loss of cultural sites such as temples and palaces to Japanese pillaging, and the Japanese brought back to Japan an estimated 100,000–200,000 noses↗ cut from Korean victims. Less than 30 years after the Japanese invasions, the Manchus↗ took advantage of Joseon's war-weakened state and invaded↗ in 1627 and 1637, and then went on to conquer↗ the destabilized Ming dynasty.

After normalising relations with the new Qing dynasty↗, Joseon experienced a nearly 200-year period of peace. Kings Yeongjo↗ and Jeongjo↗ led a new renaissance of the Joseon dynasty during the 18th century.

In the 19th century, the royal in-law families gained control of the government, leading to mass corruption and weakening of the state, with severe poverty and peasant rebellions spreading throughout the country. Furthermore, the Joseon government adopted a strict isolationist policy, earning the nickname "the hermit kingdom↗", but ultimately failed to protect itself against imperialism↗ and was forced to open its borders, beginning an era leading into Japanese imperial rule↗.

Korean Empire

Main article: Korean Empire↗

Beginning in 1871, Japan↗ began to exert more influence in Korea, forcing it out of China's traditional sphere of influence. As a result of the First Sino-Japanese War↗ (1894–95), the Qing dynasty↗ had to give up such a position according to Article 1 of the Treaty of Shimonoseki↗, which was concluded between China and Japan in 1895. That same year, Empress Myeongseong↗ of Korea was assassinated by Japanese agents.

In 1897, the Joseon dynasty↗ proclaimed the Korean Empire↗ (1897–1910). King Gojong↗ became emperor. During this brief period, Korea had some success in modernising the military, economy, real property laws, education system, and various industries. Russia↗, Japan, France↗, and the United States all invested in the country and sought to influence it politically.

The Russians were pushed out of the fight for Korea following the conclusion of the Russo-Japanese War↗ (1904–1905). Korea became a protectorate↗ of Japan shortly afterwards. In Manchuria↗ on 26 October 1909, An Jung-geun↗ assassinated the former Resident-General of Korea↗, Itō Hirobumi↗, for his role in trying to force Korea into occupation.

Japanese annexation and occupation of Korea

Main article: Korea under Japanese rule↗ See also: Japanese war crimes↗

In 1910, an already militarily occupied Korea was a forced party to the Japan–Korea Annexation Treaty↗. The treaty was signed by Lee Wan-Yong↗, who was given the General Power of Attorney by the Emperor. However, the Emperor is said to have not actually ratified the treaty according to Yi Tae-jin. There is a long dispute whether this treaty was legal or illegal due to its signing under duress, threat of force and bribes.

Korean resistance to the brutal Japanese occupation was manifested in the nonviolent March First Movement↗ of 1919, during which 7,000 demonstrators were killed by Japanese police and military. The Korean liberation movement↗ also spread to neighbouring Manchuria↗ and Siberia↗.

Over five million Koreans were conscripted for labour beginning in 1939, and tens of thousands of men were forced into Japan's military. Nearly 400,000 Korean labourers died. Approximately 200,000 girls and women, mostly from China and Korea, were forced into sexual slavery for the Japanese military. In 1993, Japanese Chief Cabinet Secretary Yohei Kono↗ acknowledged the terrible injustices faced by these euphemistically named "comfort women↗".

During the Japanese annexation, the Korean language was suppressed in an effort to eradicate indigenous Korean national identity. Koreans were forced to take Japanese surnames, known as Sōshi-kaimei↗. Traditional Korean culture↗ suffered heavy losses, as numerous Korean cultural artefacts were destroyed or taken to Japan. One such artefact is rumored to be a sacred Korean mask (tal)↗, still up on display in a Japanese museum. To this day, valuable Korean artefacts can often be found in Japanese museums or among private collections. One investigation by the South Korean government identified 75,311 cultural assets that were taken from Korea, 34,369 in Japan and 17,803 in the United States. However, experts estimate that over 100,000 artefacts actually remain in Japan. Japanese officials considered returning Korean cultural properties, but to date this has not occurred. Both Koreas and Japan still dispute the ownership of the Dokdo↗ islets, located east of the Korean Peninsula.

There was significant emigration to the overseas territories of the Empire of Japan↗ during the Japanese occupation period, including Korea↗. By the end of World War II, there were over 850,000 Japanese settlers in Korea. After World War II, most of these overseas Japanese↗ repatriated to Japan. Migrants who remained squatted↗ in informal settlements↗.

Division and conflict

Main article: Division of Korea↗

In 1945, with the surrender of Japan↗, the United Nations↗ developed plans for a trusteeship administration, the Soviet Union↗ administering the peninsula north of the 38th parallel↗ and the United States↗ administering the south↗. The politics of the Cold War↗ resulted in the 1948 establishment of two separate governments, North Korea and South Korea.

The aftermath of World War II left Korea partitioned along the 38th parallel on 2 September 1945, with the north under Soviet occupation and the south under US occupation supported by other allied states. Consequently, North Korea, a Soviet-style socialist republic was established in the north, and South Korea, a Western-style regime, was established in the south↗.

North Korea is a one-party state↗ ruled by the Workers' Party of Korea↗, now centred on Kim Il Sung↗'s Juche↗ ideology, with a centrally planned↗ industrial economy. South Korea is a multi-party state↗ with a capitalist↗ market economy↗, alongside membership in the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development and the Group of Twenty↗. The two states have greatly diverged both culturally and economically since their partition, though they still share a common traditional culture and pre-Cold War history.

Since the 1960s, the South Korean economy has grown enormously and the economic structure was radically transformed. In 1957, South Korea had a lower per capita GDP↗ than Ghana↗, and by 2008 it was 17 times as high as Ghana's.

According to R. J. Rummel↗, forced labour↗, executions, and concentration camps were responsible for over one million deaths in North Korea from 1948 to 1987; others have estimated 400,000 deaths in concentration camps alone. Estimates based on the most recent North Korean census suggest that 240,000 to 420,000 people died as a result of the 1990s famine↗ and that there were 600,000 to 850,000 unnatural deaths in North Korea from 1993 to 2008. In South Korea, as guerrilla activities expanded, the South Korean government used strong measures against peasants, such as forcefully moving their families from guerrilla areas. According to one estimate, these measures resulted in 36,000 people killed, 11,000 people wounded, and 432,000 people displaced.

Korean War

Main article: Korean War↗ The Korean War broke out when Soviet-backed North Korea invaded South Korea. Despite massive swings in territorial gain back and forth, in the end neither side gained much territory as a result. The Korean Peninsula remained divided, the Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ being the de facto border between the two states.

In June 1950 North Korea invaded the South, using Soviet tanks and weaponry. During the Korean War↗ (1950–53) more than 1.2 million people died and the three years of fighting throughout the nation effectively destroyed most cities. The war ended with an armistice agreement↗ at approximately the Military Demarcation Line↗, but the two governments are officially still at war.

North and South Korea

See also: History of North Korea↗, History of South Korea↗, Korean conflict↗, and Korean reunification↗

In 2018, the leaders of North Korea and South Korea officially signed the Panmunjom Declaration↗, announcing that they will work to end the conflict.

In November 2020, South Korea and China agreed to work together to mend South Korea's relationship with North Korea. During a meeting between President Moon↗ and China's foreign minister, Wang Yi↗, Moon expressed his gratitude to China for its role in helping to foster peace in the Korean Peninsula. Moon was quoted telling Wang during their meeting that "[the South Korean] government will not stop efforts to put an end (formally) to war on the Korean Peninsula and achieve complete denuclearization and permanent peace together with the international community, including China."

Geography

Main article: Geography of Korea↗ See also: Geography of North Korea↗, Geography of South Korea↗, and Provinces of Korea↗

Korea consists of a peninsula↗ and nearby islands located in East Asia↗. The peninsula extends southwards for about 1,100 km (684 mi) from continental Asia↗ into the Pacific Ocean↗ and is surrounded by the Sea of Japan↗ to the east and the Yellow Sea↗ (West Sea) to the west, the Korea Strait↗ connecting the two bodies of water. To the northwest, the Amnok River↗ separates Korea from China and to the northeast, the Duman River↗ separates it from China and Russia. Notable islands include Jeju Island↗, Ulleung Island↗, Dokdo↗.

The southern and western parts of the peninsula have well-developed plains, while the eastern and northern parts are mountainous. The highest mountain in Korea is Mount Paektu↗ (2,744 m), through which runs the border with China. The southern extension of Mount Paektu is a highland called Gaema Heights↗. This highland was mainly raised during the Cenozoic↗ orogeny↗ and partly covered by volcanic matter. To the south of Gaema Gowon, successive high mountains are located along the eastern coast of the peninsula. This mountain range is named Baekdu-daegan↗. Some significant mountains include Sobaeksan↗ (1,439 m), Mount Kumgang↗ (1,638 m), Seoraksan↗ (1,708 m), Taebaeksan↗ (1,567 m), and Jirisan↗ (1,915 m). There are several lower, secondary mountain series whose direction is almost perpendicular to that of Baekdu-daegan. They are developed along the tectonic line of Mesozoic↗ orogeny and their directions are basically northwest.

Unlike most ancient mountains on the mainland, many important islands in Korea were formed by volcanic activity in the Cenozoic orogeny. Jeju Island, situated off the southern coast, is a large volcanic island whose main mountain, Mount Halla↗ or Hallasan (1,950 m), is the highest in South Korea. Ulleung Island is a volcanic island in the Sea of Japan, the composition of which is more felsic↗ than Jeju. The volcanic islands tend to be younger, the more westward.

Because the mountainous region is mostly on the eastern part of the peninsula, the main rivers↗ tend to flow westwards. Two exceptions are the southward-flowing Nakdong River↗ and Seomjin River↗. Important rivers running westward include the Amnok River, the Chongchon River↗, the Taedong River↗, the Han River↗, the Geum River↗, and the Yeongsan River↗. These rivers have vast flood plains and provide an ideal environment for wet-rice↗ cultivation.

The southern and southwestern coastlines of the peninsula form a well-developed ria↗ coastline, known as Dadohae-jin in Korean. This convoluted coastline provides mild seas, and the resulting calm environment allows for safe navigation, fishing, and seaweed farming↗. In addition to the complex coastline, the western coast of the Korean Peninsula has an extremely high tidal amplitude↗ (at Incheon↗, around the middle of the western coast, the tide can get as high as 9 m). Vast tidal flats have been developing on the south and west coastlines.

Climate

Korea has a temperate climate with comparatively fewer typhoons↗ than other countries in East Asia. Due to the peninsula's position, it has a unique climate influenced by Siberia in the north, the Pacific Ocean in the east and the rest of Eurasia in the west. The peninsula has four distinct seasons: spring, summer, autumn and winter.

Spring

As influence from Siberia weakens, temperatures begin to increase while the high pressure begins to move away. If the weather is abnormally dry, Siberia will have more influence on the peninsula leading to wintry weather such as snow.

Summer

During June at the start of the summer, there tends to be a lot of rain due to the cold and wet air from the Sea of Okhotsk↗ and the hot and humid air from the Pacific Ocean combining. When these fronts combine, it leads to a so-called rainy season with often cloudy days with rain, which is sometimes very heavy. The hot and humid winds from the south west blow causing an increasing amount of humidity and this leads to the fronts moving towards Manchuria↗ in China and thus there is less rain and this is known as midsummer; temperatures can exceed 30 °C (86 °F) daily at this time of year.

Autumn

Usually, high pressure is heavily dominant during autumn leading to clear conditions. Furthermore, temperatures remain high but the humidity becomes relatively low.

Winter

The weather becomes increasingly dominated by Siberia during winter and the jet stream moves further south causing a drop in temperature. This season is relatively dry with some snow falling at times.

Biodiversity

Main article: Wildlife of Korea↗ Animal life of the Korean Peninsula includes a considerable number of bird species and native freshwater fish↗. Native or endemic↗ species of the Korean Peninsula include Korean hare↗, Korean water deer↗, Korean field mouse↗, Korean brown frog↗, Korean pine↗ and Korean spruce↗. The Korean Demilitarized Zone↗ (DMZ) with its forest and natural wetlands↗ is a unique biodiversity spot, which harbours eighty-two endangered species↗. Korea once hosted many Siberian tigers↗, but as the number of people affected by the tigers increased, the tigers were killed in the Joseon dynasty and the Siberian tigers in the South Korea became extinct during the Japanese colonial era period. It has been confirmed that Siberian tigers are only on the side of North Korea now.

There are also approximately 3,034 species of vascular plants↗ throughout the peninsula.

Economy

Science and technology

Main article: History of science and technology in Korea↗ See also: List of Korean inventions and discoveries↗

One of the best known artefacts of Korea's history of science and technology is the Cheomseongdae↗, a 9.4-meter high astronomical observatory↗ built in 634 CE.

The earliest known surviving Korean example of woodblock printing is The Great Dharani Sutra↗. It is believed to have been printed in Korea in 750–51 CE, which if correct, would make it older than the Diamond Sutra↗.

During the Goryeo↗ period, metal movable type↗ printing was invented by Ch'oe Yun-ŭi↗ in 1234 CE. This invention made printing easier, more efficient and also increased literacy, which observed by Chinese visitors was seen to be so important where it was considered to be shameful to not be able to read. The Mongol Empire↗ later adopted Korea's movable type printing and spread as far as Central Asia. There is conjecture as to whether or not Ch'oe's invention had any influence on later printing inventions such as Gutenberg's Printing press↗. When the Mongols↗ invaded Europe↗ they inadvertently introduced different kinds of Asian technology.

During the Joseon period, the Turtle Ship↗ was invented, which were covered by a wooden deck and iron with thorns, as well as other weapons such as the bigyeokjincheolloe cannon↗ (비격진천뢰, 飛擊震天雷) and the hwacha↗.

The Korean alphabet hangul↗ was also invented during this time by King Sejong the Great↗.

Demographics

Main articles: Koreans↗, Demographics of South Korea↗, and Demographics of North Korea↗ As of 2023, the combined population of the Koreas is about 77.9 million (South Korea: 51.7 million, North Korea: 26.1 million). Korea is chiefly populated by a highly homogeneous↗ ethnic↗ group, the Koreans↗, who speak the Korean language↗. The number of foreigners living in Korea has also steadily increased since the late 20th century, particularly in South Korea, where more than 1 million foreigners reside. It was estimated in 2006 that only 26,700 of the old Chinese community↗ now remain in South Korea. However, in recent years, immigration from mainland China has increased; 624,994 persons of Chinese↗ nationality have immigrated to South Korea, including 443,566 of ethnic Korean↗ descent. Small communities of ethnic Chinese and Japanese↗ are also found in North Korea.

Largest cities in Korea:

Seoul↗ (Seoul, population 9,904,312)
Busan↗ (Busan, population 3,448,737)
Pyongyang↗ (Pyongyang, population 3,255,288)
Incheon↗ (Incheon, population 2,890,451)
Daegu↗ (Daegu, population 2,446,052)
Daejeon↗ (Daejeon, population 1,538,394)
Gwangju↗ (Gwangju, population 1,502,881)
Suwon↗ (Gyeonggi, population 1,194,313)
Ulsan↗ (Ulsan, population 1,166,615)
Changwon↗ (South Gyeongsang, population 1,059,241)
Goyang↗ (Gyeonggi, population 990,073)
Yongin↗ (Gyeonggi, population 971,327)
Seongnam↗ (Gyeonggi, population 948,757)
Bucheon↗ (Gyeonggi, population 843,794)
Cheongju↗ (North Chungcheong, population 833,276)
Hamhung↗ (South Hamgyong, population 768,551)
Ansan↗ (Gyeonggi, population 747,035)
Chongjin↗ (North Hamgyong, population 667,929)
Jeonju↗ (North Jeolla, population 658,172)
Cheonan↗ (South Chungcheong, population 629,062)

Language

Main articles: Korean language↗ and Korean Sign Language↗

Korean↗ is the official language of both North and South Korea, and (along with Mandarin) of Yanbian Korean Autonomous Prefecture↗ in Jilin Province↗, China↗. Worldwide, there are up to 80 million speakers of the Korean language. South Korea has around 50 million speakers while North Korea around 25 million. Other large groups of Korean speakers through Korean diaspora↗ are found in China↗, the United States↗, Japan↗, former Soviet Union↗ and elsewhere.

Modern Korean is written almost exclusively in the script of the Korean alphabet↗ (known as Hangul in South Korea and Chosungul in China and North Korea), which was invented in the 15th century. Korean is sometimes written with the addition of some Chinese characters called Hanja; however, this is only occasionally seen nowadays.

Religion

Main articles: Religion in Korea↗, Religion in South Korea↗, and Religion in North Korea↗ See also: Korean shamanism↗, Korean Confucianism↗, Korean Buddhism↗, Taoism in Korea↗, Christianity in Korea↗, and Islam in Korea↗

Confucian↗ tradition has dominated Korean thought, along with contributions by Buddhism↗, Taoism↗, and Korean Shamanism↗. Since the middle of the 20th century, however, Christianity↗ has competed with Buddhism in South Korea, while religious practice has been suppressed in North Korea. Throughout Korean history and culture, regardless of separation, the influence of traditional beliefs of Korean Shamanism, Mahayana Buddhism, Confucianism and Taoism have remained an underlying religion of the Korean people as well as a vital aspect of their culture; all these traditions have coexisted peacefully for hundreds of years up to today despite strong Westernisation from Christian missionary conversions in the South or the pressure from the Juche↗ government↗ in the North.

According to 2005 statistics from the South Korean government, about 46% of citizens profess no particular religion. Christians↗ account for 29.2% of the population (of which are Protestants 18.3% and Catholics 10.9%) and Buddhists↗ 22.8%. In North Korea, around 71.3% claim to be non-religious or atheists, 12.9% follow Cheondoism↗ and 12.3% Korean Folk Religion↗, while Christians account for 2% of the population and Buddhists 1.5%.

Islam in South Korea↗ is practised by about 45,000 natives (about 0.09% of the population) in addition to some 100,000 foreign workers from Muslim countries. While in North Korea it's estimated to be around 3000 Muslims, which is around 0.01% of the population. The Ar-Rahman Mosque↗ is the only mosque in DPRK, and it is located at the Iranian Embassy grounds in Pyongyyang.

In 1993, the Korean Overseas Culture and Information Service↗ estimated that around 1,600,000 people practice Korean new religions↗ in both Korean countries.

Education

Main articles: Education in South Korea↗ and Education in North Korea↗ The modern South Korean school system consists of six years in elementary school, three years in middle school, and three years in high school. Students are required to go to elementary and middle school, and do not have to pay for their education, except for a small fee called a "School Operation Support Fee" that differs from school to school. The Programme for International Student Assessment↗, coordinated by the OECD↗, ranks South Korea's science education as the third best in the world and being significantly higher than the OECD average.

Although South Korean students often rank high on international comparative assessments, the education system is criticized for emphasising too much upon passive learning and memorisation. The South Korean education system is rather notably strict and structured as compared to its counterparts in most Western societies.

The North Korean education system consists primarily of universal and state funded↗ schooling by the government↗. The national literacy rate for citizens 15 years of age and above is over 99 per cent. Children go through one year of kindergarten, four years of primary education↗, six years of secondary education↗, and then on to universities↗. The most prestigious university in the DPRK is Kim Il Sung University↗. Other notable universities include Kim Chaek University of Technology↗, which focuses on computer science, Pyongyang University of Foreign Studies↗, which trains working level diplomats and trade officials, and Kim Hyong Jik University of Education↗, which trains teachers.

Culture

Main articles: Culture of Korea↗, Korean art↗, Korean pottery and porcelain↗, Korean martial arts↗, Korean dance↗, Korean bow↗, and Korean architecture↗

In ancient Chinese texts, Korea is referred to as "Rivers and Mountains Embroidered on Silk" (Korean: 금수강산 / Hanja: 錦繡江山) and "Eastern Nation of Decorum" (Korean: 동방예의지국 / Hanja: 東方禮儀之國). Individuals are regarded as one year old when they are born, as Koreans reckon the pregnancy period as one year of life for infants, and age increments increase on New Year's Day↗ rather than on the anniversary of birthdays. Thus, one born immediately before New Year's Day may only be a few days old in western reckoning, but two years old in Korea. Accordingly, a Korean person's stated age (at least among fellow Koreans) will be one or two years more than their age according to western reckoning. However, western reckoning is sometimes applied with regard to the concept of legal age↗; for example, the legal age for purchasing alcohol↗ or cigarettes↗ in the Republic of Korea is 19, which is measured according to western reckoning.

Literature

Excerpt from: Korean literature↗

Music

Main article: Traditional music of Korea↗ Traditional Korean music includes combinations of the folk, vocal, religious and ritual↗ music styles of the Korean people↗. Korean music has been practised since prehistoric times. Korean music falls into two broad categories. The first, Hyangak↗, literally means The local music or Music native to Korea, a famous example of which is Sujechon, a piece of instrumental music often claimed to be at least 1,300 years old. The second, yangak, represents a more Western style.

Cuisine

Main article: Korean cuisine↗ See also: Korean tea ceremony↗ and Korean royal court cuisine↗

Koreans traditionally believe that the taste and quality of food depend on its spices and sauces, the essential ingredients to making a delicious meal. Therefore, soybean paste↗, soy sauce↗, gochujang↗ or red pepper paste and kimchi↗ are some of the most important staples in a Korean household.

Korean cuisine was greatly influenced by the geography and climate of the Korean Peninsula, which is known for its cold autumns and winters, therefore there are many fermented dishes and hot soups and stews.

Korean cuisine is probably best known for kimchi↗, a side dish which uses a distinctive fermentation↗ process of preserving vegetables, most commonly cabbage. Kimchi is said to relieve the pores on the skin, thereby reducing wrinkles and providing nutrients to the skin naturally. It is also healthy, as it provides necessary vitamins and nutrients. Gochujang, a traditional Korean sauce made of red pepper is also commonly used, often as pepper (chilli) paste, earning the cuisine a reputation for spiciness.

Bulgogi↗ (roasted marinated meat, usually beef), galbi↗ (marinated grilled short ribs), and samgyeopsal↗ (pork belly) are popular main courses. Fish is also a popular commodity, as it is the traditional meat that Koreans eat. Meals are usually accompanied by a soup or stew, such as galbitang↗ (stewed ribs) or doenjang jjigae↗ (fermented bean paste soup). The center of the table is filled with a shared collection of sidedishes called banchan↗.

Other popular dishes include bibimbap↗, which literally means "mixed rice" (rice mixed with meat, vegetables, and red pepper paste), and naengmyeon↗ (cold noodles).

Instant noodles, or ramyeon↗, is a popular snack food. Koreans also enjoy food from pojangmacha↗s (street vendors), which serve tteokbokki↗, rice cake and fish cake with a spicy gochujang sauce; gimbap↗, made of steamed white rice wrapped in dried green laver↗ seaweed; fried squid; and glazed sweet potato. Soondae↗, a sausage made of cellophane noodles and pork blood, is widely eaten.

Additionally, some other common snacks include "Choco Pie↗", shrimp crackers, "bbeongtwigi" (puffed rice grains), and "nurungji" (slightly burnt rice). Nurungji can be eaten as it is or boiled with water to make a soup. Nurungji can also be eaten as a snack or a dessert.

Korea is unique among Asian countries in its use of metal chopsticks. Metal chopsticks have been discovered in archaeological sites belonging to the ancient Korean kingdoms of Goguryeo, Baekje and Silla.

Sports

Main articles: Sport in South Korea↗ and Sport in North Korea↗ North Korea and South Korea usually compete as two separate nations in international events. There are, however, a few examples of them having competed as one entity↗, under the name Korea.

While association football↗ remains one of the most popular sports in South Korea, the martial art of taekwondo↗ is considered to be the national sport. Baseball↗ and golf↗ are also popular. The board game Go↗, known in Korea as baduk, has also been popular for over a millennium, first arriving from China in the 5th century CE; baduk is played both casually and competitively.

Martial arts

Taekwon-Do

Main article: Taekwondo↗ Taekwon-Do is Korea's most famous martial art and sport. It combines combat techniques, self-defence, sport and exercise. Taekwon-Do has become an official Olympic sport, starting as a demonstration event in 1988↗ (when South Korea hosted the Games in Seoul) and becoming an official medal event in 2000.↗ The two major Taekwon-Do federations, the International Taekwon-Do Federation↗ and the World Taekwondo Federation↗, were founded in Korea.

Hapkido

Main article: Hapkido↗ Hapkido is a modern Korean martial art↗ with a grappling focus that employs joint locks, throws, kicks, punches and other striking attacks like attacks against pressure points. Hapkido emphasizes circular motion, non-resisting movements and control of the opponent. Practitioners seek to gain advantage through footwork and body positioning to employ leverage, avoiding the pure use of strength against strength.

Ssireum

Main article: Ssireum↗ Ssireum is a traditional form of wrestling that has been practised in Korea for thousands of years, with evidence discovered from Goguryeo of Korea's Three Kingdoms Period (57 BCE to 688). Ssireum is the traditional national sport of Korea. During a match, opponents grip each other by sash belts wrapped around the waist and the thigh, attempting to throw their competitor to the sandy ground of the ring. The first opponent to touch the ground with any body part above the knee or to lose hold of their opponent loses the round.

Ssireum competitions are traditionally held twice a year, during the Dano Festival↗ (the 5th day of the fifth lunar month) and Chuseok↗ (the 15th day of the 8th lunar month). Competitions are also held throughout the year as a part of festivals and other events.

Taekkyon

Main article: Taekkyon↗ Taekkyon is a traditional martial art, considered the oldest form of fighting technique of Korea. Practiced for centuries and especially popular during the Joseon↗ period, two forms co-existed: one for practical use, the other for sport. This form was usually practised alongside Ssireum↗ during festivals and competitions between villages. Nonetheless, Taekkyon almost disappeared during the Japanese Occupation↗ and the Korean War↗.

Though lost in North Korea, Taekkyon has enjoyed a spectacular revival from the 1980s in South Korea. It is the only martial art in the world (with Ssireum) recognized as a National Treasure of South Korea↗ and a UNESCO Intangible Cultural Heritage↗.

See also

Inter-Korean summits↗
Korean name↗
Korean natural farming↗
Korean War↗
List of Korean inventions and discoveries↗
List of peninsulas↗
National Treasures of North Korea↗
National Treasures of South Korea↗
North Korea–South Korea relations↗
Korean reunification↗

Notes

References

Citations

Bae, Kidong. 2002 Radiocarbon Dates from Palaeolithic Sites in Korea. Radiocarbon 44(2): 473–476.
"ko:발해 유민 포섭"↗. 우리역사넷. National Institute of Korean History↗
"Korean". Oxford English Dictionary
"youtube on 'Korea? Corea?'"↗. YouTube↗. 12 January 2016
"Korea"↗. Encyclopaedia Britannica
Stephen G. Haw. Marco Polo's China: A Venetian in the Realm of Khubilai Khan. Routledge, 2006. p. 4–5. ISBN 9781134275427
Baxter, William & al. "Baxter–Sagart Old Chinese Reconstruction Archived on 27 September 2013↗", pp. 43, 58 & 80. 20 February 2011. Retrieved 20 December 2013.
Geoffrey Till and Patrick Bratton. Sea Power and the Asia-Pacific: The Triumph of Neptune?. Routledge, 2012. p. 145. ISBN 9781136627248
Yunn Seung-Yong. Religious culture in Korea. Hollym, 1996. p. 99. ISBN 9781565910843
"ko:디지털 삼국유사 사전, 박물지 시범개발"↗. 문화콘텐츠닷컴. Korea Creative Content Agency
이기환. [[official-url:http://news.khan.co.kr/kh_news/khan_art_view.html?artid=201708300913001&code=960100&www|"ko:[이기환의 흔적의 역사]국호논쟁의 전말 ... 대한민국이냐 고려공화국이냐"]]. Kyunghyang Shinmun↗. 30 August 2017
Deok-il Lee. [[official-url:http://news.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2008/08/14/2008081401512.html|"ko:[이덕일 사랑] 대~한민국"]]. The Chosun Ilbo↗
Jie Li. "Some Discoveries of Fossils and Relics of Prehistoric Civilizations From Around the World"↗. Pureinsight. 21 August 2002
Alexander Vovin↗. Origins of the Japanese Language. Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Linguistics. Oxford University Press, 2017. ISBN 978-0-19-938465-5
Juha Janhunen. "RReconstructing the Language Map of Prehistorical Northeast Asia". Studia Orientalia. 2010, no. 108
"Korea"↗. Asian info
Ki-baek Yi. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 23–24. ISBN 9780674615762
Hugh Dyson Walker. East Asia: A New History. AuthorHouse, 2012. p. 104. ISBN 9781477265161
John Morris Roberts and Odd Arne Westad. The History of the World. Oxford University Press, 2013. p. 443. ISBN 9780199936762
Hall Gardner. Averting Global War: Regional Challenges, Overextension, and Options for American Strategy. Palgrave Macmillan, 27 November 2007. p. 158–159. ISBN 9780230608733
Sigfried J. de Laet. History of Humanity: From the seventh to the sixteenth century. UNESCO, 1994. p. 1133. ISBN 9789231028137
Hugh Dyson Walker. East Asia: A New History. AuthorHouse, 20 November 2012. p. 6–7. ISBN 9781477265178
Daniel Tudor. Korea: The Impossible Country: The Impossible Country. Tuttle Publishing, 10 November 2012. ISBN 9781462910229
Stephen Kotkin and David Wolff. Rediscovering Russia in Asia: Siberia and the Russian Far East: Siberia and the Russian Far East. Routledge, 4 March 2015. ISBN 9781317461296
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Bloomington, Indiana: Indiana University Press, 2012. p. 35. ISBN 978-0253000781
Hyŏn-hŭi Yi, Sŏng-su Pak, and Nae-hyŏn Yun. New history of Korea. Jimoondang, 2005. p. 201. ISBN 9788988095850 "He launched a military expedition to expand his territory, opening the golden age of Goguryeo."
John Whitney Hall. The Cambridge History of Japan. Cambridge University Press, 1988. p. 362. ISBN 9780521223522
Ainslie Thomas Embree. Encyclopedia of Asian history. Scribner, 1988. p. 324. ISBN 9780684188997
Warren I. Cohen. East Asia at the Center: Four Thousand Years of Engagement with the World. Columbia University Press, 20 December 2000. p. 50. ISBN 9780231502511
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Indiana University Press, 5 November 2012. p. 35. ISBN 978-0253000781
"Kings and Queens of Korea"↗. KBS World Radio. Korea Communications Commission
Hugh Dyson Walker. East Asia: A New History. AuthorHouse, 20 November 2012. p. 161. ISBN 9781477265178
Matthew White. Atrocities: The 100 Deadliest Episodes in Human History. W. W. Norton & Company, 7 November 2011. p. 78. ISBN 9780393081923
Reg G. Grant. 1001 Battles That Changed the Course of World History. Universe Pub., 2011. p. 104. ISBN 9780789322333
Robert Bedeski. Human Security and the Chinese State: Historical Transformations and the Modern Quest for Sovereignty. Routledge, 12 March 2007. p. 90. ISBN 9781134125975
Ki-baek Yi. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 47. ISBN 9780674615762 "Koguryŏ was the first to open hostilities, with a bold assault across the Liao River against Liao-hsi, in 598. The Sui emperor, Wen Ti, launched a retaliatory attack on Koguryŏ but met with reverses and turned back in mid-course. Yang Ti, the next Sui emperor, proceeded in 612 to mount an invasion of unprecedented magnitude, marshalling a huge force said to number over a million men. And when his armies failed to take Liao-tung Fortress (modern Liao-yang), the anchor of Koguryŏ's first line of defense, he had a nearly a third of his forces, some 300,000 strong, break off the battle there and strike directly at the Koguryŏ capital of P'yŏngyang. But the Sui army was lured into a trap by the famed Koguryŏ commander Ŭlchi Mundŏk, and suffered a calamitous defeat at the Salsu (Ch'ŏngch'ŏn) River. It is said that only 2,700 of the 300,000 Sui soldiers who had crossed the Yalu survived to find their way back, and the Sui emperor now lifted the siege of Liao-tung Fortress and withdrew his forces to China proper. Yang Ti continued to send his armies against Koguryŏ but again without success, and before long his war-weakened empire crumbled."
Andrew C. Nahm. A Panorama of 5000 Years: Korean History. Seoul: Hollym International Corporation, 2005. Second revised ed. p. 18. ISBN 978-0930878689 "China, which had been split into many states since the early 3rd century, was reunified by the Sui dynasty at the end of the 6th century. Soon afterward, Sui China mobilized its army and invaded Koguryŏ. However, the people of Koguryŏ were united and able to repel the Chinese invasion. In 612, Sui troops invaded Korea again, but Koguryŏ forces fought bravely and destroyed Sui troops everywhere. General Ŭlchi Mundŏk of Koguryŏ completely wiped out some 300,000 Sui troops which came across the Yalu River in the battles near the Salsu River (now Ch'ŏngch'ŏn River) with his ingenious military tactics. Only 2,700 Sui troops were able to flee from Korea. The Sui dynasty, which wasted so much energy and manpower in aggressive wars against Koguryŏ, fell in 618."
Spencer C. Tucker. A Global Chronology of Conflict: From the Ancient World to the Modern Middle East [6 volumes: From the Ancient World to the Modern Middle East]. ABC-CLIO, 23 December 2009. p. 406. ISBN 9781851096725
Hugh Dyson Walker. East Asia: A New History. AuthorHouse, 20 November 2012. p. 161. ISBN 9781477265178
Trudy Ring, Noelle Watson, and Paul Schellinger. Asia and Oceania: International Dictionary of Historic Places. Routledge, 12 November 2012. p. 486. ISBN 9781136639791
Injae Lee, Owen Miller, Jinhoon Park, and Hyun-Hae Yi. Korean History in Maps. Cambridge University Press, 15 December 2014. p. 29. ISBN 9781107098466
Ki-baek Yi. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 67. ISBN 9780674615762
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea, 2nd Edition. ABC-CLIO, 30 May 2014. p. 49. ISBN 9781610695824
Chairman Department of East Asian Studies Keith Pratt, Keith Pratt, and Richard Rutt. Korea: A Historical and Cultural Dictionary. Routledge, 16 December 2013. p. 135. ISBN 9781136793936
Chai-Shin Yu. The New History of Korean Civilization. iUniverse, 2012. p. 27. ISBN 9781462055593
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Indiana University Press, 5 November 2012. p. 28. ISBN 978-0253000781
Patricia Buckley Ebrey, Anne Walthall, and James B. Palais. East Asia: A Cultural, Social, and Political History. Houghton Mifflin, 2006. p. 123. ISBN 9780618133840
Joseph Kitagawa. The Religious Traditions of Asia: Religion, History, and Culture. Routledge, 5 September 2013. p. 348. ISBN 9781136875908
Patricia Buckley Ebrey, Anne Walthall, and James B. Palais. East Asia: A Cultural, Social, and Political History, Volume I: To 1800. Cengage Learning, 2013. p. 104. ISBN 978-1111808150
William Elliot Griffis. Corea, Without and Within: Chapters on Corean History, Manners and Religion. Presbyterian Board of Publication, 1885. p. 251
Yayo. Metropolitan Museum of Art↗, October 2002
Ho Chon Chon. "Kitora Tomb Originates in Koguryo Murals". Choson Sinbo↗. no. 35
Yayoi. eMuseum. MNSU
"Japanese history: Jomon, Yayoi, Kofun"↗. Japan guide. 9 June 2002
"Asia Society: The Collection in Context"↗. Asia society museum
"Pottery – MSN Encarta" "The pottery of the Yayoi culture (c. 300 BCE – CE c. 250), made by a Mongol people who came from Korea to Kyūshū, has been found throughout Japan. "
"Kanji"↗. Japan guide. 25 November 2010
Seiroku Noma. The Arts of Japan: Late Medieval to Modern. Kodansha International, 2003. ISBN 978-4-7700-2978-2
"Japanese Art and Its Korean Secret"↗. Kenyon. 6 April 2003
"Japanese Royal Tomb Opened to Scholars for First Time"↗. National geographic. 28 October 2010
A Brief History of Korea. Ewha Womans University Press, 1 January 2005. p. 29–30. ISBN 9788973006199
Chai-Shin Yu. The New History of Korean Civilization. iUniverse, 2012. p. 27. ISBN 9781462055593
Jinwung Kim. A History of Korea: From "Land of the Morning Calm" to States in Conflict. Indiana University Press, 2012. p. 44–45. ISBN 978-0253000248
Kenneth M. Wells. Korea: Outline of a Civilisation. BRILL, 3 July 2015. p. 18–19. ISBN 9789004300057
Old records of Silla 新羅古記(Silla gogi↗ [ko]): ... 高麗舊將祚榮
Rhymed Chronicles of Sovereigns 帝王韻紀(Jewang ungi↗): ... 前麗舊將大祚榮
Solitary Cloud 孤雲集(Gounjib): ... 渤海之源流也句驪未滅之時本爲疣贅部落靺羯之屬寔繁有徒是名栗末小蕃甞逐句驪, 內徙其首領乞四羽及大祚榮等至武后臨朝之際自營州作孼而逃輒據荒丘始稱振國時有句驪遺燼勿吉雜流梟音則嘯聚白山鴟義則喧張黑姶與契丹濟惡旋於突厥通謀萬里耨苗累拒渡遼之轍十年食葚晚陳降漢之旗.
Solitary Cloud 孤雲集(Gounjip): ... 其酋長大祚榮, 始受臣藩第五品大阿餐之秩
Comprehensive Institutions 通典(Tongdian↗): ... 渤海夲栗末靺鞨至其酋祚榮立國自號震旦, 先天中 玄宗王子始去靺鞨號專稱渤海
Injae Lee, Owen Miller, Jinhoon Park, and Hyun-Hae Yi. Korean History in Maps. Cambridge University Press, 15 December 2014. p. 64–65. ISBN 978-1107098466
Joseph Kitagawa. The Religious Traditions of Asia: Religion, History, and Culture. Routledge, 5 September 2013. p. 348. ISBN 978-1136875908
Jacques Gernet. A History of Chinese Civilization. Cambridge University Press, 31 May 1996. p. 291. ISBN 978-0521497817
Edwin Oldfather Reischauer. Ennins Travels in Tang China. John Wiley & Sons Canada, Limited, 1955. p. 276–283. ISBN 978-0471070535 "From what Ennin tells us, it seems that commerce between East China, Korea and Japan was, for the most part, in the hands of men from Silla. Here in the relatively dangerous waters on the eastern fringes of the world, they performed the same functions as did the traders of the placid Mediterranean on the western fringes. This is a historical fact of considerable significance but one which has received virtually no attention in the standard historical compilations of that period or in the modern books based on these sources. . . . While there were limits to the influence of the Koreans along the eastern coast of China, there can be no doubt of their dominance over the waters off these shores. . . . The days of Korean maritime dominance in the Far East actually were numbered, but in Ennin's time the men of Silla were still the masters of the seas in their part of the world."
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea, 2nd Edition. ABC-CLIO, 30 May 2014. p. 3. ISBN 978-1610695824
Michael J. Seth. A Concise History of Korea: From the Neolithic Period Through the Nineteenth Century. Rowman & Littlefield, 2006. p. 65. ISBN 978-0742540057
Neil MacGregor. A History of the World in 100 Objects. Penguin UK, 2011. ISBN 978-0141966830
Yang-mo Chŏng, Judith G. Smith, and Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.). Arts of Korea. Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1998. p. 230. ISBN 978-0870998508
Edward B. Adams. "The Legacy of Kyongju". The Rotarian. 1989, vol. 154, no. 4, pp. 28. ISSN 0035-838X
Alan Ross. After Pusan. Faber & Faber, 17 January 2013. ISBN 978-0571299355
David A. Mason. "Gyeongju, Korea's treasure house"↗. Korea.net↗. Korean Culture and Information Service↗
Edward Ben Adams. Koreaʾs Pottery Heritage. Seoul International Pub. House, 1990. p. 53. ISBN 9788985113069. OCLC 1014620947
Jill DuBois. Korea. Marshall Cavendish, 2004. p. 22. ISBN 978-0761417866
Don Michael Randel. The Harvard Dictionary of Music. Harvard University Press, 28 November 2003. p. 273. ISBN 978-0674011632
Jonathan Hopfner. Moon Living Abroad in South Korea. Avalon Travel, 10 September 2013. p. 21. ISBN 978-1612386324
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea. ABC-CLIO, 30 January 2005. p. 47. ISBN 978-0313038532
Chanju Mun and Ronald S. Green. Buddhist Exploration of Peace and Justice. Blue Pine Books, 2006. p. 147. ISBN 978-0977755301
Suzanne McIntire and William E. Burns. Speeches in World History. Infobase Publishing, 25 June 2010. p. 87. ISBN 978-1438126807
Robert E. Jr. Buswell and Donald S. Jr. Lopez. The Princeton Dictionary of Buddhism. Princeton University Press, 24 November 2013. p. 187. ISBN 978-1400848058
Mario Poceski. Ordinary Mind as the Way: The Hongzhou School and the Growth of Chan Buddhism. Oxford University Press, 13 April 2007. p. 24. ISBN 978-0198043201
Jiang Wu and Lucille Chia. Spreading Buddha's Word in East Asia: The Formation and Transformation of the Chinese Buddhist Canon. Columbia University Press, 15 December 2015. p. 155. ISBN 978-0231540193
Dale S. Wright. The Zen Canon: Understanding the Classic Texts. Oxford University Press, 25 March 2004. ISBN 978-0199882182
Su-il Jeong. The Silk Road Encyclopedia. Seoul Selection, 18 July 2016. ISBN 978-1624120763
Yoshihiro Nikaido. Asian Folk Religion and Cultural Interaction. Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 28 October 2015. p. 137. ISBN 978-3847004851
David Leffman, Simon Lewis, and Jeremy Atiyah. China. Rough Guides, 2003. p. 519. ISBN 978-1843530190
David Leffman. The Rough Guide to China. Penguin, 2 June 2014. ISBN 978-0241010372
DK Eyewitness Travel Guide: China. Penguin, 21 June 2016. p. 240. ISBN 978-1465455673
Ki-Baik Lee. A New History of Korea. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 103. ISBN 978-0674615762
Morris Rossabi. China Among Equals: The Middle Kingdom and Its Neighbors, 10th–14th Centuries. University of California Press, 20 May 1983. p. 323. ISBN 9780520045620
Ki-baek Yi. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 103. ISBN 9780674615762
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea. ABC-CLIO, 30 January 2005. p. 57. ISBN 9780313038532
James H. Grayson. Korea – A Religious History. Routledge, 5 November 2013. p. 79. ISBN 9781136869259
종기 박. 휴머니스트, 24 August 2015. ISBN 9788958629023
"Korean Metal Movable Type". World Treasures: Beginnings. 29 July 2010
"Korean Classics". Library of Congress Asian Collections: 2007 Illustrated Guide. 2007
"Gutenberg Bible"↗. British Library. The British Library Board
"Korea, 1000–1400 A.D. | Chronology | Heilbrunn Timeline of Art History | The Metropolitan Museum of Art"↗. The Met's Heilbrunn Timeline of Art History. The Metropolitan Museum of Art
"Movable type". Oxford Reference
Patricia Buckley Ebrey and Anne Walthall. East Asia: A Cultural, Social, and Political History. Cengage Learning, 1 January 2013. ISBN 978-1285528670
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea, 2nd Edition. ABC-CLIO, 30 May 2014. p. 66. ISBN 9781610695824
Richard Bulliet, Pamela Crossley, Daniel Headrick, Steven Hirsch, and Lyman Johnson. The Earth and Its Peoples, Brief: A Global History. Cengage Learning, 1 January 2014. p. 264. ISBN 9781285445519
Warren I. Cohen. East Asia at the Center: Four Thousand Years of Engagement with the World. Columbia University Press, 20 December 2000. p. 107. ISBN 9780231502511
Kenneth B. Lee. Korea and East Asia: The Story of a Phoenix. Greenwood Publishing Group, 1997. p. 61. ISBN 9780275958237
John Bowman. Columbia Chronologies of Asian History and Culture. Columbia University Press, 5 September 2000. p. 202. ISBN 9780231500043
Kenneth B. Lee. Korea and East Asia: The Story of a Phoenix. Greenwood Publishing Group, 1997. p. 72. ISBN 9780275958237
Wee Kek Koon. "Opinion | The tale of a Korean empress of China, an imperial K-drama". South China Morning Post. 6 November 2020
Ki-baek Yi. A New History of Korea. Harvard University Press, 1984. p. 165. ISBN 9780674615762. OCLC 470671149
Henry Em. The Great Enterprise: Sovereignty and Historiography in Modern Korea. Duke University Press, 25 March 2013. p. 23. ISBN 978-0822353720
Seokwoo Lee and Hee Eun Lee. The Making of International Law in Korea: From Colony to Asian Power. BRILL, 12 May 2016. p. 21. ISBN 9789004315754. OCLC 1006718121
Yuan-kang Wang. Harmony and War: Confucian Culture and Chinese Power Politics. Columbia University Press, 15 December 2010. ISBN 9780231522403. OCLC 774509438
Michael J. Seth. A History of Korea: From Antiquity to the Present. Rowman & Littlefield Publishers, 16 October 2010. p. 144. ISBN 9780742567177. OCLC 644646716
Annabelle R. Gambe. Overseas Chinese Entrepreneurship and Capitalist Development in Southeast Asia. LIT Verlag Münster, 2000. p. 99. ISBN 9783825843861
Anuson Chinvanno. Thailand's Policies towards China, 1949–54. Springer, 18 June 1992. p. 24. ISBN 9781349124305
Jane Kate Leonard. Wei Yuan and China's Rediscovery of the Maritime World. Harvard Univ Asia Center, 1984. p. 137–138. ISBN 9780674948556
Shih-shan Henry Tsai. The Eunuchs in the Ming Dynasty. SUNY Press, January 1996. p. 119–120. ISBN 9780791426876
Joshua Eisemann, Eric Heginbotham, and Derek Mitchell. China and the Developing World: Beijing's Strategy for the Twenty-first Century. Routledge, 20 August 2015. p. 23. ISBN 9781317282945
James B. Lewis. Frontier Contact Between Choson Korea and Tokugawa Japan. Routledge, 2 November 2005. ISBN 9781135795986 "Tribute trade was the oldest and most important component of the trade structure, not for its volume or content, but for its symbolism. Japanese brought items to "offer" to Korea and received in exchange "gifts" of higher value, since Korea was a greater land receiving supplicants. Koreans viewed tribute trade as a "burden" and a favor extended to needy islanders; the significance was diplomatic not economic."
David C. Kang. East Asia Before the West: Five Centuries of Trade and Tribute. Columbia University Press, 2012. p. 122. ISBN 9780231153195
Fujita Kayoko, Shiro Momoki, and Anthony Reid. Offshore Asia: Maritime Interactions in Eastern Asia Before Steamships. Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, 2013. p. 198. ISBN 9789814311779
Chun-gil Kim. The History of Korea. Greenwood Publishing Group, 2005. p. 77. ISBN 9780313332968
Kenneth B. Lee. Korea and East Asia: The Story of a Phoenix. Greenwood Publishing Group, 1997. p. 86. ISBN 9780275958237
"ko:알고 싶은 한글"↗. National Institute of Korean Language↗
Yannis Haralambous and P. Scott Horne. Fonts & Encodings. O'Reilly Media, Inc., 26 September 2007. p. 155. ISBN 9780596102425
Helaine Selin. Encyclopaedia of the History of Science, Technology, and Medicine in Non-Western Cultures. Springer Science & Business Media, 11 November 2013. p. 505–506. ISBN 9789401714167
Djun Kil Kim. The History of Korea, 2nd Edition. ABC-CLIO, 30 May 2014. ISBN 9781610695824
Gwyn Campbell. Structure of Slavery in Indian Ocean Africa and Asia. Routledge, 23 November 2004. p. 153–157. ISBN 9781135759179
David C. Kang. East Asia Before the West: Five Centuries of Trade and Tribute. Columbia University Press, 2012. p. 93–94. ISBN 9780231153195
Jeremy Black. War in the World: A Comparative History, 1450–1600. Palgrave Macmillan, 28 September 2011. ISBN 9780230345515
Ben Kiernan. Blood and soil : a world history of genocide and extermination from Sparta to Darfur. Yale University Press, 2007. ISBN 978-0-300-10098-3
신형식. A Brief History of Korea. Ewha Womans University Press, 1 January 2005. ISBN 9788973006199
Paul Beirne. Su-un and His World of Symbols: The Founder of Korea's First Indigenous Religion. Routledge, 1 April 2016. ISBN 9781317047490
Murder of Empress Myeongseong. Japan rape. Kim soft, 2002
Tae-jin Yi. 태학사, 2005. ISBN 978-89-7626-999-7
Peter N. Stearns, ed. Encyclopedia of World History: Ancient, Medieval, and Modern. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 2001. 6th ed
"Korea". Microsoft Encarta Online Encyclopedia. 2009, pp. 2
Kosuke Takahashi. "History Overshadows Japan-South Korea Rapprochement". The Asia-Pacific Journal: Japan Focus. March 28, 2005, vol. 3, no. 3 NOTE: First published 10 March 2005 under the title "Roh reopens Japan's war wounds" in, and Copyright 2005, Asia Times Online Archived on 23 February 2023↗ Ltd. This is a slightly abbreviated version of the article, posted at Japan Focus 16 March 2005. Archived copy is of full article text from Asia Times.
"March 1st Movement". Encyclopædia Britannica.. 1 March 1919
"Statistics of Japanese Genocide And Mass Murder"↗. Hawaii
啓造 Keizo 山脇 Yamawaki and et al.. 近代日本と外国人労働者―1890年代後半と1920年代前半における中国人・朝鮮人労働者問題. 明石書店 Akashi-shoten, 1994. ISBN 978-4-7503-0568-4
Werner Gruhl. Imperial Japan's World War Two: 1931–1945. Transaction Publishers, 2007. p. 111. ISBN 978-1-4128-0926-9. OCLC 1099050288
Yoshimi Yoshiaki and O'Brien, Suzanne transl. Comfort Women: Sexual Slavery in the Japanese Military During World War II. Columbia University Press, 2001. ISBN 978-0-231-12032-6
"Japanese comfort women ruling overturned". CNN. 29 March 2001
"Comfort Women"↗
Yohei Kono. "Statement by the Chief Cabinet Secretary on the result of the study on the issue of 'comfort women'"↗. MOFA. 4 August 1993
"Koreans in Japan: Past and Present"↗. HAN
"Gyeongbok Palace"↗. Seoul City. Life in Korea
Kay Itoi and BJ Lee. "Korea: A tussle over treasures — Who rightfully owns Korean artifacts looted by Japan?". Newsweek↗. 17 October 2007
Who rightfully owns Korean artifacts looted by Japan?. MSNBC
News. Naver↗
"日독도 영유권 교육강화 방침, 2005년에 이미 발표 :: 한국의 대표 진보언론 민중의소리"↗. Vop. 19 May 2008
"Japanese Periodicals in Colonial Korea"↗. Columbia
"The Life Instability of Intermarried Japanese Women in Korea"↗. USC
Yi-Jin Park. "Re-nationalizing Repatriated Japanese into Post-War Japan: From Imperial Subjects to Post-War Citizens". Sungkyun Journal of East Asian Studies. 2020, vol. 20, no. 1, pp. 113–138
Seong-Kyu Ha. "Housing poverty and the role of urban governance in Korea". Environment and Urbanization. April 2004, vol. 16, no. 1, pp. 139–154. doi:10.1177/095624780401600112. ISSN 0956-2478
Africa has to spend carefully. UK: , 13 July 2006
World Economic Outlook Database. International Monetary Fund↗, October 2008
RJ Rummel. 10. Statistics of North Korean Democide: Estimates, Calculations, and Sources. Statistics of Democide. Hawaii, 1997
Omestad, Thomas, "Gulag Nation" Archived on 9 May 2005↗, U.S. News & World Report↗, 23 June 2003.
Thomas Spoorenberg and Daniel Schwekendiek. Demographic Changes in North Korea: 1993–2008. 2012. online ed. p. 133–58
Takashi Hatada. A History of Korea. Santa Barbara, California: American Bibliographic Center-Clio Press, 1969. p. 140
Bethany Lacina and Nils Petter Gleditsch. Monitoring Trends in Global Combat: A New Dataset of Battle Deaths. 2005. p. 145–166
"ko:판문점 선언: 작년에 비해 담담해진 2주년… 문 대통령 '작은 일이라도 끊임없이 실천해야'". BBC News 코리아
"South Korea, China agree on North Korea talks, early Xi visit"↗. 27 November 2020
"Geography of the Korean Peninsula"↗. Thoughtco
Korean Map Archived on 23 July 2013↗, The People's Korea, 1998.
Geography of Korea. General Books, 6 July 2011. ISBN 9781157065555
"Climate of Korea"↗. Korea Meteorological Administration↗. South Korean Government
Shannon McCune. "Climate of Korea: Climatic Data"↗. 1941
"Cultural Heritage, the source for Koreans' Strength and Dream"↗. Cultural Heritage Administration↗
"Korean Classics : Asian Collections: An Illustrated Guide (Library of Congress – Asian Division)"↗. Library of Congress. United States Congress
"Korea, 1000–1400 A.D. | Chronology | Heilbrunn Timeline of Art History | The Metropolitan Museum of Art"↗. The Met's Heilbrunn Timeline of Art History. The Metropolitan Museum of Art
"Movable type – Oxford Reference". Oxford Reference
Baek Sauk Gi (1987). Woong-Jin-Wee-In-Jun-Gi #11 Jang Young Sil, page 61. Woongjin Publishing.
"Gutenberg and the Koreans: Did Asian Printing Traditions Influence the European Renaissance?"↗. www.rightreading.com
"Effects of the Mongol Empire on Europe"↗. Szczepanski, Kallie
Samuel Hawley. The Imjin War. Japan's Sixteenth-Century Invasion of Korea and Attempt to Conquer China. Seoul: The Royal Asiatic Society, Korea Branch, 2005. p. 195f. ISBN 978-89-954424-2-5
Stephen Turnbull. Samurai Invasion. Japan's Korean War 1592–98. London: Cassell & Co, 2002. p. 244. ISBN 978-0-304-35948-6
Young-koo Roh. "Yi Sun-shin, an Admiral Who Became a Myth". The Review of Korean Studies. 2004, vol. 7, no. 3, pp. 15–36
"Korea's ethnic nationalism is a source of both pride and prejudice, according to Gi-Wook Shin"↗. Aparc. Stanford
John M. Glionna. Trying to teach South Korea about discrimination. 24 February 2009
Hyung-jin Kim. "No 'real' Chinatown in S. Korea, the result of xenophobic attitudes". 29 August 2006
"More Than 1 Million Foreigners Live in Korea"↗. The Chosun Ilbo↗. 6 August 2009
"Korea, North"↗. The World Factbook. CIA
"Religion"↗. About Korea. Korea
"South Koreans"↗. Japan to Mali. Every Culture
"Culture of South Korea"↗. Every Culture
"Culture of North Korea"↗. Every Culture
"North Korea: people"↗. The World Factbook. CIA
"Korea, Republic of"↗. International Religious Freedom Report. Department of State. 2008
Pewforum. "Religious Composition by Country, 2010–2050"↗. Pew Research Center's Religion & Public Life Project. 2 April 2015
"The Korea Times: Islam takes root and blooms"↗. Islam awareness. 22 November 2002
"Korea, (North) Democratic Republic of, Religion And Social Profile | National Profiles | International Data | TheARDA"↗. www.thearda.com
"Inside North Korea's only mosque during Eid al-Fitr"↗. NK News↗. 18 May 2021
A Handbook of Korea. Seoul: Korean Overseas Culture and Information Service↗, December 1993. 9th ed. p. 143. ISBN 978-1-56591-022-5
"Data"↗. OECD
Library of Congress country study, see p. 7 for Education and Literacy (Archived on 28 July 2012↗)
UIS. "UIS Statistics"↗
"Democratic People's Republic of Korea"↗. UNESCO
"Republic of Korea"↗. UNESCO
"ko:대한민국의 국호"↗. Naver Encyclope
"Rare Korean musical instruments exhibited". The Korea Herald↗. 11 May 2011
Elizabeth May. Musics of Many Cultures: An Introduction. University of California Press, 1983. Ethno Musicology ed. p. 32–33. ISBN 978-0520047785
Shim Seung-Ja. "La nourriture coréenne". Revue Culture coréenne. August 2002, no. 61, pp. 17–23
Chang Duk-Sang. "L'étonnante cuisine coréenne". Revue Culture coréenne. December 1990, no. 24, pp. 2–10

Bibliography

Ian Castello-Cortes, ed. North Korea. World Reference Atlas. New York: Dorling Kindersley, 1996. 2nd American ed. ISBN 978-0-7894-1085-6.
Bruce Cumings. Korea's Place in the Sun. Norton, 1997. ISBN 978-0-393-31681-0
Kim and et al.. Women of Korea: A History from Ancient Times to 1945. Ewha Womans University Press, 1976. ISBN 978-89-7300-116-3.
History. Korea. Asian Info.
Top 500 list. CN↗: STJI, 2007
People. Facts. UMSL, 2005.
Tariq Hussain. The Korea Herald. Diamond dilemma, 5 March 2007.
Korea information. Korea Expat Community. WorknPlay.

Further reading

Chun, Tuk Chu. "Korea in the Pacific Community". Social Education 52 (March 1988), 182. EJ 368 177.
Cumings, Bruce↗. The Two Koreas. New York: Foreign Policy Association, 1984.
Don Oberdorfer. The Two Koreas: a Contemporary History. Basic Books, 2001. ISBN 978-0465051625. OCLC 47831650
Focus on Asian Studies. Special Issue: "Korea: A Teacher's Guide". No. 1, Fall 1986.
Gi-Wook Shin. Colonial modernity in Korea. Cambridge, MA↗: Harvard University, Asia Center, 1999. ISBN 978-0-674-14255-8.
Hart, Dennis. From Tradition to Consumption: Construction of a Capitalist Culture in South Korea. Seoul: Jimoondang, 2003.
Sheila Miyoshi Jager↗. Brothers at War – The Unending Conflict in Korea. London: Profile Books, 2013. ISBN 978-1-84668-067-0
Joe, W.J. & Choe, H.A. Traditional Korea: A Cultural History, Seoul: Hollym, 1997.
Joungwon, A.K. Divided Korea: The Politics of Development, Harvard University Press, 1975.
Lee Ki-baik. A New History of Korea. Cambridge: Harvard UP, 1984.
Lee Sang-sup. "The Arts and Literature of Korea". The Social Studies 79 (July–August 1988): 153–60. EJ 376 894.
Keith L Pratt. Everlasting Flower: A History of Korea. London: Reaktion, 2006. ISBN 9781861892737. OCLC 63137295
Tae-Jin, Y. "The Illegality of the Forced Treaties Leading to Japan's Annexation of the Great Han Empire", In the Korean National Commission for UNESCO, Vol. 36, No. 4, 1996.
The Gloucestershire Regiment and The Battle of the Imjin River, Korean War. UK↗: Glosters.
How Does Korea Compare. OECD Health Data. Organisation For Economic Co-operation and Development, 2009.

External links

Wiktionary: Korea↗ Wikivoyage: Korea↗ *

The Republic of Korea↗

38°19′N 127°14′E